[
    {
        "question": "Political knowledge",
        "correct_answer": "fosters political tolerance.",
        "distractor1": "is greater among youth than the elderly.",
        "distractor2": "is not that important in a democracy.",
        "distractor3": "is generally high in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Voter turnout matters because",
        "correct_answer": "politicians pay more attention to those who vote than to those who do not vote.",
        "distractor1": "federal funds are allocated on the basis of the number of voters in a congressional district.",
        "distractor2": "better candidates are selected when more people vote.",
        "distractor3": "it makes citizens feel better.",
        "distractor4": "it makes our country look better. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government is defined as the",
        "correct_answer": "institutions and processes through which public policies are made for society. ",
        "distractor1": "organization that brings problems to the attention of public officials.",
        "distractor2": "body that is concerned with economic problems while leaving social problems to other institutions of society.",
        "distractor3": "agency that implements policies that have been enacted by other institutions of the political system.",
        "distractor4": "executive branch and its agencies."
    },
    {
        "question": "The policymaking institutions of the American national government include all of thefollowing EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "political parties.",
        "distractor1": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "the presidency.",
        "distractor3": "Congress.",
        "distractor4": "the Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of the Internet for democracy is that it",
        "correct_answer": "makes it easier for citizens to communicate directly with government.",
        "distractor1": "provides less information than newspapers.",
        "distractor2": "makes it easy to avoid political topics.",
        "distractor3": "will provide more political information to political elites.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Things that are indivisible, nonexclusive, and that everyone can share are called",
        "correct_answer": "public goods. ",
        "distractor1": "intangible property.",
        "distractor2": "socialized.",
        "distractor3": "community property.",
        "distractor4": "communist."
    },
    {
        "question": "Governments in the modern world, whether democratic or not, are similar in doing all of thefollowing EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "protecting citizens ยน civil liberties.",
        "distractor1": "maintaining a national defense.",
        "distractor2": "providing public goods.",
        "distractor3": "collecting taxes.",
        "distractor4": "providing public services. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A public good is defined as",
        "correct_answer": "something in which any member of society can share.",
        "distractor1": "something provided by the government that cannot be provided by the private sector.",
        "distractor2": "a choice that government makes in response to a political issue.",
        "distractor3": "a public policy that is good for the nation as a whole.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about public goods is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Individuals have powerful incentives to provide public goods.",
        "distractor1": "The government usually provides public goods.",
        "distractor2": "Public goods are things that everyone can share.",
        "distractor3": "Public goods are not profitable.",
        "distractor4": "Public goods are indivisible and nonexclusive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All governments",
        "correct_answer": "provide public goods and socialize citizens into the political and social system.",
        "distractor1": "ensure safety on the high seas and promote free enterprise.",
        "distractor2": "maintain national parks and a national defense.",
        "distractor3": "guarantee a capitalist economy and collect taxes.",
        "distractor4": "hold elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All governments",
        "correct_answer": "provide services.",
        "distractor1": "have written constitutions.",
        "distractor2": "are elected.",
        "distractor3": "have a legislature.",
        "distractor4": "have a president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about taxes is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "One out of every three dollars earned by an American citizen is used to pay taxes.",
        "distractor1": "Despite the image presented by the media, survey data reveal that Americans feel they are getting their money's worth for the taxes they pay.",
        "distractor2": "About one-tenth of the average American citizen's salary goes to taxes.",
        "distractor3": "The tax burden in the United States is higher than in most other democratic nations.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An interest group so single-minded that its members often vote on only one issue, ignoring apolitician's stand on everything else, is known as",
        "correct_answer": "a single-issue group.",
        "distractor1": "a one-issue group.",
        "distractor2": "a uni-issue group.",
        "distractor3": "a hot-button group.",
        "distractor4": "a mono-issue group. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When compared with the rest of the world, America has a relatively low",
        "correct_answer": "voter turnout in elections.",
        "distractor1": "number of offices up for election.",
        "distractor2": "number of candidates who seek office.",
        "distractor3": "frequency of elections.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Many politicians believe that single-issue groups",
        "correct_answer": "complicate efforts to seek the middle ground on various issues.",
        "distractor1": "stimulate the political system to solve public policy problems.",
        "distractor2": "are essential to democracy.",
        "distractor3": "play a unifying role in American politics.",
        "distractor4": "do not affect policymaking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Politics is defined by Harold Lasswell as",
        "correct_answer": "who gets what, when, and how.",
        "distractor1": "conflict in society.",
        "distractor2": "the exercise of power.",
        "distractor3": "the resolution of conflict in a way that serves the public.",
        "distractor4": "a course of action to solve a problem. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Single-issue groups",
        "correct_answer": "have little sympathy for compromising.",
        "distractor1": "are rapidly losing prominence in American politics.",
        "distractor2": "usually run their own candidates for public office.",
        "distractor3": "help facilitate the construction of a cohesive national public policy.",
        "distractor4": "are highly regarded by political scientists for their contributions to democracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements best describes voter turnout in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "The United States has one of the lowest voter turnout rates in the world. ",
        "distractor1": "Among democratic nations, the United States leads the world in voter turnout.",
        "distractor2": "Voter turnout in the United States is constitutionally mandated.",
        "distractor3": "Voters are usually a microcosm of the entire body of American citizens.",
        "distractor4": "Most American voters consider politics as critical to their interests."
    },
    {
        "question": "The list of problems to which political leaders are paying serious attention is a(n)",
        "correct_answer": "policy agenda.",
        "distractor1": "problem set.",
        "distractor2": "issue constellation.",
        "distractor3": "legislative package.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is the process by which policy comes into being and evolves over time.",
        "correct_answer": "A policymaking system",
        "distractor1": "Democracy",
        "distractor2": "A constellation",
        "distractor3": "The bureaucracy",
        "distractor4": "Government "
    },
    {
        "question": "The process from above is",
        "correct_answer": "a policymaking system.",
        "distractor1": "political decision making.",
        "distractor2": "a policy agenda.",
        "distractor3": "a government.",
        "distractor4": "a linkage institution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of public policymaking would be",
        "correct_answer": "Congress and the president deciding not to act on the AIDS crisis.",
        "distractor1": "a majority of the public supporting the idea of government dealing with unemployment.",
        "distractor2": "the president meeting with the heads of oil companies.",
        "distractor3": "the press creating public concern about racial discrimination.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are parts of the policymaking system EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "public goods.",
        "distractor1": "policymaking institutions.",
        "distractor2": "linkage institutions.",
        "distractor3": "people's political interests.",
        "distractor4": "policy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about a government's policy agenda is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "A government's policy agenda tends to remain constant over time.",
        "distractor1": "When you vote, you are partly looking at whether a candidate shares your agenda or not.",
        "distractor2": "Bad news gets an issue on the policy agenda more quickly than good news.",
        "distractor3": "When people confront government officials with problems to be solved, they are trying to influence the government's policy agenda.",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; all are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A political party is a key ________ in Americaยนs democratic system.",
        "correct_answer": "linkage institution",
        "distractor1": "stimulus-response",
        "distractor2": "input",
        "distractor3": "majoritarian inhibitor",
        "distractor4": "output "
    },
    {
        "question": "In a democratic society, parties, elections, interest groups and the media are all examples of ________ between the preferences of citizens and the government's policy agenda.",
        "correct_answer": "linkage institutions ",
        "distractor1": "cross-pollination",
        "distractor2": "inputs and outputs",
        "distractor3": "ideological bridges",
        "distractor4": "obstacles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a linkage institution?",
        "correct_answer": "Congress",
        "distractor1": "political parties",
        "distractor2": "the media",
        "distractor3": "interest groups",
        "distractor4": "All of these are linkage institutions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a linkage institution?",
        "correct_answer": "USA Today",
        "distractor1": "the president's cabinet",
        "distractor2": "the House of Representatives",
        "distractor3": "the ambassador to France",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Parties and interest groups",
        "correct_answer": "work hard to get the issues they want on the policy agenda.",
        "distractor1": "determine which issues are on the policy agenda.",
        "distractor2": "are not particularly interested in the policy agenda.",
        "distractor3": "have no effect on the policy agenda.",
        "distractor4": "determine the congressional agenda. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A choice that government makes in response to some issue on its agenda is called",
        "correct_answer": "public policy.",
        "distractor1": "selective selection.",
        "distractor2": "a law.",
        "distractor3": "stimulus-response.",
        "distractor4": "rational choice theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ arise when people disagree about a problem or a public policy choice made tocombat a problem.",
        "correct_answer": "Political issues",
        "distractor1": "Revolutions",
        "distractor2": "Social crises",
        "distractor3": "Governments",
        "distractor4": "Wars "
    },
    {
        "question": "A key question that confronts government regarding different public policy choices is",
        "correct_answer": "whether or not government should do anything about them.",
        "distractor1": "whether an appropriate linkage institution is willing to frame a policy.",
        "distractor2": "which is the most complicated one to deal with.",
        "distractor3": "which is the least complicated one to deal with.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public policy is defined as a",
        "correct_answer": "choice that government makes in response to an issue. ",
        "distractor1": "policy directed at more than one person.",
        "distractor2": "course of action to solve a problem.",
        "distractor3": "set of rules and regulations issued by a government agency.",
        "distractor4": "course of action by a political party."
    },
    {
        "question": "Political issues",
        "correct_answer": "arise when people disagree about a problem or public policy choices made to combat a problem.",
        "distractor1": "are always acted upon by the government.",
        "distractor2": "are limited in number in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "usually emerge out of group consensus on a problem.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels published",
        "correct_answer": "The Communist Manifesto.",
        "distractor1": "A Theory of Democracy.",
        "distractor2": "The Federalist Papers.",
        "distractor3": "Poor Richard's Almanac.",
        "distractor4": "War and Peace. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One type of linkage institution is",
        "correct_answer": "an interest group.",
        "distractor1": "a government.",
        "distractor2": "a bureaucracy.",
        "distractor3": "a legislature.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The effects a policy has on people and problems is called",
        "correct_answer": "policy impacts.",
        "distractor1": "policy outputs.",
        "distractor2": "policy implementation.",
        "distractor3": "policy issues.",
        "distractor4": "policy agenda. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The writers of the United States Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "were distrustful of democracy.",
        "distractor1": "sought to establish the most democratic system they could.",
        "distractor2": "were interested in promoting equality above all else.",
        "distractor3": "patterned our government after Britain's except for the King.",
        "distractor4": "believed in majority rule. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A means of selecting policymakers and or organizing government so that policy representsand responds to the public's preferences is",
        "correct_answer": "democracy.",
        "distractor1": "government.",
        "distractor2": "politics.",
        "distractor3": "public administration.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT a criterion of traditional democratic theory, as formulated by RobertDahl?",
        "correct_answer": "Citizens must make rational choices. ",
        "distractor1": "freedom of speech and press",
        "distractor2": "One person gets one vote.",
        "distractor3": "Citizenship must be open to all within a nation.",
        "distractor4": "Those who participate in political organizations must be representative of the general population."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the cornerstones of an ideal democracy?",
        "correct_answer": "economic equality",
        "distractor1": "a constitution",
        "distractor2": "effective participation",
        "distractor3": "citizen control of the agenda",
        "distractor4": "equality in voting "
    },
    {
        "question": "Two of the most important principles of democratic theory are majority rule and",
        "correct_answer": "minority rights.",
        "distractor1": "the plurality rule.",
        "distractor2": "judicial review.",
        "distractor3": "majority restraint.",
        "distractor4": "Roberts ยน Rules of Order. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following takes the most positive view of democracy in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist theory",
        "distractor1": "democratic centralism",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralism",
        "distractor3": "democratic positivism",
        "distractor4": "elite theory "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are ingredients of a pluralistic democracy EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "majority rule.",
        "distractor1": "group competition for policy benefits.",
        "distractor2": "bargaining and compromise.",
        "distractor3": "multiple access points to policymakers.",
        "distractor4": "separation of powers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most fundamental element of democratic theory is",
        "correct_answer": "majority rule.",
        "distractor1": "  power to the people!  ",
        "distractor2": "government efficiency.",
        "distractor3": "equality.",
        "distractor4": "access to information. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Representation refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the correspondence between the few leaders and the many followers in a democracy. ",
        "distractor1": "majority rule.",
        "distractor2": "all policy views being included in political debate.",
        "distractor3": "the protection of minority rights in a pluralist system.",
        "distractor4": "electing office-holders in fair and free elections."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following individuals have suggested that pluralist theory is less descriptive ofAmerican politics than in the past?",
        "correct_answer": "Robert Putnam",
        "distractor1": "Anthony King",
        "distractor2": "Robert Dahl",
        "distractor3": "Alexis de Tocqueville",
        "distractor4": "Thomas Jefferson "
    },
    {
        "question": "American government is viewed most positively by the",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist theory.",
        "distractor1": "socialist theory.",
        "distractor2": "positivist philosophy.",
        "distractor3": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor4": "elite and class theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A system in which many groups make themselves heard and felt somewhere in the policyprocess is",
        "correct_answer": "pluralistic.",
        "distractor1": "direct democracy.",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralistic.",
        "distractor3": "elitist.",
        "distractor4": "bureaucratic. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The theory that argues that group competition results in a rough approximation of the publicinterest in public policy is",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist theory.",
        "distractor1": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor2": "balance of power theory.",
        "distractor3": "elite and class theory.",
        "distractor4": "bureaucratic theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a contemporary theory of democracy?",
        "correct_answer": "democratic centralism",
        "distractor1": "hyperpluralism",
        "distractor2": "class theory",
        "distractor3": "pluralism",
        "distractor4": "elite theory "
    },
    {
        "question": "Robert Putnam's claim that Americans are now   bowling alone   is a criticism of",
        "correct_answer": "pluralism.",
        "distractor1": "elite theory.",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralism.",
        "distractor3": "social network theory.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most fundamentally critical of American democracy?",
        "correct_answer": "elite and class theory ",
        "distractor1": "traditional democratic theory",
        "distractor2": "democratic negativism",
        "distractor3": "pluralist theory",
        "distractor4": "critical democratic theory"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many elite and class theorists believe that ________ of Americans control most governmentpolicy decisions.",
        "correct_answer": "1 percent",
        "distractor1": "5 percent",
        "distractor2": "a majority",
        "distractor3": "the vast middle class",
        "distractor4": "10 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over a third of America's wealth is owned by",
        "correct_answer": "one percent of the population.",
        "distractor1": "the United States government.",
        "distractor2": "a third of the population.",
        "distractor3": "seven percent of the population.",
        "distractor4": "Japanese investors. "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the center of all theories of elite domination of politics is",
        "correct_answer": "big business.",
        "distractor1": "the Congress.",
        "distractor2": "the nouveau riche.",
        "distractor3": "the Trilateral Commission.",
        "distractor4": "the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Elite and class theory holds that",
        "correct_answer": "all societies are divided along class lines and that an upper-class elite will rule.",
        "distractor1": "power is dispersed among many institutions.",
        "distractor2": "in a democracy the majority class must overthrow the government and rule by itself if government is to be freed from the control of the rich.",
        "distractor3": "there is little consensus in policymaking among elites.",
        "distractor4": "politics is the basis of elite power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The theory that sees wealth as the basis of power is the",
        "correct_answer": "elite and class theory.",
        "distractor1": "democratic theory.",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor3": "Jeffersonian theory.",
        "distractor4": "pluralist theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Hyperpluralists believe that the dominant player in American politics is",
        "correct_answer": "groups.",
        "distractor1": "the president.",
        "distractor2": "the government.",
        "distractor3": "the media.",
        "distractor4": "rich individuals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In evaluating American democracy, hyperpluralists",
        "correct_answer": "claim that too many influential groups cripple government's ability to govern.",
        "distractor1": "claim that competing groups vying for power make for generally efficient, honest government.",
        "distractor2": "claim that society is governed solely by an upper-class elite.",
        "distractor3": "believe that the public interest is nearly always translated into public policy in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to hyperpluralists, the increasing caseloads of federal and state courts demonstrate",
        "correct_answer": "the expanding scope of government in the United States.",
        "distractor1": "the high status of attorneys in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "the inability to control the bureaucracy in implementing policy.",
        "distractor3": "that groups are more likely to appeal to different institutions in order to gain policy benefits.",
        "distractor4": "the increasing complexity of our social networks. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   power of the few   in the United States today is likely to refer to",
        "correct_answer": "technical experts.",
        "distractor1": "high-level bureaucrats.",
        "distractor2": "elected officials.",
        "distractor3": "property holders.",
        "distractor4": "a silent majority. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The nature of groups and the government in hyperpluralist theory is",
        "correct_answer": "strong groups and weak government.",
        "distractor1": "strong government and strong groups.",
        "distractor2": "weak groups and strong government.",
        "distractor3": "weak groups, strong elites, and weak government.",
        "distractor4": "too few groups result in the creation of many governments. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Hyperpluralists would argue that",
        "correct_answer": "too many influential groups cripple government's ability to govern.",
        "distractor1": "society is divided along class lines.",
        "distractor2": "group competition will result in a rough approximation of the public interest.",
        "distractor3": "wealth is the basis of power.",
        "distractor4": "too few groups lead to a proliferation of governments. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT considered a challenge to democracy by the textbook?",
        "correct_answer": "the tendency of the American political system to change rapidly ",
        "distractor1": "the diversity of the American people",
        "distractor2": "the level of political participation by Americans",
        "distractor3": "PACs",
        "distractor4": "the specialization of knowledge held by experts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would NOT be considered a contemporary challenge to Americandemocracy?",
        "correct_answer": "the threat of communism",
        "distractor1": "complexity of the issues",
        "distractor2": "the use of money in politics",
        "distractor3": "political participation rates",
        "distractor4": "diversity "
    },
    {
        "question": "Increased technical expertise is a challenge to democracy because",
        "correct_answer": "it goes against the tenets of pluralist political theory.",
        "distractor1": "it is difficult to have an informed   non-technical   public debate on technical issues.",
        "distractor2": "it violates the notion of one man, one vote.",
        "distractor3": "elected officials find it hard to understand technical experts.",
        "distractor4": "interest groups have a difficult time securing technical expertise. "
    },
    {
        "question": "PAC stands for",
        "correct_answer": "Political Action Committee. ",
        "distractor1": "Partisan Assistance Contribution.",
        "distractor2": "Party Affairs Council.",
        "distractor3": "Policy Advisory Commission.",
        "distractor4": "Politically Active Constituency."
    },
    {
        "question": "People who worry about PACs are most especially concerned about",
        "correct_answer": "the close connection between money and politics.",
        "distractor1": "the decline in American voter turnout.",
        "distractor2": "too much democracy being dangerous to social stability.",
        "distractor3": "the role Party Affairs Councils play in elections.",
        "distractor4": "single-issue voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Escalating campaign costs are a challenge to democracy because",
        "correct_answer": "it is believed that PAC contributions affect the way members of Congress vote on single issues.",
        "distractor1": "they are associated with more technical policies.",
        "distractor2": "they lead to policy gridlock.",
        "distractor3": "they reflect diverse interests.",
        "distractor4": "they make it easier for candidates to raise money. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, the diversity of political interests in America is resulting in",
        "correct_answer": "policy gridlock.",
        "distractor1": "a decrease in political participation.",
        "distractor2": "the breakdown of the educational system.",
        "distractor3": "an increase in political participation.",
        "distractor4": "a cultural renaissance. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ability of groups to prevent the government from taking actions adverse to their interestsleads to what the text calls",
        "correct_answer": "policy gridlock. ",
        "distractor1": "Dahl's   ideal democratic process.  ",
        "distractor2": "elite dominance.",
        "distractor3": "budget deficits.",
        "distractor4": "enlightened understanding."
    },
    {
        "question": "The overall set of shared values in a society is known as",
        "correct_answer": "political culture.",
        "distractor1": "individualism.",
        "distractor2": "value added voting.",
        "distractor3": "populism.",
        "distractor4": "collectivism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to G.K. Chesterston, the United States is the only country in the world that isfounded on",
        "correct_answer": "a creed.",
        "distractor1": "heredity.",
        "distractor2": "isolationism.",
        "distractor3": "civic virtue.",
        "distractor4": "religious principles. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the American Revolution, Patrick Henry said",
        "correct_answer": "  Give me liberty or give me death.  ",
        "distractor1": "  We fight for truth, justice, and the American way!  ",
        "distractor2": "  I regret that I have but one life to give for my country.  ",
        "distractor3": "  Our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.  ",
        "distractor4": "  Live free or die.   "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Thomas Jefferson, which of the following is an inalienable right?",
        "correct_answer": "Liberty",
        "distractor1": "Taxes",
        "distractor2": "Justice",
        "distractor3": "Jurisprudence",
        "distractor4": "Incontinence "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence says that   all men are created equal.   Which aspect of theAmerican creed does this suggest?",
        "correct_answer": "Liberty",
        "distractor1": "Individualism",
        "distractor2": "Egalitarianism",
        "distractor3": "Capitalism",
        "distractor4": "Populism "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the primary reasons for the comparatively small scope of American government is",
        "correct_answer": "individualism. ",
        "distractor1": "liberalism.",
        "distractor2": "pluralism.",
        "distractor3": "judicial review.",
        "distractor4": "capitalism."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Frederick Jackson Turner, the existence of the frontier in American history mostdirectly resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "a strong preference for limited government.",
        "distractor1": "the abolition of slavery.",
        "distractor2": "the environmental movement.",
        "distractor3": "the space program.",
        "distractor4": "the civil rights movement. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Populism emphasizes",
        "correct_answer": "the people.",
        "distractor1": "the elected officials.",
        "distractor2": "representative democracy.",
        "distractor3": "the meritocracy.",
        "distractor4": "prosperity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who argue that the United States is in the midst of a culture war argue that Americansare becoming increasingly",
        "correct_answer": "polarized. ",
        "distractor1": "isolationist.",
        "distractor2": "secular.",
        "distractor3": "hypocritical.",
        "distractor4": "egalitarian."
    },
    {
        "question": "National, state, and local governments in America spend almost ________ of the grossdomestic product.",
        "correct_answer": "30 percent",
        "distractor1": "3 percent",
        "distractor2": "all",
        "distractor3": "10 percent",
        "distractor4": "none "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government owns ________ of the land in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "one-third",
        "distractor1": "all",
        "distractor2": "5 percent",
        "distractor3": "2 percent",
        "distractor4": "none "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest item in the United States government budget, consuming more than one -fifth ofspending, is",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security payments.",
        "distractor1": "foreign aid.",
        "distractor2": "education spending.",
        "distractor3": "national defense.",
        "distractor4": "welfare for the poor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States national government spends about ________ a year.",
        "correct_answer": "$2.8 trillion ",
        "distractor1": "$4 billion",
        "distractor2": "$250 billion",
        "distractor3": "$1,000,000,000,000",
        "distractor4": "$500 billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following categories is the largest expenditure in the federal budget?",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security",
        "distractor1": "Medicaid",
        "distractor2": "environment",
        "distractor3": "national defense",
        "distractor4": "homeland security "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is TRUE about the United States Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "None of these are true. ",
        "distractor1": "It centralizes political power.",
        "distractor2": "It is superseded only by decrees of the president.",
        "distractor3": "It sets neutral rules for the game of politics.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are true."
    },
    {
        "question": "In setting the broad rules of the game of politics, constitutions",
        "correct_answer": "are never neutral; they give some participants advantages over others.",
        "distractor1": "are fair and impartial.",
        "distractor2": "allow all participants the same political opportunities.",
        "distractor3": "have no effect on the distribution of power in society.",
        "distractor4": "are constantly changing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By eighteenth-century standards, life was ________ for most people in the United States at thetime of the Revolution.",
        "correct_answer": "not bad",
        "distractor1": "hell both politically and economically",
        "distractor2": "politically oppressive",
        "distractor3": "ideal",
        "distractor4": "an economic nightmare "
    },
    {
        "question": "The British government stepped up its controls over the American colonies with new taxesand stronger commerce regulations right after",
        "correct_answer": "the French and Indian War. ",
        "distractor1": "King Phillip's War.",
        "distractor2": "the assassination of the Duke of Windsor.",
        "distractor3": "King George's War.",
        "distractor4": "the Civil War."
    },
    {
        "question": "The British levied new taxes on its North American colonies in the eighteenth century in orderto pay for",
        "correct_answer": "defending new territories obtained after the French and Indian War.",
        "distractor1": "maintaining the elegant lifestyle of the British royalty.",
        "distractor2": "conquest of territories in Africa and Asia.",
        "distractor3": "tax cuts and social welfare programs for residents of the British Isles.",
        "distractor4": "the rising cost of tea. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who issued the Declaration of Independence?",
        "correct_answer": "the Continental Congress",
        "distractor1": "the Constitutional Convention of 1776",
        "distractor2": "President George Washington",
        "distractor3": "the 13 colonial legislatures",
        "distractor4": "General George Washington "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence was primarily",
        "correct_answer": "a polemic, announcing and justifying a revolution.",
        "distractor1": "a treaty with France for war against Britain.",
        "distractor2": "an original philosophical treatise on politics.",
        "distractor3": "an outline for a new government.",
        "distractor4": "the United States ยน first constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary author of the Declaration of Independence was",
        "correct_answer": "Thomas Jefferson.",
        "distractor1": "Benjamin Franklin.",
        "distractor2": "James Madison.",
        "distractor3": "King George III.",
        "distractor4": "George Washington. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence",
        "correct_answer": "became one of the most important statements of American political philosophy.",
        "distractor1": "contained completely new ideas on political philosophy.",
        "distractor2": "took several months to write.",
        "distractor3": "blamed the British parliament for abuses on the colonies.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Revolution was based upon the ideas of",
        "correct_answer": "European political thinkers.",
        "distractor1": "intellectual slaves.",
        "distractor2": "intellectual frontiersmen.",
        "distractor3": "George Washington.",
        "distractor4": "American farmers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The foundation of John Locke's philosophy was that human beings",
        "correct_answer": "derive their rights from nature.",
        "distractor1": "have rights that are granted them by government.",
        "distractor2": "determine their own rights.",
        "distractor3": "derive their rights from God.",
        "distractor4": "are granted their rights by their King. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these was NOT among John Locke's key philosophical concepts?",
        "correct_answer": "checks and balances",
        "distractor1": "limited government",
        "distractor2": "natural rights",
        "distractor3": "consent of the governed",
        "distractor4": "property rights "
    },
    {
        "question": "John Locke's ideas on natural rights were related to human law in that",
        "correct_answer": "natural rights were considered higher than human law.",
        "distractor1": "natural rights were less important than human law.",
        "distractor2": "human law was the source of natural rights.",
        "distractor3": "human law protected property rights, making human law equal to natural rights.",
        "distractor4": "human law and natural rights were unimportant after revolution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "John Locke believed in each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "divine right of kings.",
        "distractor1": "limited government.",
        "distractor2": "consent of the governed.",
        "distractor3": "natural rights.",
        "distractor4": "both C and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Declaration of Independence argued that",
        "correct_answer": "people should revolt when they suffer deep injustices.",
        "distractor1": "nations are indivisible and a people must never secede from their mother nation.",
        "distractor2": "the British parliament was to blame for the evils imposed upon the colonists.",
        "distractor3": "people should always work peacefully within the system to redress any grievances they have.",
        "distractor4": "revolution is justifiable whenever people become angry with their government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reflecting the natural rights philosophy, the Declaration of Independence stated thatgovernments derive their just powers from",
        "correct_answer": "the consent of the governed.",
        "distractor1": "God.",
        "distractor2": "tradition.",
        "distractor3": "their elected leaders.",
        "distractor4": "a Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The justification for separation from England in the Declaration of Independence was basedheavily on the ideas of the English philosopher",
        "correct_answer": "John Locke. ",
        "distractor1": "Lord North.",
        "distractor2": "Henry VIII.",
        "distractor3": "Oliver Cromwell.",
        "distractor4": "David Hume."
    },
    {
        "question": "The sole purpose of government, according to John Locke, was to",
        "correct_answer": "protect natural rights. ",
        "distractor1": "promote the common good.",
        "distractor2": "prevent anarchy.",
        "distractor3": "educate its people.",
        "distractor4": "protect individuals from violence."
    },
    {
        "question": "John Locke believed that the   end of government   was",
        "correct_answer": "preservation of property.",
        "distractor1": "majority rule.",
        "distractor2": "equality of man.",
        "distractor3": "pursuit of happiness.",
        "distractor4": "  the beginning of life.   "
    },
    {
        "question": "In John Locke's philosophy, the requirements that standing laws be known and privateproperty be preserved",
        "correct_answer": "impose two major limits on government.",
        "distractor1": "are always threatened by democratic government.",
        "distractor2": "are unenforceable when government is limited.",
        "distractor3": "must be sacrificed in the interest of democracy.",
        "distractor4": "could only be enforced by a powerful king. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson's phrase   life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness   was a modification ofJohn Locke's phrase   Life, liberty, and ________.  ",
        "correct_answer": "property",
        "distractor1": "God",
        "distractor2": "heaven",
        "distractor3": "health",
        "distractor4": "equality "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary goal of the American Revolution was",
        "correct_answer": "to restore the colonists ยน rights as British subjects.",
        "distractor1": "to gain control over the colonies ยน trade with foreign nations.",
        "distractor2": "to cut taxes.",
        "distractor3": "to win the right to print paper money that could be used to pay off debts.",
        "distractor4": "to gain control of the western frontier. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Revolution was different from the French, Russian, and Iranian revolutions inthat",
        "correct_answer": "it produced little societal change.",
        "distractor1": "it was much bloodier.",
        "distractor2": "it was much shorter.",
        "distractor3": "it did not result in a change of government.",
        "distractor4": "It was different in all these ways. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Articles of Confederation were adopted by",
        "correct_answer": "the Continental Congress.",
        "distractor1": "President George Washington.",
        "distractor2": "a small, self-appointed committee of the nation's political leaders.",
        "distractor3": "the British Parliament.",
        "distractor4": "the Continental Army under command of General George Washington. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Beginning in 1781, the United States was governed under the",
        "correct_answer": "Articles of Confederation.",
        "distractor1": "Mayflower Compact.",
        "distractor2": "Basic Law of 1781.",
        "distractor3": "British Constitution.",
        "distractor4": "current United States Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary goal of the American Revolution was to",
        "correct_answer": "restore rights the colonists felt were already theirs as British subjects.",
        "distractor1": "establish a new political system.",
        "distractor2": "create a new economic order.",
        "distractor3": "institutionalize new social values based on equality.",
        "distractor4": "establish property rights. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Revolution",
        "correct_answer": "did not drastically alter the colonists ยน way of life.",
        "distractor1": "produced great societal change.",
        "distractor2": "was won quickly and decisively by the superior American troops.",
        "distractor3": "created class conflicts that split society.",
        "distractor4": "was fought between a large army of colonials and a small British army. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Articles of Confederation, most power rested with the",
        "correct_answer": "state legislatures.",
        "distractor1": "the British Parliament.",
        "distractor2": "president.",
        "distractor3": "United States Senate.",
        "distractor4": "Continental Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is FALSE about the United States government under the Articles ofConfederation?",
        "correct_answer": "Most authority rested with the United States Congress rather than the state governments.",
        "distractor1": "Each state had only one vote in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "The Congress had only one house.",
        "distractor3": "There was no president.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are false. "
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Revolution, power in the state legislatures shifted",
        "correct_answer": "from the wealthy to those with more moderate incomes.",
        "distractor1": "from merchants to lawyers.",
        "distractor2": "from the poor to the wealthy.",
        "distractor3": "from radicals to conservatives.",
        "distractor4": "from the upper to the lower chambers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government under the Articles of Confederation can best be described as",
        "correct_answer": "weak and ineffective.",
        "distractor1": "overly prone to intervention in foreign affairs.",
        "distractor2": "overly bureaucratic.",
        "distractor3": "dictatorial.",
        "distractor4": "a personal tool of George Washington. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a source of revenue for the United States government underthe Articles of Confederation?",
        "correct_answer": "taxes levied by the Continental Congress",
        "distractor1": "printing its own money",
        "distractor2": "selling off western lands",
        "distractor3": "state governments",
        "distractor4": "All of the above were revenue sources. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a problem with the national government under the Articlesof Confederation?",
        "correct_answer": "the lack of power given to state legislatures",
        "distractor1": "the unwillingness of the states to send money requisitioned by the central national government",
        "distractor2": "the lack of an executive to lead the nation",
        "distractor3": "the inability of the central national government to regulate foreign trade or regulate the national economy",
        "distractor4": "None of these were problems at the time. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Articles of Confederation most governmental power rested in",
        "correct_answer": "the state governments.",
        "distractor1": "the national government.",
        "distractor2": "the president.",
        "distractor3": "the Congress.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Revolution, a major power shift occurred in the states from ________ to ________.",
        "correct_answer": "wealthy individuals; broad middle class ",
        "distractor1": "the broad middle class; a handful of wealthy individuals",
        "distractor2": "countryside; city",
        "distractor3": "city; countryside",
        "distractor4": "the east coast; the western interior"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the American Revolution, state legislatures were composed of",
        "correct_answer": "significantly more middle-class representatives and fewer wealthy members compared to before the war.",
        "distractor1": "revolutionary war militiamen.",
        "distractor2": "about the same ratio of wealthy members and not so wealthy members as before the war.",
        "distractor3": "significantly more landless laborers and poor farmers than any other group.",
        "distractor4": "a higher percentage of wealthy planters, lawyers, and merchants than ever before. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Right after the Revolutionary War, a dramatic change swept through the new countryresulting in",
        "correct_answer": "a dramatic increase in democracy and freedom.",
        "distractor1": "a population shift from the cities to the country.",
        "distractor2": "a population shift from country to city.",
        "distractor3": "an explosion in prosperity.",
        "distractor4": "full-scale industrialization. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Articles of Confederation, Congress had the power to",
        "correct_answer": "maintain an army and navy.",
        "distractor1": "levy taxes.",
        "distractor2": "overturn state laws.",
        "distractor3": "regulate commerce.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT occurring in the states during the time of the Articles ofConfederation?",
        "correct_answer": "upper-class dominance",
        "distractor1": "abolishment of religious qualifications for holding office",
        "distractor2": "adoption of bills of rights",
        "distractor3": "expanded political participation",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Articles of Confederation, power in the states began to shift to the hands of",
        "correct_answer": "middle-class farmers and craft workers.",
        "distractor1": "merchants and lawyers.",
        "distractor2": "governors.",
        "distractor3": "low-income landowners.",
        "distractor4": "new industrialists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In post-Revolutionary America, state governors were often selected by",
        "correct_answer": "state legislatures. ",
        "distractor1": "judges.",
        "distractor2": "the president.",
        "distractor3": "heredity.",
        "distractor4": "the people directly."
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of the Revolutionary War,",
        "correct_answer": "a postwar depression severely hurt small farmers and many others.",
        "distractor1": "captured British troops were herded into large prison camps where they served life sentences for their treachery.",
        "distractor2": "a strong, new national government began immediately to keep the economy running smoothly with careful regulation.",
        "distractor3": "the condition of the economy was largely the same as it had been before the war.",
        "distractor4": "a period of tremendous economic prosperity began. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A small band of farmers in western Massachusetts took up arms in what is remembered as",
        "correct_answer": "Shays ยน Rebellion. ",
        "distractor1": "the Farmers ยน Revolt.",
        "distractor2": "King George's War.",
        "distractor3": "the Boston Tea Party.",
        "distractor4": "the Whiskey Rebellion."
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Revolution, James Madison observed that   the most common and durable source offaction has been",
        "correct_answer": "the various and unequal divisions of property.  ",
        "distractor1": "urban and rural divisions.  ",
        "distractor2": "aristocracy.  ",
        "distractor3": "the British army.  ",
        "distractor4": "racial inequalities.   "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the top of the political agenda during the period of the Articles of Confederation was",
        "correct_answer": "economic issues.",
        "distractor1": "social-equality issues.",
        "distractor2": "military issues.",
        "distractor3": "voting rights issues.",
        "distractor4": "slavery. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the factors that contributed to economic turmoil under the Articles of Confederationwas the",
        "correct_answer": "postwar depression that left many small farmers unable to pay their debts and threatened mortgage foreclosures.",
        "distractor1": "decreasing economic viability of slavery.",
        "distractor2": "power shift from middle-class farmers to wealthy landowners.",
        "distractor3": "state legislatures that favored creditors and created more debt.",
        "distractor4": "All of these factors contributed to the economic turmoil. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Shays ยน Rebellion was",
        "correct_answer": "an uprising by farmers to prevent judges from foreclosing on farms. ",
        "distractor1": "the most decisive battle of the Revolution, after which British troops were never again able to mount a major offensive against American troops.",
        "distractor2": "a slave uprising in Virginia.",
        "distractor3": "an uprising by small merchants demanding credit.",
        "distractor4": "an uprising by Revolutionary War veterans demanding pensions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state boycotted the Constitutional Convention?",
        "correct_answer": "Rhode Island",
        "distractor1": "Texas, because it took too long to get to Philadelphia",
        "distractor2": "Virginia",
        "distractor3": "No state boycotted.",
        "distractor4": "Both Virginia and Rhode Island boycotted. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the significance of the Annapolis meeting?",
        "correct_answer": "It issued the original call for the Constitutional Convention in Philadelphia. ",
        "distractor1": "It was the first national convention of women demanding the right to vote.",
        "distractor2": "It issued the Declaration of Independence.",
        "distractor3": "It dissolved the Continental Congress.",
        "distractor4": "It selected George Washington as the first post-Revolutionary president."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Annapolis, Maryland, in 1786, delegates from five states met to discuss",
        "correct_answer": "the problems of the national government under the Articles of Confederation.",
        "distractor1": "the need to declare independence from England.",
        "distractor2": "the need for a Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor3": "the issue of slavery.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who met at the Constitutional Convention in 1787 were",
        "correct_answer": "wealthy planters, lawyers, and merchants.",
        "distractor1": "a mix of wealthy and middle-class Americans.",
        "distractor2": "overwhelmingly middle-class farmers.",
        "distractor3": "primarily British officials overseeing the implementation of the new government agreed to in the peace treaty.",
        "distractor4": "split evenly between Democrats and Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the original, sole, and express purpose of the convention in Philadelphia?",
        "correct_answer": "to revise the Articles of Confederation",
        "distractor1": "to choose the first president",
        "distractor2": "to negotiate the peace treaty with Great Britain",
        "distractor3": "to abolish the Articles of Confederation",
        "distractor4": "to grant women the right to vote "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a characteristic of the 55 delegates who attended theConstitutional Convention?",
        "correct_answer": "Most were residents of the western frontiers.",
        "distractor1": "They were all men.",
        "distractor2": "A significant number were urbanites.",
        "distractor3": "Many were college graduates.",
        "distractor4": "They were mostly wealthy planters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first two weeks of the Constitutional Convention were spent debating",
        "correct_answer": "the nature of republican government.",
        "distractor1": "the economic structure of the new government.",
        "distractor2": "the terms of Britain's surrender.",
        "distractor3": "military issues and the need for a standing army.",
        "distractor4": "practical political issues. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to James Madison and many of the delegates at the Constitutional Convention,what is the primary source of political conflict?",
        "correct_answer": "unequal distribution of wealth ",
        "distractor1": "ignorance",
        "distractor2": "stupidity",
        "distractor3": "emotions",
        "distractor4": "religious beliefs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the delegates at the Constitutional Convention regarded what as the greatest threat togovernment?",
        "correct_answer": "factions",
        "distractor1": "kings",
        "distractor2": "slaves",
        "distractor3": "foreign adversaries",
        "distractor4": "charismatic leaders "
    },
    {
        "question": "The view of human nature most prevalent among the Founding Fathers was that",
        "correct_answer": "people are self-interested in acquiring wealth and power.",
        "distractor1": "men abhor power and the burdens that come with it.",
        "distractor2": "human nature can be perfected, given the right social and political institutions.",
        "distractor3": "people are basically cooperative and community-oriented.",
        "distractor4": "people are disorganized and without vision. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Delegates to the Constitutional Convention generally agreed on each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "issues of equality. ",
        "distractor1": "questions of human nature.",
        "distractor2": "the need for a limited government.",
        "distractor3": "the object and nature of a republican government.",
        "distractor4": "causes of political conflict."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Founding Fathers believed that a major source of political conflict was the",
        "correct_answer": "unequal distribution of property.",
        "distractor1": "government's attempt to preserve private property.",
        "distractor2": "absence of majority rule.",
        "distractor3": "religious differences in society.",
        "distractor4": "Indian tribes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________, offered as a proposal at the Constitutional Convention, called for each state tobe equally represented in Congress.",
        "correct_answer": "New Jersey Plan",
        "distractor1": "Equal Rights Amendment (ERA)",
        "distractor2": "Connecticut Compromise",
        "distractor3": "three-fifths compromise",
        "distractor4": "Virginia Plan "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most delegates to the Constitutional Convention believed that the secret of good governmentis a",
        "correct_answer": "balanced government.",
        "distractor1": "centralized government.",
        "distractor2": "government that is open and not secretive.",
        "distractor3": "popularly controlled government.",
        "distractor4": "strong executive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Virginia and New Jersey Plans introduced at the Constitutional Convention differedmainly over whether",
        "correct_answer": "states should send equal numbers of representatives to Congress.",
        "distractor1": "there should be a president.",
        "distractor2": "the states or the national government should regulate interstate commerce.",
        "distractor3": "there should be a legislative branch at the national level.",
        "distractor4": "slavery should be permitted in the country. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these was NOT one of the big three disagreements at the Constitutional Convention?",
        "correct_answer": "whether the courts should have the power of judicial review",
        "distractor1": "what to do about slavery",
        "distractor2": "who should have the right to vote",
        "distractor3": "whether or not the states should have an equal number of votes in Congress",
        "distractor4": "issues of equality "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution, each state was entitled to how many senators?",
        "correct_answer": "two ",
        "distractor1": "as many as it wanted to send",
        "distractor2": "none",
        "distractor3": "one",
        "distractor4": "It depended on the state's population."
    },
    {
        "question": "As originally established by the Constitution, the House of Representatives had how manymembers from each state?",
        "correct_answer": "It depended on the state's population.",
        "distractor1": "seven",
        "distractor2": "one",
        "distractor3": "two",
        "distractor4": "none "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the time of the constitutional convention, slavery",
        "correct_answer": "was illegal only in Massachusetts.",
        "distractor1": "existed only in Georgia and the Carolinas.",
        "distractor2": "was permitted in all thirteen states.",
        "distractor3": "was prohibited north of the Mason-Dixon line.",
        "distractor4": "was prohibited by the Connecticut Compromise, which was never put into effect. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Connecticut Compromise at the Constitutional Convention",
        "correct_answer": "resolved the impasse between those who favored the New Jersey Plan and those who preferred the Virginia Plan.",
        "distractor1": "added the Bill of Rights to the Constitution in order to lessen concerns about too much power for the new government.",
        "distractor2": "settled the dispute over whether slavery should be allowed in the final constitution.",
        "distractor3": "threw out the idea of having a monarchy in the United States, opting instead for an indirectly elected president.",
        "distractor4": "involved all of these elements. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitutional Convention dealt with slavery by",
        "correct_answer": "recognizing it by providing for the return of escaped slaves.",
        "distractor1": "prohibiting it only north of the Mason-Dixon line.",
        "distractor2": "prohibiting it after twenty years.",
        "distractor3": "counting the slaves as a full part of the population for the purposes of representation in the House.",
        "distractor4": "emancipating slaves on the principle of equality. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding the right to vote in national elections, the framers of the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "decided to leave it up to the individual states to determine voter qualifications in their own states.",
        "distractor1": "required that all free, adult males with property worth at least $50 be allowed to vote.",
        "distractor2": "finally granted women the right to vote.",
        "distractor3": "included a requirement that all free, adult males be allowed to vote.",
        "distractor4": "provided that free men and women over the age of 20 be allowed to vote. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT one of the economic difficulties the writers of theConstitution attempted to address?",
        "correct_answer": "lack of unemployment compensation and welfare payments",
        "distractor1": "some states kept printing virtually worthless money",
        "distractor2": "the tariffs states had erected against one another to protect their state-made products",
        "distractor3": "the difficulty of the Continental Congress in raising money from the states",
        "distractor4": "All of these were dealt with in the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The debate at the Philadelphia Convention over eligibility to vote was resolved by",
        "correct_answer": "leaving it up to the individual states.",
        "distractor1": "allowing all males, but no females to vote.",
        "distractor2": "requiring voter registration before one would be eligible to vote.",
        "distractor3": "requiring universal manhood suffrage.",
        "distractor4": "permitting all citizens over 21 to vote. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A major purpose of the economic provisions in the Constitution was to",
        "correct_answer": "create a strong national government so as to bring stability out of economic chaos. ",
        "distractor1": "promote a more equal distribution of wealth in the country.",
        "distractor2": "guarantee the states a significant economic role.",
        "distractor3": "preserve and strengthen the farm economy to the disadvantage of manufacturing.",
        "distractor4": "establish a comprehensive set of social welfare programs to assist people in times of need."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations was NOT considered an economic problem by the writers ofthe Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "National taxes were too high. ",
        "distractor1": "States put up tariffs against products from other states.",
        "distractor2": "Paper money was virtually worthless in some states.",
        "distractor3": "The economy was in a recession.",
        "distractor4": "States were passing laws favoring debtors over creditors."
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to the government under the Articles of Confederation, the Constitution gave thecentral government",
        "correct_answer": "more economic powers.",
        "distractor1": "far fewer powers.",
        "distractor2": "total control of the economy.",
        "distractor3": "about the same economic powers.",
        "distractor4": "almost no economic powers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to put the national economy on sound footing, the Constitution obligated the newgovernment to ________ all the government debts incurred under the Continental Congress.",
        "correct_answer": "repay",
        "distractor1": "forgive",
        "distractor2": "renegotiate at lower interest rates",
        "distractor3": "renegotiate at higher interest rates",
        "distractor4": "negate "
    },
    {
        "question": "The framers of the Constitution gave the chief economic policymaking role to",
        "correct_answer": "Congress.",
        "distractor1": "the courts.",
        "distractor2": "the Federal Reserve Board.",
        "distractor3": "the president.",
        "distractor4": "the states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution prohibited the states from doing each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "establishing a republican form of government.",
        "distractor1": "harboring runaway slaves.",
        "distractor2": "placing duties on imports from other states.",
        "distractor3": "printing paper money.",
        "distractor4": "interfering with lawfully contracted debts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The delegates to the Constitutional Convention did not worry about preserving individualrights for all of the following reasons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "they included a bill of rights in Article V.",
        "distractor1": "every state had its own bill of rights.",
        "distractor2": "they were constructing a limited government that could not threaten personal freedoms.",
        "distractor3": "they dispersed power so that each branch or level could constrain the other.",
        "distractor4": "the various states were already doing a sufficient job of protecting individual rights. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Each of the following violations of individual rights is forbidden in the original ConstitutionEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "suspension of freedom of speech. ",
        "distractor1": "passing ex post facto laws.",
        "distractor2": "strict limits on the prosecution of treason.",
        "distractor3": "passing bills of attainder.",
        "distractor4": "suspension of the writ of habeas corpus."
    },
    {
        "question": "The government designed at the Constitutional Convention allowed the voters to directly elect",
        "correct_answer": "only the House of Representatives. ",
        "distractor1": "both the House and Senate.",
        "distractor2": "the president and all members of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "only the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "only the president."
    },
    {
        "question": "Madisonian principles in the Constitution were based on",
        "correct_answer": "concern that government would be dominated by a majority or minority faction.",
        "distractor1": "states ยน rights.",
        "distractor2": "a concentration of power, so that the minority faction could dominate the government.",
        "distractor3": "the belief that government should always be dominated by the majority.",
        "distractor4": "the ideas of a group of professors at Madison University. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The one element of government that Madison's plan placed within direct control of the voterswas the",
        "correct_answer": "House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "Senate.",
        "distractor2": "presidency.",
        "distractor3": "Congress.",
        "distractor4": "Supreme Court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Two key elements of the Madisonian model were to",
        "correct_answer": "keep most of the government beyond the control of a popular majority and separate the powers of different institutions.",
        "distractor1": "promote state power while separating the powers of different national institutions.",
        "distractor2": "keep as much of the government as possible beyond the control of a popular majority and extend the right to vote to everyone.",
        "distractor3": "combine the powers of different institutions and create a powerful presidency.",
        "distractor4": "require a system of checks and balances and extend democracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The system of checks and balances in the Constitution means that",
        "correct_answer": "change usually comes slowly, if at all, and moderation and compromise are typical in our political system.",
        "distractor1": "a majority can easily manipulate the system, but a minority cannot.",
        "distractor2": "changes in government policy can be made with relative ease, with few obstacles to stop a popular new force.",
        "distractor3": "we have a direct democracy, with all branches equally accessible to strong public pressure.",
        "distractor4": "each branch of government has its own powers independent of the other. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Madisonian requirement that each branch of government acquire the consent of the othersfor many of its actions created a system of",
        "correct_answer": "checks and balances.",
        "distractor1": "confederated government.",
        "distractor2": "constitutional republic.",
        "distractor3": "cross-cutting requirements.",
        "distractor4": "separation of powers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Madisonian system",
        "correct_answer": "has a conservative bias favoring the status quo.",
        "distractor1": "is a form of direct democracy.",
        "distractor2": "encourages change.",
        "distractor3": "discourages moderation and compromise.",
        "distractor4": "both C and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the Madisonian model, people desiring change",
        "correct_answer": "must usually have a sizable majority.",
        "distractor1": "find a government that is highly responsive and acts quickly and decisively.",
        "distractor2": "have no chance of victory.",
        "distractor3": "need only win at one point in the policymaking process.",
        "distractor4": "need just a simple majority over 50 percent. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federalist Papers were",
        "correct_answer": "essays in support of ratification of the constitution.",
        "distractor1": "essays written that were critical of the constitution.",
        "distractor2": "newspapers which backed the Federalist party in early United States elections.",
        "distractor3": "the original name of the constitution written by the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor4": "the notes that George Washington took at the Constitutional Convention. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ratification of the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "needed the approval of nine states.",
        "distractor1": "needed the approval of a majority of the people.",
        "distractor2": "occurred when it was approved by the delegates to the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor3": "needed the approval of all the states.",
        "distractor4": "was by two-thirds vote of the Continental Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Anti-Federalists is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The Anti-Federalists were basically unpatriotic and un-American.",
        "distractor1": "The Anti-Federalists fought to prevent ratification of the new constitution.",
        "distractor2": "The Anti-Federalists believed that the new government was an enemy of freedom.",
        "distractor3": "The Anti-Federalists believed the new government would erode fundamental liberties.",
        "distractor4": "The Anti-Federalists believed the new Constitution was a class-based document. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bill of Rights was added to the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "after the ratification process was complete, and partly to fulfill a promise to those who supported ratification.",
        "distractor1": "during the ratification process, before final ratification of the constitution.",
        "distractor2": "during the Constitutional Convention, at the insistence of Thomas Jefferson.",
        "distractor3": "in 1865 after the union victory in the Civil War.",
        "distractor4": "piece by piece during the first hundred years of its operation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ratification of the Constitution was done by",
        "correct_answer": "special conventions in each state.",
        "distractor1": "the voters in each state casting open ballots.",
        "distractor2": "the state legislatures approving the document.",
        "distractor3": "approval by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "majority vote of the delegates at the Constitutional Convention. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution was ratified by",
        "correct_answer": "special conventions in each of the states.",
        "distractor1": "popular vote in each of the states.",
        "distractor2": "the electoral college.",
        "distractor3": "state representatives to the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor4": "the state legislatures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The amendments that have been added to the Constitution have made it",
        "correct_answer": "more egalitarian and democratic.",
        "distractor1": "more elitist and undemocratic.",
        "distractor2": "more protective of property rights.",
        "distractor3": "weaker and less significant to American society.",
        "distractor4": "much more like the European constitutions it originally condemned. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Constitutional amendments are usually ratified by",
        "correct_answer": "legislatures of three-fourths of the states. ",
        "distractor1": "state conventions called by two-thirds vote in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "a national convention.",
        "distractor3": "a majority of the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "a two-thirds vote in each house of Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important effect of the constitutional amendments has been to",
        "correct_answer": "expand liberty and equality.",
        "distractor1": "reinforce elite control of government.",
        "distractor2": "expand the powers of the states.",
        "distractor3": "strengthen the capitalist economy.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Public opinion polls showed little support for the ERA after 1960.",
        "distractor1": "The ERA was opposed by many southern states.",
        "distractor2": "The ERA was proposed by Congress in 1978.",
        "distractor3": "The ERA was first proposed in 1923.",
        "distractor4": "The ERA never became part of the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To propose a formal amendment to the Constitution, one needs to have a",
        "correct_answer": "two-thirds vote in Congress.",
        "distractor1": "three-quarters vote in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "national convention requested by half of the states.",
        "distractor3": "majority vote of the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "the president's approval. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The failure of the Equal Rights Amendment showed that",
        "correct_answer": "a national majority in favor of an amendment is not sufficient to add it to the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "Congress was unwilling to support a measure opposed by a strong minority of the public.",
        "distractor2": "most states did not want to grant constitutional equality to women.",
        "distractor3": "we are a democracy, and majority opinion prevails.",
        "distractor4": "men are pigs, still unwilling to grant women equal rights. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is established by the written Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "None of these are mentioned in the written Constitution. ",
        "distractor1": "the right to an abortion",
        "distractor2": "media coverage of the House and Senate",
        "distractor3": "political parties",
        "distractor4": "All of these are mentioned in the written Constitution."
    },
    {
        "question": "Informal changes to the Constitution have reflected changes in all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "constitutional amendments.",
        "distractor1": "technology.",
        "distractor2": "political practice.",
        "distractor3": "judicial interpretation.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "How has the electoral college changed from the original intent of the framers?",
        "correct_answer": "Almost all electors now vote for the presidential candidate who wins the most popular votes in their state.",
        "distractor1": "Affirmative action programs have made the student body much more diverse, although standards have also been lowered.",
        "distractor2": "The president must now be elected by two-thirds vote of the electoral college rather than a simple majority.",
        "distractor3": "The number of electors has decreased dramatically.",
        "distractor4": "Today, the electors vote for whom they personally feel would make the best president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court in Marbury v. Madison (1803) asserted the power of the Court to",
        "correct_answer": "check the actions of the other branches through judicial review.",
        "distractor1": "nullify constitutional amendments.",
        "distractor2": "confirm presidential appointments.",
        "distractor3": "determine its own size and makeup.",
        "distractor4": "impeach the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political parties are an important example of the",
        "correct_answer": "unwritten constitution.",
        "distractor1": "Third Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "formal amendment process.",
        "distractor3": "wishes of the founders.",
        "distractor4": "rigidity of the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about judicial interpretation is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The power of judicial interpretation is explicitly stated in the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "Judicial interpretation can profoundly affect how the Constitution is understood.",
        "distractor2": "The power of judicial review gives courts the right to decide whether legislative actions are in accord with the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "In the case of Marbury v. Madison, the Supreme Court decided it would be the one to decide constitutional disputes.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The development of the two-party system is an example of informal constitutional changethrough",
        "correct_answer": "political practice.",
        "distractor1": "technology.",
        "distractor2": "judicial interpretation.",
        "distractor3": "increasing demands on policymakers.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "does not prescribe the function and structure of government in detail.",
        "distractor1": "lists the executive departments that are required to advise the president.",
        "distractor2": "is one of the oldest and longest constitutions in the world.",
        "distractor3": "gives particular detail to the function of the judiciary.",
        "distractor4": "was modeled on the British Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is FALSE about the Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "It discourages hyperpluralism.",
        "distractor1": "It creates many government access points where groups can attempt to initiate or block policy changes.",
        "distractor2": "It places many limits on the government's powers.",
        "distractor3": "It protects individual liberty.",
        "distractor4": "It creates government gridlock and inaction. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Some scholars have suggested that a consequence of separation of powers and checks andbalances has been",
        "correct_answer": "fragmented policymaking processes.",
        "distractor1": "the inability of groups to get their grievances heard.",
        "distractor2": "the tyranny of the majority.",
        "distractor3": "streamlined, but hasty, government decision making.",
        "distractor4": "political instability. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The separation of powers and the checks and balances established by the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "allow almost all groups some place in the political system where their demands for public policy can be heard.",
        "distractor1": "have acted to discourage the growth of groups in American society.",
        "distractor2": "have made the United States one of the most democratic countries in the world.",
        "distractor3": "create so many obstacles that groups have no place for their policy demands to be heard.",
        "distractor4": "are basically undemocratic since only elites can formulate policies within the system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federalism is",
        "correct_answer": "a system of shared power by the state and national governments.",
        "distractor1": "the same as unitary government.",
        "distractor2": "sole government authority in the national government.",
        "distractor3": "sole government authority in the states.",
        "distractor4": "a three-branch government with a system of checks and balances. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federalism is",
        "correct_answer": "practiced by fewer than 20 nations worldwide. ",
        "distractor1": "unique to the United States alone.",
        "distractor2": "practiced by about half the nations worldwide.",
        "distractor3": "practiced in about half the American states.",
        "distractor4": "practiced by nearly all of the 190 nations worldwide."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true?",
        "correct_answer": "No unitary governments are democratic.",
        "distractor1": "Few countries have federal systems.",
        "distractor2": "Most federal systems are democracies.",
        "distractor3": "Authoritarian regimes generally do not use federalist systems.",
        "distractor4": "Only some democracies use federal systems. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the governments in the world today are ________, in which all power resides in thecentral national government.",
        "correct_answer": "unitary",
        "distractor1": "federalist",
        "distractor2": "nationalist",
        "distractor3": "confederations",
        "distractor4": "fiscal "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "The American states have unitary governments.",
        "distractor1": "Federalism is the typical way nations organize their governments.",
        "distractor2": "Great Britain has a federal system.",
        "distractor3": "Most European countries are confederations.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "How is a unitary system different from a federal one?",
        "correct_answer": "The national government can change the boundaries of states, or abolish them.",
        "distractor1": "The national government can coin money, conduct foreign relations, and declare war.",
        "distractor2": "State governments have political autonomy and can nullify national laws.",
        "distractor3": "Administrative subunits, such as states, can collect taxes, conduct elections, and make laws independently of the national government.",
        "distractor4": "both B and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federalism is a way of organizing a nation so that",
        "correct_answer": "both national and state levels of government have authority over the same land and people.",
        "distractor1": "power is centralized in state and local government.",
        "distractor2": "there is one federal government and all regional governments are administrative subunits of it.",
        "distractor3": "power is centralized in the national government.",
        "distractor4": "there are three branches of government and a system of checks and balances. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following countries has federalism as its method of governing?",
        "correct_answer": "Canada",
        "distractor1": "China",
        "distractor2": "France",
        "distractor3": "Kenya",
        "distractor4": "No other country uses federalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal system",
        "correct_answer": "decentralizes our politics. ",
        "distractor1": "decreases judicial power.",
        "distractor2": "centralizes our politics.",
        "distractor3": "decreases opportunities for political participation.",
        "distractor4": "decreases the number of government officeholders."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an effect of federalism?",
        "correct_answer": "It simplifies the governmental system.",
        "distractor1": "Courts are called upon to be referees, and they gain power.",
        "distractor2": "It decentralizes political power.",
        "distractor3": "It creates more access points to government.",
        "distractor4": "It increases bureaucracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The power to directly regulate such things as drinking ages, marriage and divorce, and sexualbehavior has been granted",
        "correct_answer": "to state governments.",
        "distractor1": "to all governments by the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor2": "to the national government.",
        "distractor3": "to the president.",
        "distractor4": "to both the state and national governments. "
    },
    {
        "question": "States are responsible for most public policies dealing with each of the following issuesEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "economic issues.",
        "distractor1": "social issues.",
        "distractor2": "police powers.",
        "distractor3": "family issues.",
        "distractor4": "moral issues. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Laws that directly regulate abortion, drinking ages, marriage and divorce, or sexual behaviorare policy prerogatives that belong to",
        "correct_answer": "the states.",
        "distractor1": "the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor2": "Congress.",
        "distractor3": "local governments.",
        "distractor4": "federal courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are examples of how federalism decentralizes our policies EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "federal income tax.",
        "distractor1": "regulation of abortion.",
        "distractor2": "death penalty.",
        "distractor3": "funding of education.",
        "distractor4": "homeland security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT among the factors that tend to lead to the creation of a federal form ofgovernment in a country?",
        "correct_answer": "industrialization ",
        "distractor1": "large population",
        "distractor2": "diverse population",
        "distractor3": "large land area",
        "distractor4": "the existence of multiple religions"
    },
    {
        "question": "In our federal system, the powers of the state governments are ultimately granted by",
        "correct_answer": "the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "their state's Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "the people of their state.",
        "distractor3": "their state legislature.",
        "distractor4": "the United States government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Almost every policy the national government has adopted has originated with",
        "correct_answer": "the states.",
        "distractor1": "the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about federalism is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Federalism was hotly debated at the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor1": "Eighteenth-century Americans had little experience in thinking of themselves as Americans first and state citizens second.",
        "distractor2": "There was no other practical choice in 1787 but to create a federal system of government.",
        "distractor3": "Loyalty to state governments was so strong that the Constitution would have been resoundingly defeated had it tried to abolish them.",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; all are TRUE. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The supremacy clause of the Constitution states that all of the following are the supreme lawof the land, EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "state constitutions.",
        "distractor1": "laws of the national government (when consistent with the Constitution).",
        "distractor2": "the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "treaties of the national government (when consistent with the Constitution).",
        "distractor4": "both C and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution's supremacy clause",
        "correct_answer": "made the Constitution, the laws of the national government, and the national government's treaties the supreme law of the land.",
        "distractor1": "does not apply to state and local matters.",
        "distractor2": "gives the states superiority over the national government's Constitution and laws.",
        "distractor3": "is vague about which level of government should prevail in a dispute involving federalism.",
        "distractor4": "makes the president supreme in any constitutional conflicts with the other two branches. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The efforts of Candy Lightner and Mothers Against Drunk Driving (MADD) to raise the legaldrinking age to 21 are an example of",
        "correct_answer": "the ability of the national government to influence state policy. ",
        "distractor1": "the supremacy of state government to regulate its own affairs.",
        "distractor2": "the constitutional authority of the national government to impose policies on state governments.",
        "distractor3": "states acting as policy innovators.",
        "distractor4": "the unconstitutionality of age discrimination."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Constitution, the powers to coin money, to enter into treaties, and to regulate commercewith foreign nations and among the states were given to",
        "correct_answer": "the national government.",
        "distractor1": "neither the individual states nor the national government.",
        "distractor2": "the individual states.",
        "distractor3": "the Senate only.",
        "distractor4": "both the individual states and the national government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main criticism of the national bank created by the United States government?",
        "correct_answer": "It was an instrument of the elite and gave the national government too much control of the economy.",
        "distractor1": "It was printing too much worthless paper money which debtors were using to pay off their debts.",
        "distractor2": "It was charging exorbitant interest rates on its loans.",
        "distractor3": "It was borrowing too much money, putting the United States government hopelessly in debt.",
        "distractor4": "It did not efficiently distribute money to the states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The McCulloch v. Maryland case dealt with what specific grievance?",
        "correct_answer": "a state taxing a national bank",
        "distractor1": "toll bridges on interstate roads",
        "distractor2": "the location of Maryland's capital city",
        "distractor3": "a state coining its own money",
        "distractor4": "import taxes on goods made in other states "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of the supremacy of federal law over state law was affirmed in",
        "correct_answer": "McCulloch v. Maryland.",
        "distractor1": "Marbury v. Madison.",
        "distractor2": "the Tenth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "United States v. Darby.",
        "distractor4": "the presidential election of 1804. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court case of McCulloch v. Maryland (1819)",
        "correct_answer": "stated that the Constitution gave Congress implied powers.",
        "distractor1": "established Baltimore as the capital of Maryland.",
        "distractor2": "established the principle of judicial review.",
        "distractor3": "established the supremacy of state governments.",
        "distractor4": "recognized that Congress was limited to its enumerated powers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle that the national government has certain implied powers that go beyond itsenumerated powers was first elaborated in the Supreme Court's decision in",
        "correct_answer": "McCulloch v. Maryland.",
        "distractor1": "United States v. the States.",
        "distractor2": "Gibbons v. Ogden.",
        "distractor3": "Miranda v. Arizona.",
        "distractor4": "Marbury v. Madison. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The enumerated powers of Congress and the national government are those",
        "correct_answer": "specifically spelled out in the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "set out in the first ten amendments.",
        "distractor2": "involving taxes, spending, and fiscal policy.",
        "distractor3": "not specifically spelled out in the Constitution, but nonetheless acknowledged.",
        "distractor4": "requiring ratification by the states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal policies to regulate food and drugs, build interstate highways, protect consumers, tryto clean up dirty air and water, and do many other things are all justified as ________ ofCongress.",
        "correct_answer": "implied powers",
        "distractor1": "categorical grants",
        "distractor2": "constitutionally specified powers",
        "distractor3": "reserved powers",
        "distractor4": "enumerated powers "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution's provision that Congress has the right to   make all laws necessary andproper for carrying into execution   its powers is often referred to as the",
        "correct_answer": "elastic clause.",
        "distractor1": "enumerated powers.",
        "distractor2": "heart of fiscal federalism.",
        "distractor3": "Unwritten Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "privileges and immunities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following federal policies exemplifies the implied powers of Congress?",
        "correct_answer": "environmental protection law",
        "distractor1": "income tax",
        "distractor2": "the regulation of interstate commerce",
        "distractor3": "the provision of an army and a navy",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal policies to regulate food and drugs, build interstate highways, and protect consumersare all justified as",
        "correct_answer": "implied powers of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "presidential prerogatives.",
        "distractor2": "enumerated powers of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "delegated powers of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "both C and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court case of Gibbons v. Ogden",
        "correct_answer": "defined commerce as virtually every form of commercial activity.",
        "distractor1": "defined the meaning of the elastic clause.",
        "distractor2": "settled the contested presidential election of 1824.",
        "distractor3": "established the principle of implied powers.",
        "distractor4": "established the supremacy of the national government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Enumerated powers are those that are",
        "correct_answer": "stated in the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "reserved for the states.",
        "distractor2": "implied in the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "involving money matters.",
        "distractor4": "granted specifically to the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Abraham Lincoln announced in his 1861 inaugural address that he would willingly support aconstitutional amendment to",
        "correct_answer": "guarantee slavery. ",
        "distractor1": "prohibit states from seceding from the Union.",
        "distractor2": "return the United States to a confederation, with greater powers given to the states.",
        "distractor3": "establish the United States as a unitary system, where states would have to obey all national government decisions.",
        "distractor4": "outlaw slavery."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution requires that states give ________ to the public acts, records, and civil judicialproceedings of every other state.",
        "correct_answer": "full faith and credit",
        "distractor1": "privileges and immunities",
        "distractor2": "due process",
        "distractor3": "some consideration",
        "distractor4": "extradition "
    },
    {
        "question": "Contracts between business firms can be enforced across state boundaries as part of theconstitutional provision of",
        "correct_answer": "full faith and credit. ",
        "distractor1": "interstate compacts.",
        "distractor2": "privileges and immunities.",
        "distractor3": "implied powers of the states.",
        "distractor4": "extradition."
    },
    {
        "question": "A marriage license issued in one state is valid and honored in all states under theconstitutional provision of",
        "correct_answer": "full faith and credit.",
        "distractor1": "separation of powers.",
        "distractor2": "national supremacy.",
        "distractor3": "national licensure.",
        "distractor4": "privileges and immunities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fact that a driver's license from one state is valid in other states is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "full faith and credit.",
        "distractor1": "privileges and immunities.",
        "distractor2": "extradition.",
        "distractor3": "implied powers.",
        "distractor4": "unmandated reciprocity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The constitutional requirement that the states return a person charged with a crime in anotherstate to that state for trial or imprisonment is known as",
        "correct_answer": "extradition.",
        "distractor1": "forfeiture.",
        "distractor2": "privileges and immunities.",
        "distractor3": "full faith and credit.",
        "distractor4": "the elastic clause. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One recently controversial application of the   full faith and credit   provision of theConstitution is for",
        "correct_answer": "same gender marriages.",
        "distractor1": "extradition.",
        "distractor2": "birth certificates.",
        "distractor3": "bigamy.",
        "distractor4": "abortion "
    },
    {
        "question": "Extradition is the requirement that states",
        "correct_answer": "must return a person charged with a crime in another state to that state for trial or imprisonment.",
        "distractor1": "provide sanctuary for federal criminals.",
        "distractor2": "cannot discriminate against citizens of other states.",
        "distractor3": "recognize each others public acts, records, and civil judicial proceedings.",
        "distractor4": "enforce federal law within their state. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In ________ federalism, the powers and policy assignments of the different levels ofgovernment are distinct, like a layer cake.",
        "correct_answer": "dual",
        "distractor1": "fiscal",
        "distractor2": "tripartite",
        "distractor3": "cooperative",
        "distractor4": "anti- "
    },
    {
        "question": "The national government has exclusive control over foreign and military policy, the postalsystem, and monetary policy, while the states have exclusive control over other specific areas.This division of responsibilities reflects",
        "correct_answer": "dual federalism.",
        "distractor1": "divided government.",
        "distractor2": "tripartite federalism.",
        "distractor3": "cooperative federalism.",
        "distractor4": "fiscal federalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Saenz v. Roe, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "California could not require a new resident to wait one year before being eligible for welfare benefits.",
        "distractor1": "California was required to recognize the legality of same sex marriages.",
        "distractor2": "California could withhold educational benefits from children of illegal immigrants.",
        "distractor3": "California was required to offer bilingual education programs in the public elementary schools.",
        "distractor4": "California could not provide welfare benefits to illegal immigrants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A tuition difference between in-state and out-of-state students is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "how states make exceptions to the privileges and immunities clause.",
        "distractor1": "dual federalism.",
        "distractor2": "federal exceptions to the full faith and credit provision.",
        "distractor3": "full faith and credit being extended to all students.",
        "distractor4": "project grants to the states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If the allocation of power in a cooperative federal system were compared to a cake it would bemost like",
        "correct_answer": "fifty marbled cupcakes.",
        "distractor1": "a layer cake with two distinct layers.",
        "distractor2": "a single-layer cake.",
        "distractor3": "a cake walk: who gets what is random.",
        "distractor4": "a layer cake with many layers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If the allocation of power under dual federalism were compared to a cake it would be mostlike",
        "correct_answer": "a layer cake, with two distinct layers.",
        "distractor1": "a marbled cake where the flavors blend into each other.",
        "distractor2": "an angel food cakeรฎโฌโfluffy with little substance.",
        "distractor3": "New York cheesecakeรฎโฌโheavy and crushing under its own weight.",
        "distractor4": "a cupcake. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over time, there has been a gradual change from a dual federalism to a(n) ________federalism.",
        "correct_answer": "cooperative",
        "distractor1": "unitary",
        "distractor2": "single",
        "distractor3": "tripartite",
        "distractor4": "fiscal "
    },
    {
        "question": "In ________ federalism, the powers and policy assignments of different levels of governmentare like a marble cake, with mingled responsibilities and blurred distinctions between layers ofgovernment.",
        "correct_answer": "cooperative",
        "distractor1": "fiscal",
        "distractor2": "mixed",
        "distractor3": "dual",
        "distractor4": "tripartite "
    },
    {
        "question": "In dual federalism,",
        "correct_answer": "states and the national government each remain supreme within their own spheres. ",
        "distractor1": "the state governments assume greater fiscal responsibility.",
        "distractor2": "there are only two branches of government.",
        "distractor3": "the federal government assumes greater fiscal responsibility.",
        "distractor4": "powers are shared between states and the federal government."
    },
    {
        "question": "In cooperative federalism,",
        "correct_answer": "responsibilities are mingled and distinctions are blurred between the levels of government.",
        "distractor1": "states and the national government each remain supreme within their own spheres.",
        "distractor2": "powers and policy assignments of the layers of government are distinct.",
        "distractor3": "states are supreme over the national government.",
        "distractor4": "both A and B "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the ratification of the Constitution, American federalism has gradually changed from",
        "correct_answer": "dual to cooperative federalism.",
        "distractor1": "cooperative to dual federalism.",
        "distractor2": "state domination to national domination.",
        "distractor3": "a unitary to a federal system.",
        "distractor4": "a federal system to a unitary one. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about federalism is false?",
        "correct_answer": "The American system has always been neatly separated into purely state and purely national responsibilities.",
        "distractor1": "In cooperative federalism, sometimes even blame is shared when programs do not work well.",
        "distractor2": "In cooperative federalism, policy assignments are shared between states and the national government.",
        "distractor3": "Cooperative federalism today rests on several standard operating procedures.",
        "distractor4": "None; all are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal support for public education is an example of a",
        "correct_answer": "cooperative federalism.",
        "distractor1": "pragmatic federalism.",
        "distractor2": "dual federalism.",
        "distractor3": "layer cake federalism.",
        "distractor4": "separation of powers "
    },
    {
        "question": "Funding for the interstate highway system is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "cooperative federalism.",
        "distractor1": "dual federalism.",
        "distractor2": "tripartite federalism.",
        "distractor3": "a unitary system of government.",
        "distractor4": "national federalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Defense Education Act, the Elementary and Secondary Education Act, and theInterstate Highway System are all examples of",
        "correct_answer": "cooperative federalism.",
        "distractor1": "dual federalism.",
        "distractor2": "triangulation.",
        "distractor3": "layer cake federalism.",
        "distractor4": "unitary federalism "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a standard operating procedure of cooperative federalismtoday?",
        "correct_answer": "distinctly separated powers of state and national governments",
        "distractor1": "federal grants-in-aid",
        "distractor2": "shared administration of programs",
        "distractor3": "shared financing of government",
        "distractor4": "federal guidelines imposed on states "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT characterize the standard operating procedure ofcooperative federalism today?",
        "correct_answer": "separate and distinct roles for the national and state governments",
        "distractor1": "federal guidelines",
        "distractor2": "grants-in-aid",
        "distractor3": "shared costs",
        "distractor4": "shared administration "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard operating procedures in cooperative federalism include each of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "federal funding with no strings attached.",
        "distractor1": "shared administration.",
        "distractor2": "shared costs.",
        "distractor3": "federal guidelines.",
        "distractor4": "categorical and block grants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In cooperative federalism, in order to qualify for federal grant money, cities and states must",
        "correct_answer": "follow federal guidelines for adopting and enforcing federal laws.",
        "distractor1": "match federal funding dollar for dollar.",
        "distractor2": "propose standard operating procedures.",
        "distractor3": "allow federal agencies to administer the funds.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal regulation of state governments is usually accomplished through",
        "correct_answer": "attaching conditions to grants it gives them.",
        "distractor1": "United States Supreme Court decisions.",
        "distractor2": "presidential decrees.",
        "distractor3": "federalization of a state's national guard.",
        "distractor4": "direct, executive orders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "About ________ of the funds state and local governments spend comes from the federalgovernment.",
        "correct_answer": "25 percent",
        "distractor1": "33 percent",
        "distractor2": "50 percent",
        "distractor3": "75 percent",
        "distractor4": "90 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal aid to state and local governments accounts for how much of federal spending?",
        "correct_answer": "18 percent",
        "distractor1": "33 percent",
        "distractor2": "50 percent",
        "distractor3": "2 percent",
        "distractor4": "75 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The main instrument the national government uses to influence state governments is",
        "correct_answer": "grants-in-aid.",
        "distractor1": "mandates.",
        "distractor2": "judicial review.",
        "distractor3": "the Tenth Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "presidential decrees. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The main instrument the national government uses for both aiding and influencing states andlocalities is",
        "correct_answer": "grants-in-aid.",
        "distractor1": "judicial decisions.",
        "distractor2": "politics.",
        "distractor3": "mandates.",
        "distractor4": "revenue sharing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Of all the funds spent by state and local governments, federal aid accounts for about",
        "correct_answer": "one-fourth.",
        "distractor1": "two-thirds.",
        "distractor2": "one-half.",
        "distractor3": "three percent.",
        "distractor4": "one-third. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principal type of federal aid for states and localities is",
        "correct_answer": "categorical grants.",
        "distractor1": "disaster loans.",
        "distractor2": "revenue sharing.",
        "distractor3": "block grants.",
        "distractor4": "urban renewal grants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about categorical grants?",
        "correct_answer": "The federal government is less likely to apply conditions to these grants today than in the 1970s.",
        "distractor1": "There are several hundred specific purposes or categories for which these grants can be used.",
        "distractor2": "Virtually every one is enshrouded in rules and regulations for its use.",
        "distractor3": "A project grant is the most typical type of categorical grant.",
        "distractor4": "Categorical grants are monies that can be spent in broad categories of functions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The main type of federal aid to state and local governments is in the form of",
        "correct_answer": "categorical grants.",
        "distractor1": "block grants.",
        "distractor2": "formula grants.",
        "distractor3": "project grants",
        "distractor4": "revenue sharing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The requirement of a drinking age provision before states can receive federal highway aid isan example of",
        "correct_answer": "a string attached to categorical grants.",
        "distractor1": "an important element of the   formula   used to calculate formula grants.",
        "distractor2": "a project grant supported by the interest groups.",
        "distractor3": "the efforts of state agencies to get federal funds.",
        "distractor4": "an unfunded mandate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common type of categorical grant is",
        "correct_answer": "project grants.",
        "distractor1": "block grants.",
        "distractor2": "a rescission fund.",
        "distractor3": "disaster relief.",
        "distractor4": "revenue sharing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In contrast to the Democratic Congress of recent decades, the new Republican majority inCongress is passing more federal aid in the form of",
        "correct_answer": "block grants.",
        "distractor1": "revenue sharing.",
        "distractor2": "categorical grants.",
        "distractor3": "tax credits.",
        "distractor4": "tax expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "On the whole, federal grant distribution follows the principle of",
        "correct_answer": "universalism.",
        "distractor1": "stinginess.",
        "distractor2": "cronyism.",
        "distractor3": "to the victors go the spoils.",
        "distractor4": "needs-testing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Project grants",
        "correct_answer": "are awarded on the basis of competitive applications.",
        "distractor1": "have no strings attached.",
        "distractor2": "are distributed according to a specific formula.",
        "distractor3": "are automatically given to states and communities.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Grants for specific programs distributed according to community demographic factors, such aspopulation or income, are",
        "correct_answer": "formula grants.",
        "distractor1": "categorical grants.",
        "distractor2": "revenue sharing grants.",
        "distractor3": "project grants.",
        "distractor4": "block grants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicaid and Aid for Families with Dependent Children are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "formula grants.",
        "distractor1": "categorical grants.",
        "distractor2": "project grants.",
        "distractor3": "state grants.",
        "distractor4": "block grants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Grants that are given more or less automatically to states or communities, which havediscretion in deciding how to spend the money are called",
        "correct_answer": "block grants. ",
        "distractor1": "project grants.",
        "distractor2": "discretionary grants.",
        "distractor3": "formula grants.",
        "distractor4": "categorical grants."
    },
    {
        "question": "A broad program for community development would most likely be supported through a(n)",
        "correct_answer": "block grant. ",
        "distractor1": "formula grant.",
        "distractor2": "enterprise zone.",
        "distractor3": "project grant.",
        "distractor4": "categorical grant."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about federal block grants is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Congress has established an unlimited number of block grants to support narrowly defined programs.",
        "distractor1": "Block grants were created to lessen the paperwork and strings attached to many grants-in-aid.",
        "distractor2": "The Republican Congress is increasing block grants.",
        "distractor3": "States have discretion in deciding how to spend block grant money.",
        "distractor4": "They provide the states more flexibility in spending. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest percentage of federal grants to states and localities is in the area of",
        "correct_answer": "health.",
        "distractor1": "defense.",
        "distractor2": "transportation.",
        "distractor3": "education.",
        "distractor4": "homeland security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Expansions of mandated programs by the national government present especially difficultfunding problems for",
        "correct_answer": "state and local governments.",
        "distractor1": "Congress.",
        "distractor2": "federal taxpayers.",
        "distractor3": "foreign governments.",
        "distractor4": "the recipient of the service or program. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1995, the Republican majority in Congress, in contrast to previous Democratic Congresses,",
        "correct_answer": "limited the use of unfunded mandates.",
        "distractor1": "prohibited the states from using unfunded mandates.",
        "distractor2": "limited the use of block grants.",
        "distractor3": "avoided funded mandates.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicaid is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "a federal grant program that puts an economic strain on the states.",
        "distractor1": "a federal grant program that produces considerable competition between the states.",
        "distractor2": "a federal grant program that receives little support from the political parties.",
        "distractor3": "a federal block grant.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most equitably distributed in America?",
        "correct_answer": "federal aid to states and cities ",
        "distractor1": "income",
        "distractor2": "access to education",
        "distractor3": "taxes",
        "distractor4": "credit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "Federal grants can put an unwanted financial burden on states.",
        "distractor1": "When Congress imposes a program on the states, it also provides the funds for the program.",
        "distractor2": "Congress decreased funding of Medicaid in the 1980s to relieve state financial burdens.",
        "distractor3": "States are always seeking increases in grant programs.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Sometimes states tackle problems that are generally considered national problems. This ismost likely to occur when the federal government acts in a way that most state residents donot like. An example of this is",
        "correct_answer": "state funding for stem cell research in California.",
        "distractor1": "lowering the minimum wage.",
        "distractor2": "collecting taxes on purchases made on the Internet.",
        "distractor3": "restrictions on the chemicals that can be used for developing digital photographs.",
        "distractor4": "local school board policies about which textbooks are appropriate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Business interests have traditionally found their demands received most favorably by",
        "correct_answer": "state governments.",
        "distractor1": "the courts.",
        "distractor2": "Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the president.",
        "distractor4": "cities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federalism is advantageous for democracy for each of the following reasons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "increases the number of decisions and compromises made at the national level.",
        "distractor1": "allows for a greater diversity of opinion to be reflected in public policies.",
        "distractor2": "increases access to government.",
        "distractor3": "allows more opportunities for political participation.",
        "distractor4": "allows customization of policies for local needs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federalism contributes to democracy by each of the following ways EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "providing a means for unified public policy. ",
        "distractor1": "easing the burdens on the national government so it can function more effectively.",
        "distractor2": "increasing the opportunities for government to be responsive to demands for policies.",
        "distractor3": "increasing access to government.",
        "distractor4": "having state governments add thousands of elected offices for which citizens may vote or run."
    },
    {
        "question": "As a result of our federal form of government, the death penalty in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "varies substantially by state.",
        "distractor1": "is mandatory.",
        "distractor2": "is in violation of the Eighth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "is permissible at the federal level, but banned at the state level.",
        "distractor4": "is permissible because it is not considered cruel and unusual punishment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "How many governments are there in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "over 100,000",
        "distractor1": "538",
        "distractor2": "51",
        "distractor3": "one",
        "distractor4": "50 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "As the country became more industrialized and urbanized, economic interest groups turned to the state governments rather than the federal government for help.",
        "distractor1": "The federal government has given billions of dollars in subsidies to private industries.",
        "distractor2": "The national government took a direct interest in economic affairs from the very founding of the republic.",
        "distractor3": "As the country became more industrialized many interests asked the national government to restrain monopolies and encourage open competition.",
        "distractor4": "The national government has increasingly involved itself in the economic marketplace. "
    },
    {
        "question": "America's ________ society makes it more sensible to have Social Security administered on anational rather than a state-by-state basis.",
        "correct_answer": "mobile",
        "distractor1": "electronic",
        "distractor2": "free enterprise",
        "distractor3": "multi-ethnic",
        "distractor4": "aging "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, the national government spends roughly ________ of the gross domestic product.",
        "correct_answer": "20 percent",
        "distractor1": "15 percent",
        "distractor2": "2.5 percent",
        "distractor3": "9 percent",
        "distractor4": "44 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The proportion of the United States gross national product spent by state and localgovernments has ________ since 1929.",
        "correct_answer": "increased, but not nearly as fast as the national government's",
        "distractor1": "increased at a much faster rate compared to the national government",
        "distractor2": "dropped considerably",
        "distractor3": "remained steady",
        "distractor4": "dropped slightly "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, roughly ________ of the gross domestic product is spent by state and localgovernments.",
        "correct_answer": "1 percent ",
        "distractor1": "7.5 percent",
        "distractor2": "25 percent",
        "distractor3": "10 percent",
        "distractor4": "15 percent"
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, the national government spends about",
        "correct_answer": "a fifth of our gross domestic product.",
        "distractor1": "a tenth of our gross domestic product.",
        "distractor2": "a half of our gross domestic product.",
        "distractor3": "100 percent of our gross domestic product.",
        "distractor4": "a third of our gross domestic product. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the state governments is accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "They carry out virtually all the functions they always have, while the national government has taken on new functions.",
        "distractor1": "The national government has taken away nearly all the functions the states used to perform.",
        "distractor2": "The national government has taken away about half the functions the states used to perform.",
        "distractor3": "There has been a sharp decrease in the proportion of gross national product spent by states and localities since 1929.",
        "distractor4": "Their policy functions have nearly been taken over by the national government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans ยน civil liberties are set down in",
        "correct_answer": "the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor1": "the Declaration of Independence.",
        "distractor2": "Article I of the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "no written document or law.",
        "distractor4": "the Preamble to the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the final interpreter of the content and scope of Americans ยน civil liberties.",
        "correct_answer": "Supreme Court",
        "distractor1": "president",
        "distractor2": "Congress",
        "distractor3": "American Civil Liberties Union",
        "distractor4": "Constitution "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bill of Rights was written and proposed by",
        "correct_answer": "the First Congress of the United States in 1789.",
        "distractor1": "the United States Supreme Court in 1796.",
        "distractor2": "the Constitutional Convention in 1787.",
        "distractor3": "President George Washington in 1789.",
        "distractor4": "President Thomas Jefferson in 1801. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bill of Rights was adopted primarily in response to",
        "correct_answer": "British abuses of the colonists ยน civil liberties.",
        "distractor1": "the Spanish Inquisition.",
        "distractor2": "the abuses committed by the United States Continental Army during the Revolutionary War.",
        "distractor3": "the horrors of the French Revolution.",
        "distractor4": "Shays ยน Rebellion. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Bill of Rights is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Most state constitutions did not have a Bill of Rights at the time of the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor1": "The Bill of Rights was written by the First Congress of the United States.",
        "distractor2": "The Bill of Rights consists of the first ten amendments to the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "Many states made adoption of a Bill of Rights a condition of ratification of the Constitution.",
        "distractor4": "The Constitution of 1787 contained no Bill of Rights. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of ________, the Supreme Court ruled that the Bill of Rights restrained only thenational government, not states and cities.",
        "correct_answer": "Barron v. Baltimore",
        "distractor1": "Miranda v. Arizona",
        "distractor2": "New York v. the United States",
        "distractor3": "Engel v. Vitale",
        "distractor4": "Gitlow v. New York "
    },
    {
        "question": "The great freedoms of speech, press, religion, and assembly are contained in the",
        "correct_answer": "First Amendment. ",
        "distractor1": "First, Second, Third and Fourth Amendments.",
        "distractor2": "Fourth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "Second Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Third Amendment."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court decision in Barron v. Baltimore (1833) maintained that the Bill of Rightsintended to prevent",
        "correct_answer": "only the national government from abridging civil liberties.",
        "distractor1": "both the national and state governments from violating civil rights.",
        "distractor2": "cities from taking private property without due process.",
        "distractor3": "the states from infringing on individual rights.",
        "distractor4": "the United States government from granting titles of royalty. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, ________ apply to the states.",
        "correct_answer": "all but five provisions or amendments of the Bill of Rights ",
        "distractor1": "all of the Bill of Rights except the First Amendment",
        "distractor2": "all of the Bill of Rights",
        "distractor3": "none of the Bill of Rights",
        "distractor4": "four amendments of the Bill of Rights"
    },
    {
        "question": "Beginning with the case of ________ in 1925, the Supreme Court began to rule that the Bill ofRights applied directly to the states, as well as to the national government.",
        "correct_answer": "Gitlow v. New York ",
        "distractor1": "United States v. Bill of Rights",
        "distractor2": "Miranda v. Arizona",
        "distractor3": "Engel v. Vitale",
        "distractor4": "Barron v. Baltimore"
    },
    {
        "question": "In deciding to incorporate parts of the Bill of Rights into state laws since 1925, the SupremeCourt has relied on the due process clause of the",
        "correct_answer": "Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "First Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "Twenty-sixth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "Fifth Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Eighteenth Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ includes the clause   Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment ofreligion.  ",
        "correct_answer": "First Amendment",
        "distractor1": "Fifth Amendment",
        "distractor2": "Second Amendment",
        "distractor3": "Religious Rights Amendment",
        "distractor4": "Fourteenth Amendment "
    },
    {
        "question": "The incorporation doctrine involves",
        "correct_answer": "application of the Bill of Rights to the states.",
        "distractor1": "the government's power to regulate corporations.",
        "distractor2": "the procedures for creating a city government.",
        "distractor3": "the interpretation of the commerce clause.",
        "distractor4": "the extension of judicial review to state courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson argued that the First Amendment created a   wall of separation   between",
        "correct_answer": "church and state.",
        "distractor1": "the government and the people.",
        "distractor2": "the Congress, the president, and the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "the people and the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "men and women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Unlike Great Britain and many other nations, the United States does not have an ________church that is officially supported by the government and recognized as a national institution.",
        "correct_answer": "established ",
        "distractor1": "ecclesiastical",
        "distractor2": "adjudicated",
        "distractor3": "imperial",
        "distractor4": "incorporated"
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, ________ have (has) an established church that is officially supported by thegovernment.",
        "correct_answer": "Great Britain",
        "distractor1": "the United States",
        "distractor2": "no nation",
        "distractor3": "all nations",
        "distractor4": "both the United States and Great Britain "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Gitlow v. New York (1925), the decision that states could not abridge the freedoms ofexpression protected by the First Amendment was based on the",
        "correct_answer": "Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Fifth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "New York State Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "First Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "exclusionary rule of the judiciary. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The significance of Gitlow v. New York (1925) was that",
        "correct_answer": "a provision of the Bill of Rights was applied to the states for the first time.",
        "distractor1": "the national government was prevented from violating the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor2": "a state constitution had precedence over the United States Constitution within that state.",
        "distractor3": "the Bill of Rights was interpreted as restraining only the national government and not cities or states.",
        "distractor4": "the U.S. Constitution has precedence over the state constitution within the state. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Aid to parochial schools was first passed in the 1960s at the request of",
        "correct_answer": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor1": "Richard M. Nixon.",
        "distractor2": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor3": "John F. Kennedy.",
        "distractor4": "Barry Goldwater. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Lemon v. Kurtzman, the Supreme Court established that aid to church -related schools mustdo all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "inhibit religion.",
        "distractor1": "have a secular purpose.",
        "distractor2": "not advance religion.",
        "distractor3": "not create excessive government entanglement with religion.",
        "distractor4": "treat all religions equally. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The abridgment of citizens ยน freedom to worship, or not to worship, as they please is prohibitedby the",
        "correct_answer": "free exercise clause.",
        "distractor1": "due process clause.",
        "distractor2": "establishment clause.",
        "distractor3": "freedom of religion.",
        "distractor4": "Second Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In dealing with First Amendment cases involving religion, the Supreme Court has ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "while all religious beliefs are constitutionally protected, all religious practices are not.",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution does not protect anti-religious beliefs and practices.",
        "distractor2": "such questions should be resolved at the state and local levels of government.",
        "distractor3": "government must not interfere with any expression of religious faith.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Lemon v. Kurtzman decision of 1971, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "aid to church-related schools must be for secular purposes only, and cannot be used to advance or inhibit religion.",
        "distractor1": "any aid of any sort to church-related schools is not constitutional, because it violates church-state separation.",
        "distractor2": "aid to church-related schools is fully constitutional, and can be used for any purposes needed by the schools.",
        "distractor3": "spoken prayers in public schools were unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "devotional Bible-reading in public schools was unconstitutional. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Engel v. Vitale case of 1962, the Supreme Court ruled that ________ was (were)unconstitutional.",
        "correct_answer": "prayers done as classroom exercises in public schools",
        "distractor1": "the Connecticut statute barring the distribution of birth control information",
        "distractor2": "segregation",
        "distractor3": "prior restraint",
        "distractor4": "police search or seizure without an authorized warrant "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court has interpreted the establishment clause of the First Amendment as",
        "correct_answer": "prohibiting school-organized Bible-reading and prayer in public schools.",
        "distractor1": "grounds for denying federal aid to children attending parochial schools.",
        "distractor2": "merely preventing the establishment of a national church.",
        "distractor3": "allowing nondenominational school prayer.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court has ruled that government aid to church -related schools",
        "correct_answer": "is permitted when the aid is for a non-religious purpose.",
        "distractor1": "is acceptable for things such as field trips and teacher salaries, but not for textbooks or transportation to school.",
        "distractor2": "is acceptable if the school is affiliated with a major religion but not for small, fringe religious sects.",
        "distractor3": "violates the Establishment Clause.",
        "distractor4": "does not constitute an establishment of religion. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government aid to religious schools has been a major issue",
        "correct_answer": "since the mid 1960s.",
        "distractor1": "since the Civil War.",
        "distractor2": "since the colonial era.",
        "distractor3": "since ratification of the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor4": "since the growth of the fundamentalist movement in the 1980s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a free exercise issue?",
        "correct_answer": "teacher led prayers in public schools",
        "distractor1": "animal sacrifice",
        "distractor2": "religious use of peyote",
        "distractor3": "whether Amish children must go to school",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2005, the Supreme Court found that two Kentucky counties violated the establishmentclause of the First Amendment by",
        "correct_answer": "banning   intelligent design   from the curriculum",
        "distractor1": "establishing English as the   official first language of the State of Kentucky.  ",
        "distractor2": "by posting the Ten Commandments as a way of promoting religion.",
        "distractor3": "providing an   inefficient   system of public education.",
        "distractor4": "requiring students to say the Pledge of Allegiance. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1980s, the Supreme Court ________ the displaying of Christmas nativity scenes andHanukkah menorahs on public property.",
        "correct_answer": "upheld the constitutionality of",
        "distractor1": "refused to hear cases challenging",
        "distractor2": "first permitted and then prohibited",
        "distractor3": "declared unconstitutional",
        "distractor4": "encouraged "
    },
    {
        "question": "In free exercise cases, the Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "allows the government to interfere with religious practices as long as it is not specifically aimed at religion.",
        "distractor1": "permits the government to interfere with religious practices.",
        "distractor2": "prohibits prayer in public schools but permits government aid to religious schools.",
        "distractor3": "prohibits the government from interfering with religious practices.",
        "distractor4": "never allows the government to interfere with religious practices. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In regard to the free exercise clause, the Supreme Court has made each of the following rulingsEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "polygamy may be justified for Mormons on religious grounds.",
        "distractor1": "the Air Force can enforce its dress code even against religiously based dress choices.",
        "distractor2": "Amish parents may take their children out of school after the eighth grade.",
        "distractor3": "people could become conscientious objectors to war on religious grounds.",
        "distractor4": "public schools cannot require Jehovah's Witnesses to attend flag saluting ceremonies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In what case did the Supreme Court rule that a newspaper, no matter how outrageous itsopinions, must be allowed to publish without prior restraint?",
        "correct_answer": "Near v. Minnesota",
        "distractor1": "Wisconsin v. Yoder",
        "distractor2": "Miranda v. Arizona",
        "distractor3": "New York Times v. Sullivan",
        "distractor4": "Mapp v. Ohio "
    },
    {
        "question": "The extent of an individual's or group's freedom from prior restraint depends on",
        "correct_answer": "who the individual or group is.",
        "distractor1": "whether the nation is at war.",
        "distractor2": "nothingรฎโฌโit is absolute.",
        "distractor3": "the moods of the Supreme Court justices.",
        "distractor4": "the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pentagon Papers dealt with",
        "correct_answer": "a documented history of United States involvement in the Vietnam War which the government wanted kept secret.",
        "distractor1": "a documented history of United States involvement in the Korean War which the government wanted kept secret.",
        "distractor2": "prisoners of war from World War II.",
        "distractor3": "secret agreements between the United States and the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following elements of the Bill of Rights was extended to the states by theSupreme Court case of Near v. Minnesota?",
        "correct_answer": "freedom of the press",
        "distractor1": "freedom of speech",
        "distractor2": "right to counsel in felony cases",
        "distractor3": "grand jury requirement",
        "distractor4": "right to privacy "
    },
    {
        "question": "Time and time again, the Supreme Court has protected freedom of the press by",
        "correct_answer": "striking down prior restraint.",
        "distractor1": "ruling in favor of strict libel laws.",
        "distractor2": "refusing to allow the subpoena of reporters.",
        "distractor3": "relaxing due process procedures.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The case of Near v. Minnesota (1931)",
        "correct_answer": "held that government had illegally issued a prior restraint.",
        "distractor1": "ruled that newspapers could not publish secret information that threatens national security.",
        "distractor2": "ruled that states cannot prohibit animal sacrifice.",
        "distractor3": "identified an exception to the Constitutional guarantees barring government censorship of the press.",
        "distractor4": "upheld Minnesota's right to close down a newspaper making slanderous remarks. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior restraint is most often considered acceptable on the grounds of",
        "correct_answer": "national security.",
        "distractor1": "libel.",
        "distractor2": "obscenity.",
        "distractor3": "cruel and unusual punishment.",
        "distractor4": "religious freedom. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Schenck v. United States (1919), Justice Holmes said that speech can be restricted when it",
        "correct_answer": "provokes   a clear and present danger   to people.",
        "distractor1": "is uttered by government officials in an effort to establish a religion.",
        "distractor2": "advocates the violent overthrow of the United States.",
        "distractor3": "is spoken rather than non-verbal or symbolic.",
        "distractor4": "is expressed on private property. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Constitutional protections of free speech are ________ on private property .",
        "correct_answer": "diminished",
        "distractor1": "completely invalidated",
        "distractor2": "fully protected",
        "distractor3": "untested",
        "distractor4": "unchanged "
    },
    {
        "question": "A shield law",
        "correct_answer": "gives reporters the right to withhold information from the courts.",
        "distractor1": "gives judges the right to issue a gag order.",
        "distractor2": "protects certain religious practices not covered by Supreme Court rulings.",
        "distractor3": "prevents the courts from closing criminal trials to the press.",
        "distractor4": "prevents reporters from disclosing secret government information. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court ruled in Branzburg v. Hayes (1972) that in the absence of shield laws,",
        "correct_answer": "the right of a free trial preempts the reporter's right to protect sources.",
        "distractor1": "that newspaper files are protected by the First Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "that reporters have more rights than other citizens.",
        "distractor3": "judges can bar cameras from the courtroom.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Obscenity is",
        "correct_answer": "not protected under the Constitution. ",
        "distractor1": "equated with nudity by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "clearly defined as it pertains to both freedom of the press and freedom of speech.",
        "distractor3": "prohibited in the First Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "a matter of federal standards rather than state or local standards."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Zurcher v. Stanford Daily, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "the Stanford Daily must open its files for use as police evidence.",
        "distractor1": "the Stanford Daily had complete control over its photograph files.",
        "distractor2": "the Stanford Daily must cease publication of military strategy papers.",
        "distractor3": "the Stanford Daily must disclose the location of its reporters.",
        "distractor4": "the Stanford Daily is controlled by the University president, not state laws. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In ________, the Court clarified its doctrine of what was obscene, including such gauges aswhether material appealed to merely a prurient interest in sex, and whether it lacked seriousartistic, literary, political or scientific merit.",
        "correct_answer": "Miller v. California",
        "distractor1": "Osborne v. Ohio",
        "distractor2": "Engel v. Vitale",
        "distractor3": "Near v. Minnesota",
        "distractor4": "Federal Communications Commission v. Stern "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Miller v. California (1971), the Court ruled that decisions regarding whether or not materialwas obscene should generally be made by",
        "correct_answer": "local communities, with some guidelines provided by the Court itself about how to make such judgments.",
        "distractor1": "Congress, through statutory law.",
        "distractor2": "lower federal judges as they see fit, but in conformance with the First Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court itself, on a case-by-case basis.",
        "distractor4": "individual persons in their own private lives. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Miller v. California (1973)",
        "correct_answer": "stated that local communities should have more responsibility over deciding what constitutes obscenity.",
        "distractor1": "achieved a workable definition of legal obscenity.",
        "distractor2": "abolished pornographic material only when it involved children.",
        "distractor3": "resulted in uniform state laws regulating obscenity.",
        "distractor4": "prohibited hanging as a cruel and unusual punishment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Communications Decency Act banning obscene material and criminalizing thetransmission of indecent speech or images to anyone under the age of 18 was",
        "correct_answer": "overturned by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor1": "affirmed by the Court.",
        "distractor2": "opposed by Christian groups.",
        "distractor3": "the first regulation of obscenity affirmed by the Court.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the urging of feminists and conservative Christians, some cities have banned pornographyon the grounds it dehumanizes and endangers women. How have the courts dealt with thesebans?",
        "correct_answer": "They have struck them down as violations of the First Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "They have upheld them based on the Equal Protection Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "They have refused to review them.",
        "distractor3": "They have upheld them based on the First Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "The courts have been erratic, allowing some ordinances and revoking others. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened when Jacksonville, Florida, tried to ban movies with nudity in them frombeing shown at drive-in theaters on grounds of obscenity?",
        "correct_answer": "The Supreme Court ruled that all nudity cannot be deemed obscene.",
        "distractor1": "The Court upheld the ban to protect citizens ยน rights to privacy.",
        "distractor2": "The ban was upheld to help the community rid itself of a public nuisance and potential traffic hazard.",
        "distractor3": "The Court ruled that X-rated movies were protected under the First Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "a riot "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle that statements about public figures are libelous only if made with malice andreckless disregard for the truth was established in",
        "correct_answer": "New York Times v. Sullivan.",
        "distractor1": "Texas v. Johnson.",
        "distractor2": "Osborne v. Ohio.",
        "distractor3": "the Anti-Defamation Act of 1952.",
        "distractor4": "Hustler Magazine v. Falwell. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding libel is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Public figures are protected against libel since publications must prove that what they wrote is true and not malicious.",
        "distractor1": "Libel cases are very difficult for public figures to win.",
        "distractor2": "Libel laws do inhibit the press to some extent.",
        "distractor3": "General William Westmoreland failed to prove libel.",
        "distractor4": "It is more difficult for a public figure than a private individual to win a libel suit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Wearing an arm band and burning a United States flag are examples of ________: actions thatdo not consist of speaking or writing but that express an opinion.",
        "correct_answer": "symbolic speech",
        "distractor1": "commercial speech",
        "distractor2": "obscenity",
        "distractor3": "the free exercise clause",
        "distractor4": "unspoken speech "
    },
    {
        "question": "Symbolic speech",
        "correct_answer": "consists of action that expresses an opinion.",
        "distractor1": "consists of speech criticizing the symbols of government.",
        "distractor2": "cannot be prohibited because it is too vague for government to legislate against.",
        "distractor3": "has been ruled as disruptive and as a criminal activity.",
        "distractor4": "is prohibited under the First Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Advertising is considered a form of ________, and, according to the decisions of the SupremeCourt, is subject to greater restrictions on free speech than religious or political speech.",
        "correct_answer": "commercial speech ",
        "distractor1": "symbolic speech",
        "distractor2": "paid speech",
        "distractor3": "imaged expression",
        "distractor4": "propaganda"
    },
    {
        "question": "Commercial speech on radio and television is regulated by",
        "correct_answer": "the Federal Trade Commission.",
        "distractor1": "state and local governments.",
        "distractor2": "no government agency, as such would be a violation of the freedom of speech.",
        "distractor3": "the Federal Communications Commission.",
        "distractor4": "the Bureau of Consumer Affairs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most regulated forms of speech is",
        "correct_answer": "commercial speech. ",
        "distractor1": "symbolic speech.",
        "distractor2": "obscenity.",
        "distractor3": "libel.",
        "distractor4": "unintended speech."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2000, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "government regulation of sexually explicit material on cable stations must be narrowly tailored to promote the government's interest in protecting children.",
        "distractor1": "government had a legitimate interest in protecting sexually explicit material on cable stations.",
        "distractor2": "government had no right to regulate sexually explicit material on cable stations.",
        "distractor3": "government had a legitimate interest in prohibiting sexually explicit material on cable stations.",
        "distractor4": "government had a legitimate interest in protecting sexually explicit print material. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of ________, the Supreme Court ruled that requiring an organization to turn overits membership lists was an unconstitutional restriction on freedom of association.",
        "correct_answer": "NAACP v. Alabama",
        "distractor1": "Planned Parenthood v. Casey",
        "distractor2": "Near v. Minnesota",
        "distractor3": "Mapp v. Ohio",
        "distractor4": "United States v. Communist Party "
    },
    {
        "question": "The rights of accused persons included in the Bill of Rights were originally intended to protectthe accused in",
        "correct_answer": "political arrests and trials.",
        "distractor1": "federal civil cases.",
        "distractor2": "federal criminal cases.",
        "distractor3": "local civil and criminal cases.",
        "distractor4": "police custody. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To prevent abuse of police power, the Constitution requires that no court may issue ________unless probable cause exists to believe that a crime has occurred or is about to occur.",
        "correct_answer": "a search warrant",
        "distractor1": "a writ of habeas corpus",
        "distractor2": "a prior restraint",
        "distractor3": "an exclusionary rule",
        "distractor4": "any of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Viewing the stages of the criminal justice system as a series of funnels of decreasing size tellsus that",
        "correct_answer": "many more arrests occur than trials. ",
        "distractor1": "most arrests result in a trial.",
        "distractor2": "most trials result in a guilty verdict.",
        "distractor3": "many more trials are held than prosecutions.",
        "distractor4": "the likelihood of being punished decreases as one moves through the system."
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless they witness a crime, police officers cannot arrest a suspect without",
        "correct_answer": "probable cause.",
        "distractor1": "due process.",
        "distractor2": "a search warrant.",
        "distractor3": "informing them of their Miranda rights.",
        "distractor4": "a writ of habeas corpus. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ever since 1914, the courts have used ________ to prevent illegally seized evidence from beingintroduced into the courtroom.",
        "correct_answer": "an exclusionary rule ",
        "distractor1": "prior restraint",
        "distractor2": "the Miranda rule",
        "distractor3": "probable cause",
        "distractor4": "search warrants"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ Amendment forbids forced self-incrimination, stating that no person   shall becompelled to be a witness against himself.  ",
        "correct_answer": "Fifth",
        "distractor1": "First",
        "distractor2": "Twenty-sixth",
        "distractor3": "Fourth",
        "distractor4": "Ninth "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of Miranda v. Arizona, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "police must inform any suspect of a series of rights, including the constitutional right to remain silent.",
        "distractor1": "illegally obtained evidence cannot be used in a trial.",
        "distractor2": "the death penalty could be imposed for the most extreme of crimes.",
        "distractor3": "defendants in all felony cases have a right to counsel, even if the state has to provide such legal assistance.",
        "distractor4": "the police must show probable cause before making an arrest. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In what case did the Supreme Court rule that suspects must be told of their constitutionalrights to remain silent, that what they say can be used against them, and of their right to havean attorney present during any questioning?",
        "correct_answer": "Miranda v. Arizona",
        "distractor1": "Gideon v. Wainwright",
        "distractor2": "Near v. Minnesota",
        "distractor3": "Plucennik v. United States",
        "distractor4": "Mapp v. Ohio "
    },
    {
        "question": "Fifth Amendment rights were expanded to include guidelines for police interrogationprocedures in the famous case of",
        "correct_answer": "Miranda v. Arizona.",
        "distractor1": "California v. Simpson.",
        "distractor2": "Dennis v. United States.",
        "distractor3": "Gideon v. Wainwright.",
        "distractor4": "Mapp v. Ohio. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Miranda Rule",
        "correct_answer": "has required all police officers to inform accused persons of their rights. ",
        "distractor1": "has been strengthened by the Court in recent years.",
        "distractor2": "was openly welcomed by police departments throughout the country.",
        "distractor3": "has made police interrogations easier.",
        "distractor4": "was based on the probable cause clause of the Fourth Amendment."
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, courts must provide a lawyer for a defendant",
        "correct_answer": "whenever imprisonment could be imposed.",
        "distractor1": "only in felony cases or where civil fines exceeding $10,000 could be levied.",
        "distractor2": "whenever they plead not guilty.",
        "distractor3": "only in capital cases where the punishment would be execution.",
        "distractor4": "immediately after being arrested. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1963 case of ________, the Supreme Court ruled that defendants in all felony cases had aright to counsel, and if they could not afford to hire a lawyer, one must be provided.",
        "correct_answer": "Gideon v. Wainwright",
        "distractor1": "Mapp v. Ohio",
        "distractor2": "Engel v. Vitale",
        "distractor3": "Miranda v. Arizona",
        "distractor4": "National Bar Association v. United States "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution and the Bill of Rights, how many members should there be on ajury?",
        "correct_answer": "no specifications are made as to jury size ",
        "distractor1": "a minimum of six",
        "distractor2": "a minimum of twelve",
        "distractor3": "between six and twelve",
        "distractor4": "a maximum of twelve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most criminal cases are settled in",
        "correct_answer": "plea bargaining.",
        "distractor1": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "municipal and county courts.",
        "distractor3": "district court.",
        "distractor4": "the jury room. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court case of Gideon v. Wainwright",
        "correct_answer": "extended the right to counsel to everyone accused of a felony.",
        "distractor1": "prohibited government officials from issuing gag orders to the media.",
        "distractor2": "ruled that illegally seized evidence can not be used in court.",
        "distractor3": "gave only those accused of capital crimes the right to counsel.",
        "distractor4": "set guidelines for police questioning of suspects. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Sixth Amendment right to counsel in federal courts was expanded in the famous 1963Supreme Court case of",
        "correct_answer": "Gideon v. Wainwright.",
        "distractor1": "Gregg v. Georgia.",
        "distractor2": "Arizona v. the United States.",
        "distractor3": "Mapp v. Ohio.",
        "distractor4": "Miranda v. Arizona. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most cases are settled through",
        "correct_answer": "plea bargaining.",
        "distractor1": "paupers ยน petitions.",
        "distractor2": "judicial tribunals.",
        "distractor3": "trial by a judge.",
        "distractor4": "trial by jury. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Eighth Amendment to the Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "forbids cruel and unusual punishment.",
        "distractor1": "is the freedom of privacy.",
        "distractor2": "is the right to bear arms.",
        "distractor3": "grants women equal rights including the right to vote.",
        "distractor4": "protects freedom of assembly. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the Supreme Court's decision in Hamdam v. Rumsfeld?",
        "correct_answer": "The procedures for trying prisoners at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba were insufficient for ensuring a fair trial.",
        "distractor1": "Terrorists are not entitled to protection by the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor2": "The Geneva Convention does not apply because the   enemy combatants   are not soldiers in a recognized army.",
        "distractor3": "The president has   inherent power   to fight the war on terror as he sees fit. Therefore, the president can establish judicial procedures on his own.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Cruel and unusual punishment is forbidden by the",
        "correct_answer": "Eighth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "self-incrimination clause.",
        "distractor2": "Sixth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "exclusionary clause.",
        "distractor4": "Fifth Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT protected in the First Amendment?",
        "correct_answer": "right to privacy",
        "distractor1": "right of people to petition the government for a redress of grievances",
        "distractor2": "no establishment of religion",
        "distractor3": "freedom of speech",
        "distractor4": "freedom of the press "
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the right to privacy found in the Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Tenth Amendment",
        "distractor2": "First Amendment",
        "distractor3": "Sixth Amendment",
        "distractor4": "Ninth Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT specifically stated in the Bill of Rights?",
        "correct_answer": "right to privacy",
        "distractor1": "protection against double jeopardy",
        "distractor2": "right to bear arms",
        "distractor3": "freedom of speech",
        "distractor4": "All of these are specifically stated. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court ruled in its Roe v. Wade decision that",
        "correct_answer": "abortion could not be prohibited by any state during the first trimester of pregnancy. ",
        "distractor1": "each state and not the federal government has authority to determine whether to permit or prohibit abortion in that state.",
        "distractor2": "all restrictions on abortions at any stage of a pregnancy were a violation of a woman's right to privacy.",
        "distractor3": "abortion was murder.",
        "distractor4": "abortion was to be allowed only in cases of rape or incest, or when the life of the pregnant woman was in danger."
    },
    {
        "question": "Since its Roe v. Wade decision, the Supreme Court has",
        "correct_answer": "generally moved to allow states more room to regulate abortions (e.g., waiting periods) than was true in Roe.",
        "distractor1": "not moved an inch from its dramatic original ruling.",
        "distractor2": "greatly extended the right of a woman to make her own decision about terminating her pregnancy.",
        "distractor3": "reversed itself within the last few years, and has now overturned the Roe decision.",
        "distractor4": "been silent on the politically divisive issue of abortion. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The idea that the Constitution guarantees a right to privacy was first enunciated in",
        "correct_answer": "Griswold v. Connecticut.",
        "distractor1": "Marbury v. Madison.",
        "distractor2": "Roe v. Wade.",
        "distractor3": "Webster v. Reproductive Health Services.",
        "distractor4": "Planned Parenthood v. Casey. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The right to privacy was applied to the states by the Supreme Court case of",
        "correct_answer": "Griswold v. Connecticut. ",
        "distractor1": "Gitlow v. New York.",
        "distractor2": "Gitlow, Near & Mapp v. the States.",
        "distractor3": "Mapp v. Ohio.",
        "distractor4": "Near v. Minnesota."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important application of privacy rights has come in the area of",
        "correct_answer": "abortion.",
        "distractor1": "birth control.",
        "distractor2": "sexual preference.",
        "distractor3": "pornography.",
        "distractor4": "the death penalty. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court case of Roe v. Wade (1973) ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "a state cannot forbid abortions during the first trimester of pregnancy.",
        "distractor1": "abortions are not protected under the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "a state cannot regulate abortions under any circumstances.",
        "distractor3": "family planning services cannot provide women any abortion counseling.",
        "distractor4": "states must permit abortions on demand during all nine months of pregnancy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The abortion decision in Roe v. Wade (1973) was justified by the Supreme Court largely on thegrounds of",
        "correct_answer": "the right of privacy implied in the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor1": "the freedom of religion clause of the First Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "the free exercise clause of the First Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "our constitutional right to life.",
        "distractor4": "new advances in medical technology. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Civil liberties relating to defendants ยน rights have often been used to",
        "correct_answer": "protect individual rights.",
        "distractor1": "break up factions.",
        "distractor2": "enhance the power of the courts",
        "distractor3": "enhance diversity.",
        "distractor4": "gain a plea bargain. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Policies that extend basic rights to groups historically subject to discrimination are known as",
        "correct_answer": "civil rights.",
        "distractor1": "civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "human rights.",
        "distractor3": "suffrage.",
        "distractor4": "affirmative action. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Civil rights",
        "correct_answer": "are policies that extend basic rights to groups historically subject to discrimination.",
        "distractor1": "is the other term for civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "involve the principles of criminal justice.",
        "distractor3": "consist of legal and constitutional protections against the government.",
        "distractor4": "can be divided into the great political freedoms and protections at the bar of justice. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The phrase   all men are created equal   comes from the",
        "correct_answer": "Declaration of Independence.",
        "distractor1": "Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor2": "Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "famous pamphlet, Common Sense.",
        "distractor4": "Bible. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The concept that everyone should have the same chance is called equality of",
        "correct_answer": "opportunity. ",
        "distractor1": "distribution.",
        "distractor2": "fate.",
        "distractor3": "rewards.",
        "distractor4": "results."
    },
    {
        "question": "American society generally emphasizes equal",
        "correct_answer": "opportunity. ",
        "distractor1": "pay for equal work.",
        "distractor2": "results.",
        "distractor3": "rewards.",
        "distractor4": "distribution."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "The delegates to the Constitutional Convention did not resolve the tension between slavery and the principles of the Declaration of Independence.",
        "distractor1": "The American Revolution was fought principally in the name of equality.",
        "distractor2": "Women's rights were hotly debated at the Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor3": "Most colonists were eager to defend slavery.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Thomas Jefferson, who wrote in the Declaration of Independence   We hold these truths to beself evident, that all men are created equal,   believed",
        "correct_answer": "that blacks were genetically inferior to whites.",
        "distractor1": "that slavery was immoral.",
        "distractor2": "in the principle of equal rewards.",
        "distractor3": "that there were no differences among human beings.",
        "distractor4": "that all people are created equal at birth, but become unequal over time. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Fourteenth Amendment was one of three passed",
        "correct_answer": "directly following the Civil War.",
        "distractor1": "during the 1960s.",
        "distractor2": "during George Washington's administration.",
        "distractor3": "during the Depression of the 1930s.",
        "distractor4": "right after the Revolutionary War. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Fourteenth Amendment specifically forbids the states from denying to anyone",
        "correct_answer": "equal protection of the laws.",
        "distractor1": "freedom on the basis of race.",
        "distractor2": "freedom of privacy.",
        "distractor3": "the right to vote on the basis of race.",
        "distractor4": "the right to vote on the basis of sex. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first and only place in which the idea of equality appears in the Constitution is in the",
        "correct_answer": "Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Ninth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "Preamble.",
        "distractor3": "First Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Declaration of Independence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The concept of equality before the law was introduced to the Constitution in the",
        "correct_answer": "Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Preamble.",
        "distractor2": "Fifteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "Sixteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Thirteenth Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the last 100 years, the provisions of the Fourteenth Amendment have become the vehiclefor",
        "correct_answer": "expansive constitutional interpretation to outlaw arbitrary classifications which deny equality under the law.",
        "distractor1": "extending the right to vote to non-whites, women, and 18-year-olds.",
        "distractor2": "limiting the national government's ability to interfere in matters affecting individual states.",
        "distractor3": "government regulation of business and industry.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standards of review used by the Supreme Court in discrimination cases include all of thefollowing EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "more than reasonable.",
        "distractor1": "inherently suspect.",
        "distractor2": "reasonable.",
        "distractor3": "intermediate, between reasonable and inherently suspect.",
        "distractor4": "cautious. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The courts have recently ruled that, under the Fourteenth Amendment, racial and ethnicclassifications by states in regard to any matter",
        "correct_answer": "are inherently suspect.",
        "distractor1": "are reasonable.",
        "distractor2": "are unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "are not the proper business of the federal courts to consider, but are up to the states individually.",
        "distractor4": "are arbitrary, but usually reasonable. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Classifications by race and ethnicity have now been ruled by the Court to be acceptable only in",
        "correct_answer": "laws seeking to remedy previous discrimination.",
        "distractor1": "matters wherein certain races or ethnic groups show greater talent or less aptitude.",
        "distractor2": "laws passed by Congress, not those passed by the individual states.",
        "distractor3": "regard to rules and regulations of the armed forces.",
        "distractor4": "matters involving national security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Classifications based on gender have been ruled to be ________ by the decisions of the Courtin the past several years.",
        "correct_answer": "somewhere between inherently suspect and reasonable ",
        "distractor1": "reasonable",
        "distractor2": "strictly unconstitutional",
        "distractor3": "sexist",
        "distractor4": "inherently suspect"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first African immigrants to America were",
        "correct_answer": "kidnap victims.",
        "distractor1": "clergy.",
        "distractor2": "small shopkeepers.",
        "distractor3": "farmers.",
        "distractor4": "Nigerian ivory traders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today the equal protection clause is interpreted broadly enough to do all of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "permit sexual harassment.",
        "distractor1": "reapportion state legislatures.",
        "distractor2": "prohibit job discrimination.",
        "distractor3": "forbid racial segregation in the public schools.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of ________, the Supreme Court ruled that a black man, slave or free, was   chattel  and had no rights under a white man's government; it also ruled that Congress had no powerto ban slavery in the western territories.",
        "correct_answer": "Dred Scott v. Sandford",
        "distractor1": "Plessy v. Ferguson",
        "distractor2": "Craig v. Boren",
        "distractor3": "Brown v. Board of Education",
        "distractor4": "Amos v. Colorado "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ Amendment outlawed slavery in the United States.",
        "correct_answer": "Thirteenth",
        "distractor1": "Nineteenth",
        "distractor2": "Tenth",
        "distractor3": "First",
        "distractor4": "Equal Rights "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Thirteenth Amendment",
        "correct_answer": "forbade slavery and involuntary servitude.",
        "distractor1": "gave African Americans the right to vote.",
        "distractor2": "repealed the Twelfth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "established the principle of separate but equal.",
        "distractor4": "repealed Prohibition. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Thirteenth Amendment was passed",
        "correct_answer": "at the end of the Civil War. ",
        "distractor1": "in 1920.",
        "distractor2": "in 1850.",
        "distractor3": "in the 1960s.",
        "distractor4": "as one of the original Bill of Rights."
    },
    {
        "question": "The constitutional trail for securing equal rights for all Americans was blazed primarily by",
        "correct_answer": "African Americans. ",
        "distractor1": "women.",
        "distractor2": "Hispanic Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor4": "the American Indians."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Dred Scott v. Sandford (1857), Chief Justice Taney declared that",
        "correct_answer": "Congress had no authority to ban slavery in the territories.",
        "distractor1": "the importation of slaves into the United States was illegal, but slavery itself was not.",
        "distractor2": "a slave who had escaped to a free state became a free man.",
        "distractor3": "slavery is inherently unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "slavery can be practiced in the so-called free states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Slavery was declared unconstitutional by the",
        "correct_answer": "Thirteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Fourteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "Jim Crow laws.",
        "distractor3": "Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor4": "Dred Scott v. Sandford Supreme Court case. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Jim Crow laws were those which",
        "correct_answer": "were enacted by Southern whites in the late nineteenth century to segregate African Americans from whites.",
        "distractor1": "the North enforced in the South in the Reconstruction era following the Civil War, granting rights to former slaves.",
        "distractor2": "sought to end segregation and bring the races into closer contact with one another.",
        "distractor3": "justified slavery and set codes for slaves ยน behavior.",
        "distractor4": "established slavery and contract law regulating the slave trade. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court's decision in the case of Plessy v. Ferguson",
        "correct_answer": "stated that the principle of separate but equal public facilities for African Americans was constitutional.",
        "distractor1": "for the first time established race as a suspect classification and ruled that former slaves must be granted land or otherwise compensated for their years of forced labor.",
        "distractor2": "outlawed slavery.",
        "distractor3": "stated that the principle of separate but equal public facilities for African Americans was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "ruled that slaves were chattel property and entitled to no rights under the Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of ________, the Supreme Court ruled that segregation of races by law wasconstitutional so long as the facilities that were separate were also equal.",
        "correct_answer": "Plessy v. Ferguson",
        "distractor1": "Amos v. Alabama",
        "distractor2": "Brown v. Board of Education",
        "distractor3": "Craig v. Boren",
        "distractor4": "Dred Scott v. Sandford "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the first half of the twentieth century, the Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "paid more attention to the   separate   than to the   equal   part of the separate but equal doctrine.",
        "distractor1": "allowed segregation in the armed forces.",
        "distractor2": "upheld the legality of all-white primaries.",
        "distractor3": "declared all Jim Crow laws unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Legal segregation of the races was declared unconstitutional in the 1954 landmark rulingknown as",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "King v. University of Kansas.",
        "distractor2": "Plessy v. Ferguson.",
        "distractor3": "Dred Scott v. Sandford.",
        "distractor4": "Craig v. Boren."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Brown v. Board of Education decision overturned the Supreme Court's 1896 ruling in",
        "correct_answer": "Plessy v. Ferguson. ",
        "distractor1": "Craig v. Boren.",
        "distractor2": "Dred Scott v. Sandford.",
        "distractor3": "Marbury v. Madison.",
        "distractor4": "Amos v. Alabama."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Brown v. Board of Education (1954), the Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "ruled that school segregation was inherently unequal. ",
        "distractor1": "ordered the Topeka school district to spend more money on black schools.",
        "distractor2": "enunciated the principle of equal but separate.",
        "distractor3": "ruled that the visible signs of education were substantially equal between black schools and white ones.",
        "distractor4": "enunciated the principle of separate but equal."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court's ruling in Brown v. Board of Education was based on the legal argumentthat segregation violated the ________ Amendment.",
        "correct_answer": "Fourteenth",
        "distractor1": "First",
        "distractor2": "Twenty-sixth",
        "distractor3": "Nineteenth",
        "distractor4": "Equal Rights "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of ________, the Supreme Court upheld federal court rulings ordering busing ofstudents to achieve racially balanced schools.",
        "correct_answer": "Swann v. Charlotte-Mecklenberg County Schools ",
        "distractor1": "Craig v. Boren",
        "distractor2": "Plessy v. Ferguson",
        "distractor3": "Brown v. Board of Education",
        "distractor4": "Unified Transportation Co. v Madison County"
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following were tactics of the Civil Rights Movement EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "marches.",
        "distractor2": "civil disobedience.",
        "distractor3": "sit-ins.",
        "distractor4": "bus boycotts."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of ________, the most important law since the EmancipationProclamation, made racial discrimination illegal in public accommodations throughoutAmerica.",
        "correct_answer": "1964",
        "distractor1": "1947",
        "distractor2": "1984",
        "distractor3": "1974",
        "distractor4": "1954 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ Amendment, adopted in 1870, guaranteed the right of African Americans to voteรฎโฌโat least in principle.",
        "correct_answer": "Fifteenth",
        "distractor1": "Nineteenth",
        "distractor2": "Thirteenth",
        "distractor3": "First",
        "distractor4": "Fifth "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of 1964",
        "correct_answer": "both A and B",
        "distractor1": "made racial discrimination illegal in places of public accommodation.",
        "distractor2": "forbade discrimination in employment on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, or gender.",
        "distractor3": "prohibited gender discrimination in the work place.",
        "distractor4": "neither A nor B "
    },
    {
        "question": "Suffrage refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the legal right to vote.",
        "distractor1": "the practice of de facto slavery rather than de jure slavery.",
        "distractor2": "the legal segregation of the races or of men and women in hotels, motels, restaurants, and other public places.",
        "distractor3": "the hardships endured to obtain civil rights for African Americans and equal rights for women.",
        "distractor4": "the practice of shackling slaves working in fields so they could not run away. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The legal right to vote is referred to as",
        "correct_answer": "suffrage.",
        "distractor1": "civil liberties.",
        "distractor2": "the grandfather clause.",
        "distractor3": "civil rights.",
        "distractor4": "coverture. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Civil Rights Act of 1964",
        "correct_answer": "guaranteed equal access to hotels, restaurants, and other public accommodations. ",
        "distractor1": "established the first affirmative action programs.",
        "distractor2": "ended discrimination in the purchase or rental of housing.",
        "distractor3": "ended the white primary.",
        "distractor4": "guaranteed minority groups the right to vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "Blacks were first given the legal right to vote by the",
        "correct_answer": "Fifteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Civil Rights Act of 1964.",
        "distractor2": "Twenty-fourth Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "Voting Rights Act of 1965.",
        "distractor4": "Emancipation Proclamation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To render African-American votes ineffective, several southern states used the ________, adevice that permitted political parties to choose their nominees in elections off limits to blacks.",
        "correct_answer": "white primary ",
        "distractor1": "suffrage",
        "distractor2": "grandfather clause",
        "distractor3": "poll tax",
        "distractor4": "hidden ballot"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Twenty-fourth Amendment, ratified in 1964,",
        "correct_answer": "prohibited the use of poll taxes in federal elections. ",
        "distractor1": "prohibited discrimination in employment or public accommodations based on race.",
        "distractor2": "granted Negroes the right to vote.",
        "distractor3": "outlawed the use of literacy tests in order to register to vote.",
        "distractor4": "outlawed the grandfather clause and the white primary."
    },
    {
        "question": "Poll taxes for federal elections were outlawed in the",
        "correct_answer": "Twenty-fourth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Voting Rights Act.",
        "distractor2": "Civil Rights Act of 1964.",
        "distractor3": "Supreme Court's Guinn v. United States decision of 1915.",
        "distractor4": "Tax Reform Act of 1963. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One consequence of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 was",
        "correct_answer": "dramatic increase in the number of African Americans registered to vote.",
        "distractor1": "increased access of blacks to public accommodations.",
        "distractor2": "the increased use of gerrymandering.",
        "distractor3": "decreased involvement of federal officials in state election procedures.",
        "distractor4": "an increase in segregation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The white primary",
        "correct_answer": "excluded blacks from primary elections, thus depriving them of a voice in the real electoral contests in the South.",
        "distractor1": "was the examination voters had to pass before being allowed to vote, designed to prevent blacks from voting because they had been denied educational opportunities.",
        "distractor2": "denied blacks the right to run for office in primary elections in the South.",
        "distractor3": "denied blacks the right to vote in all southern elections.",
        "distractor4": "allowed blacks to vote only in Republican primaries in the heavily Democratic South. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Native-American Indians were made citizens of the United States in",
        "correct_answer": "1924.",
        "distractor1": "1964.",
        "distractor2": "1789.",
        "distractor3": "1868.",
        "distractor4": "They were never made citizens of the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Native Americans is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Native Americans were made citizens of the United States long before African Americans received the same status.",
        "distractor1": "Native Americans are the oldest minority group in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "Native Americans are guaranteed access to the polls, housing, and to jobs.",
        "distractor3": "The Indian Claims Act of 1946 established a means to settle financial disputes arising from lands taken from the Indians.",
        "distractor4": "Native Americans are the poorest minority group in the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Hispanic Americans comprise approximately ________ percent of the United Statespopulation.",
        "correct_answer": "14",
        "distractor1": "5",
        "distractor2": "22",
        "distractor3": "10",
        "distractor4": "20 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fastest growing minority group in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "Asian Americans. ",
        "distractor1": "Native Americans.",
        "distractor2": "African Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Japanese Americans.",
        "distractor4": "Hispanic Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "The women's rights movement was launched with the signing of the",
        "correct_answer": "Seneca Falls Declaration.",
        "distractor1": "Feminist Manifesto.",
        "distractor2": "Emancipation Proclamation.",
        "distractor3": "Equal Rights Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Declaration of Independence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ gave women the constitutional right to vote.",
        "correct_answer": "Nineteenth Amendment ",
        "distractor1": "Bill of Rights",
        "distractor2": "Fifteenth Amendment",
        "distractor3": "Twenty-fourth Amendment",
        "distractor4": "Equal Rights Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "From about 1920-1960, the feminist movement",
        "correct_answer": "was in a period of hibernation.",
        "distractor1": "experienced great growth and activity.",
        "distractor2": "was preoccupied with winning the right to vote.",
        "distractor3": "concentrated on anti-war causes.",
        "distractor4": "first coalesced as a significant political movement in the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Alice Paul authored the Equal Rights Amendment, and unsuccessfully pushed for its passagebeginning in the",
        "correct_answer": "1920s.",
        "distractor1": "1960s.",
        "distractor2": "1970s.",
        "distractor3": "1980s.",
        "distractor4": "1940s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Women were first given the right to vote by the",
        "correct_answer": "Nineteenth Amendment. ",
        "distractor1": "Suffrage Act of 1880.",
        "distractor2": "Equal Rights Amendment.",
        "distractor3": "Fifteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Voting Rights Act."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the immediate consequence of women receiving theright to vote is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The feminist movement gained steam immediately after the right to vote was secured.",
        "distractor1": "Many supporters of the right to vote accepted the traditional model of the family.",
        "distractor2": "Winning the right to vote did not automatically give women equal rights, pay, and status.",
        "distractor3": "Many state laws continued to enshrine the traditional view of the family in public policy.",
        "distractor4": "Gaining the right to vote did not eliminate many of the challenges facing women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "After passage of the Nineteenth Amendment in 1920, public policy toward women wasdominated by",
        "correct_answer": "protectionism.",
        "distractor1": "the principle of equality.",
        "distractor2": "coverture.",
        "distractor3": "matriarchalism.",
        "distractor4": "economic, but not political, advances. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The feminist movement was reborn",
        "correct_answer": "during the Civil Rights movement of the 1950s and 1960s.",
        "distractor1": "when women became involved in the war effort during World War II.",
        "distractor2": "when the Supreme Court made its decision in Roe v. Wade.",
        "distractor3": "after the Civil War when women became inspired by the emancipation of the slaves.",
        "distractor4": "when the Equal Rights Amendment was first introduced in the 1920s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Betty Friedan's book, ________, published in 1963, encouraged many women to questiontraditional assumptions and to assert their rights.",
        "correct_answer": "The Feminine Mystique ",
        "distractor1": "A Handmaid's Tale",
        "distractor2": "The Second Sex",
        "distractor3": "The Female Eunuch",
        "distractor4": "Women and Economics"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ________, the Supreme Court ruled that any   arbitrary   sex -based classification violated theequal protection clause.",
        "correct_answer": "Reed v. Reed",
        "distractor1": "Regents of the University of California v. Bakke",
        "distractor2": "Dred Scott v. Sandford",
        "distractor3": "Swann v. Charlotte-Mecklenberg County Schools",
        "distractor4": "Roe v. Wade "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of Craig v. Boren, the Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "it would employ a   medium scrutiny   standard: sex discrimination would be treated as neither valid nor invalid.",
        "distractor1": "sex classifications would be treated by the Court as inherently suspect.",
        "distractor2": "racial classifications were constitutional if they have a compelling, legitimate, and rational purpose.",
        "distractor3": "sex classifications would be treated by the Court as valid.",
        "distractor4": "all sex classifications were unconstitutional. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "Many sex discrimination cases have involved men seeking equality with women.",
        "distractor1": "The Supreme Court first struck down a law on the basis of sex discrimination in 1920.",
        "distractor2": "The Supreme Court has so far struck down only a handful of laws for discriminating on the basis of gender.",
        "distractor3": "All of these are true.",
        "distractor4": "None of these are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Equal Rights Amendment failed because",
        "correct_answer": "it fell three states short of sufficient ratification. ",
        "distractor1": "it was vetoed by the President.",
        "distractor2": "the Supreme Court voided it as unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "it did not win the required two-thirds vote in each chamber of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "it was rejected by the United States Senate."
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ banned gender discrimination in employment by law.",
        "correct_answer": "Civil Rights Act of 1964",
        "distractor1": "Fair Labor Standards Act",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court ruling in National Organization for Women v. Bank of America",
        "distractor3": "Nineteenth Amendment",
        "distractor4": "Gender Equity Act of 1972 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Supreme Court has handed down each of the following decisionsconcerning gender discrimination in employment and business activity EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "requiring the federal government to give women equal pay for jobs of comparable worth.",
        "distractor1": "prohibiting gender discrimination in private business and service clubs.",
        "distractor2": "voiding laws and rules barring women from jobs through arbitrary height and weight requirements.",
        "distractor3": "protecting women from being required to take mandatory pregnancy leaves from their jobs.",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; the court has handed down each of the decisions above. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The issue of ________ deals with women seeking to redress the fact that jobs traditionally heldby men tend to pay far greater salaries than jobs requiring similar skills but are traditionallyheld by women.",
        "correct_answer": "comparable worth",
        "distractor1": "gender equality",
        "distractor2": "affirmative action",
        "distractor3": "feminized wage scales",
        "distractor4": "the lace purse "
    },
    {
        "question": "  Comparable worth   refers to the issue of",
        "correct_answer": "paying men and women equivalent salaries for jobs requiring similar skills.",
        "distractor1": "government subsidization of women who choose to work at home.",
        "distractor2": "the inherent dignity and equality of women with men.",
        "distractor3": "reduced work responsibilities for women workers with children.",
        "distractor4": "equal voting rights and access to public office for women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Women are prohibited from serving as combat pilots.",
        "distractor2": "Women are prohibited on navy warships.",
        "distractor3": "Women are now allowed in ground combat units.",
        "distractor4": "Both men and women must register for the draft at age 18."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about women in the military is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Women, as well as men, are now required to register for the draft.",
        "distractor1": "Congress has opened all the service academies to women.",
        "distractor2": "Statutes and regulations prohibit women from serving in most combat situations.",
        "distractor3": "Women have served in every branch of the armed services since World War II.",
        "distractor4": "Women do not have a ceiling on the rank they can achieve. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Persian Gulf War showed that",
        "correct_answer": "women could serve as combat pilots.",
        "distractor1": "women would not volunteer for combat positions.",
        "distractor2": "there is no place in the military for women.",
        "distractor3": "women did well in the military, but should not serve in combat positions.",
        "distractor4": "women's military performance was inferior to men's. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1993, the Supreme Court ruled that sexual harassment is sex discrimination that violates theCivil Rights Act when",
        "correct_answer": "the workplace environment becomes hostile or abusive.",
        "distractor1": "the target objects a second time to touching, body language, or dirty talk.",
        "distractor2": "it causes severe psychological injury.",
        "distractor3": "an employee can no longer perform his or her job.",
        "distractor4": "the target suffers a nervous breakdown. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Faragher v. City of Boca Raton (1998), the Supreme Court held that",
        "correct_answer": "employers are responsible for preventing and eliminating sexual harassment.",
        "distractor1": "school districts can be held liable for sexual harassment.",
        "distractor2": "the military can not be responsible for sexual harassment at conferences.",
        "distractor3": "government entities are not responsible for preventing sexual harassment.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   gray liberation   movement refers to",
        "correct_answer": "those fighting for the rights of the elderly.",
        "distractor1": "elderly homosexuals seeking equality.",
        "distractor2": "those seeking laws that break down racial barriers and promote harmony.",
        "distractor3": "anti-pollution activists who seek to reduce smog.",
        "distractor4": "those fighting for equal rights and justice for the disabled. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fastest growing age group in the American population is",
        "correct_answer": "people in their 80s.",
        "distractor1": "Generation X.",
        "distractor2": "infants.",
        "distractor3": "teenagers.",
        "distractor4": "baby-boomers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Age discrimination laws have",
        "correct_answer": "denied federal funds to any institution discriminating against people over forty.",
        "distractor1": "allowed children between the ages of 12 and 18 to leave their parents.",
        "distractor2": "lowered the minimum compulsory retirement age to 55.",
        "distractor3": "required employers to hire a certain percentage of people over the age of 50.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1990, Congress enacted the ________, a far-reaching law to protect a particular group ofAmericans from discrimination, ignoring those who claimed the price tag would be too high.",
        "correct_answer": "Americans with Disabilities Act",
        "distractor1": "Gay and Lesbian Civil Rights Bill",
        "distractor2": "Native-Americans Inclusion Act",
        "distractor3": "Children's Rights Act",
        "distractor4": "Immigrant Grant Act "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Rehabilitation Act of 1973",
        "correct_answer": "added handicapped people to the list of Americans protected from discrimination.",
        "distractor1": "entitles all children to a free public education appropriate to their needs.",
        "distractor2": "increased the amount of financial aid to disabled people.",
        "distractor3": "guaranteed free, lifetime medical care and physical therapy for Vietnam War veterans.",
        "distractor4": "prohibits employment discrimination against the disabled. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990",
        "correct_answer": "prohibited employment discrimination against the disabled.",
        "distractor1": "required all governmental buildings to have wheelchair-accessible entrances and facilities.",
        "distractor2": "added AIDS victims to the list of handicapped persons.",
        "distractor3": "added handicapped people to the list of Americans protected from discrimination.",
        "distractor4": "required an affirmative action program for the disabled. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Opposition to Civil Rights laws for the handicapped has been justified primarily on the basisof the",
        "correct_answer": "high cost of programs to help the disabled.",
        "distractor1": "inability of disabled persons to handle most employment requirements.",
        "distractor2": "fear that laws will lead to a quota system to hire disabled persons.",
        "distractor3": "fear that the disabled will take jobs away from able-bodied persons.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Homophobia refers to",
        "correct_answer": "fear and hatred toward gay men and lesbian women.",
        "distractor1": "the tendency to be sexually attracted to members of one's own sex.",
        "distractor2": "the development of positive stereotypes concerning gay men and lesbian women.",
        "distractor3": "promoting the Civil Rights of gay men and lesbian women.",
        "distractor4": "an attitude of tolerance and acceptance toward gay men and lesbian women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Affirmative action seeks to move beyond",
        "correct_answer": "equal opportunity to equal results.",
        "distractor1": "equal results to equal opportunity.",
        "distractor2": "equal opportunity to equal rights.",
        "distractor3": "equal rights to equal opportunity.",
        "distractor4": "negativism to positivism in human relations. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The public policy paths for women and minorities converged in the debate about",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action.",
        "distractor1": "the Equal Rights Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "military service.",
        "distractor3": "gay rights.",
        "distractor4": "comparable worth. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The goal of affirmative action is to move toward",
        "correct_answer": "equal results.",
        "distractor1": "equal facilities.",
        "distractor2": "equal opportunity.",
        "distractor3": "equal pay.",
        "distractor4": "comparable worth. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The strongest and most controversial form of affirmative action is",
        "correct_answer": "numerical quotas.",
        "distractor1": "busing.",
        "distractor2": "comparable worth.",
        "distractor3": "comparative worth.",
        "distractor4": "equal opportunity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court ruled against some of the basic principles of affirmative action in which ofthe following cases?",
        "correct_answer": "Regents of the University of California v. Bakke",
        "distractor1": "Metro Broadcasting Inc. v. Federal Communications Commission",
        "distractor2": "Fullilove v. Klutznick",
        "distractor3": "United Steelworkers of America, AFL-CIO v. Weber",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about affirmative action is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Polling data shows that most Americans support affirmative action.",
        "distractor1": "The constitutional status of affirmative action has not been very clear.",
        "distractor2": "Affirmative action puts an emphasis on equal results and not merely equal opportunities.",
        "distractor3": "Affirmative action has been used to establish special provisions to ensure that a portion of school admissions go to minorities and women.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The case of Regents of the University of California v. Bakke dealt with",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action.",
        "distractor1": "sexual harassment.",
        "distractor2": "the right to establish a gay student organization.",
        "distractor3": "comparable worth.",
        "distractor4": "paid maternity leave. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Supreme Court rulings concerning affirmative actionis FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The Court has ruled that affirmative action can exempt recently hired minorities from traditional work rules specifying   last hired, first fired   order of layoffs.",
        "distractor1": "The Court has approved preferential treatment of minorities in promotions.",
        "distractor2": "The Court has ordered quotas for minority union memberships.",
        "distractor3": "The Court has ruled that public employers may use affirmative action promotion plans to counter the underrepresentation of women and minorities in the workplace.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Affirmative action programs are referred to by critics as",
        "correct_answer": "reverse discrimination.",
        "distractor1": "negative reaction.",
        "distractor2": "positive negativism.",
        "distractor3": "comparable worth.",
        "distractor4": "degenderizing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Supporters of affirmative action believe that",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action produces so important a social goal that some reverse discrimination is acceptable.",
        "distractor1": "merit is the only fair basis for distributing benefits.",
        "distractor2": "discrimination is wrong, even when its purpose is to rectify past injustices.",
        "distractor3": "any form of quota system is unjust.",
        "distractor4": "some discrimination is acceptable. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When proposition 209 was passed in California in 1996, it banned",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action in public hiring, contracting, and educational admissions.",
        "distractor1": "affirmative action in federal hiring.",
        "distractor2": "affirmative action on behalf of homosexuals.",
        "distractor3": "affirmative action in the private sector.",
        "distractor4": "affirmative action on behalf of women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Current civil rights policies conform to the eighteenth-century idea of limited government.",
        "distractor1": "Civil rights policies have expanded the power of government.",
        "distractor2": "The steady expansion of civil rights has brought more groups into the democratic process.",
        "distractor3": "The rights ensured by the First Amendment are essential to a democracy.",
        "distractor4": "Lyndon Johnson was president when civil rights legislation was passed in the 1960s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most valuable method for understanding demographic changes in America is the",
        "correct_answer": "census.",
        "distractor1": "Statistical Abstract of the United States.",
        "distractor2": "public opinion poll.",
        "distractor3": "turnout in presidential elections.",
        "distractor4": "Internal Revenue Service statistical tax abstracts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is the distribution of the population's beliefs about politics and policy issues.",
        "correct_answer": "Public opinion",
        "distractor1": "Random sampling",
        "distractor2": "Direct mail",
        "distractor3": "Political socialization",
        "distractor4": "Political ideology "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the American people is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Most Americans view cultural diversity as one of the least appealing aspects of their society.",
        "distractor1": "There are about 295 million Americans.",
        "distractor2": "America is one of the most culturally diverse countries in the world.",
        "distractor3": "America was founded on the principle of tolerating diversity.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The science of population changes is called",
        "correct_answer": "demography.",
        "distractor1": "public opinion.",
        "distractor2": "political science.",
        "distractor3": "census.",
        "distractor4": "popuology. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion is defined in the text as",
        "correct_answer": "the distribution of the population's beliefs about politics and policy.",
        "distractor1": "opinions which are expressible in public, as opposed to the more truthful private opinions which most individuals are reluctant to state publicly.",
        "distractor2": "beliefs about government held by a majority of people.",
        "distractor3": "opinions solicited from a random sample of the public.",
        "distractor4": "widely held beliefs about the public's role in politics and policy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By constitutional requirement, the government conducts the United States Census every",
        "correct_answer": "ten years. ",
        "distractor1": "two years.",
        "distractor2": "year.",
        "distractor3": "five years.",
        "distractor4": "presidential election year."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Constitution requires that the government conduct an   actual enumeration  of the population every",
        "correct_answer": "ten years.",
        "distractor1": "25 years.",
        "distractor2": "year.",
        "distractor3": "five years.",
        "distractor4": "presidential election year. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first census in the United States was conducted in",
        "correct_answer": "1790.",
        "distractor1": "1900.",
        "distractor2": "1970.",
        "distractor3": "1850.",
        "distractor4": "1800. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An issue that became controversial regarding the 1990 census was",
        "correct_answer": "the undercount of minority groups.",
        "distractor1": "inclusion of immigrants.",
        "distractor2": "cost of the census.",
        "distractor3": "the overcount of urbanites.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The 2000 census indicated that the largest minority population is comprised of",
        "correct_answer": "Hispanics.",
        "distractor1": "illegals.",
        "distractor2": "African Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor4": "Native Americans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately what percent of African Americans live below the poverty line?",
        "correct_answer": "25",
        "distractor1": "28",
        "distractor2": "42",
        "distractor3": "6",
        "distractor4": "17 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest racial/ethnic minority group in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "Hispanics.",
        "distractor1": "African Americans.",
        "distractor2": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Native Americans.",
        "distractor4": "African Americans and Hispanics are tied in size. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately what percent of Asian Americans hold a college degree?",
        "correct_answer": "49",
        "distractor1": "32",
        "distractor2": "12",
        "distractor3": "22",
        "distractor4": "60 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The least healthy, poorest, and least educated racial/ethnic group in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "Native Americans.",
        "distractor1": "African Americans.",
        "distractor2": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor3": "Hispanics.",
        "distractor4": "Caucasians. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most recent wave of immigration since World War II has consisted primarily of",
        "correct_answer": "Hispanics and Asians.",
        "distractor1": "Africans.",
        "distractor2": "northwestern Europeans.",
        "distractor3": "southern and eastern Europeans.",
        "distractor4": "refugees from communist countries. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Demographic changes in the United States population could translate to political consequencesthrough the process of",
        "correct_answer": "reapportionment.",
        "distractor1": "political socialization.",
        "distractor2": "political acculturation.",
        "distractor3": "political assimilation",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The term   minority majority   refers to the fact that",
        "correct_answer": "America will soon cease to have a white majority and together the minority groups will become a majority.",
        "distractor1": "the majority in America has always been a collection of minority ethnic groups.",
        "distractor2": "minority groups have been able to impose their will upon the majority.",
        "distractor3": "African Americans are the largest minority group in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "Hispanic Americans will soon become the largest minority group in the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "African Americans comprise what proportion of the American population?",
        "correct_answer": "about 12 percent",
        "distractor1": "about 30 percent",
        "distractor2": "about 25 percent",
        "distractor3": "about 20 percent",
        "distractor4": "about 5 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Hispanics comprise approximately what percent of the American population?",
        "correct_answer": "13 percent",
        "distractor1": "5 percent",
        "distractor2": "23 percent",
        "distractor3": "18 percent",
        "distractor4": "28 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest component of the minority majority is the",
        "correct_answer": "Hispanic population.",
        "distractor1": "Asian population.",
        "distractor2": "Caucasian population.",
        "distractor3": "Native-American population.",
        "distractor4": "African-American population. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Hispanics are primarily concentrated in the rural areas.",
        "distractor1": "In the 2000 Census, the Hispanic population outnumbered the African -American population.",
        "distractor2": "African Americans have recently been exercising a good deal of political power.",
        "distractor3": "about 24 percent of African Americans currently live under the poverty line.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Unlike Hispanics who have come to America to escape poverty, the recent influx of Asians hasbeen driven by",
        "correct_answer": "a new class of professionals looking for greater opportunity.",
        "distractor1": "upper-class elites who feared political persecution.",
        "distractor2": "civil wars.",
        "distractor3": "ethnic minorities seeking refuge from human rights violations.",
        "distractor4": "B and C only "
    },
    {
        "question": "Native Americans tend to be",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above",
        "distractor1": "the poorest group in America.",
        "distractor2": "the least educated group in America.",
        "distractor3": "the least healthy group in America.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Simpson-Mazzoli Act",
        "correct_answer": "represented a crackdown on illegal aliens by requiring that employers document the citizenship or legitimate immigrant status of workers or pay stiff fines.",
        "distractor1": "requires that states keep their polls open for at least ten hours on election day in order to facilitate participation.",
        "distractor2": "established federal guidelines and regulations for taking public opinion polls.",
        "distractor3": "reformed the jury procedures in felony cases, particularly the unanimous verdict requirement.",
        "distractor4": "required that the homeless be counted in the 1990 census. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ Act required that as of 1987, employers document the citizenship or legalimmigrant status of their employees, or face substantial criminal penalties for failing to do so.",
        "correct_answer": "Simpson-Mazzoli",
        "distractor1": "National Origins",
        "distractor2": "National Labor Relations",
        "distractor3": "Hatch",
        "distractor4": "Immigrant Employment "
    },
    {
        "question": "The least-healthy, the poorest, and the least-educated group in the American mosaic are the",
        "correct_answer": "Native-American Indians.",
        "distractor1": "Hispanic Americans.",
        "distractor2": "Appalachian Caucasians.",
        "distractor3": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor4": "African Americans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Simpson-Mazzoli Act",
        "correct_answer": "required employers to document the citizenship of their employees.",
        "distractor1": "granted amnesty to all illegal aliens.",
        "distractor2": "established a National Identification Card that all Americans will have to possess by the year 2000 in order to get employment.",
        "distractor3": "placed a limit on the number of Mexican immigrants allowed in the United States per year.",
        "distractor4": "required all immigrants to register with the Immigration and Naturalization Service. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The worst off of America's minority groups are",
        "correct_answer": "Native Americans.",
        "distractor1": "homosexuals.",
        "distractor2": "Asian Americans.",
        "distractor3": "African Americans.",
        "distractor4": "Hispanic Americans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political culture refers to",
        "correct_answer": "an overall set of values widely shared within a society.",
        "distractor1": "a set of beliefs about the role of government in society.",
        "distractor2": "how truly   American   someone is.",
        "distractor3": "a high degree of homogeneity in political opinions.",
        "distractor4": "political party affiliation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the last fifty years much of America's population growth has occurred",
        "correct_answer": "in the West and South.",
        "distractor1": "on the East Coast.",
        "distractor2": "east of the Mississippi River.",
        "distractor3": "north of the Mason-Dixon line.",
        "distractor4": "in the Midwest. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Between 1990 and 2000,",
        "correct_answer": "the Sunbelt continued to experience rapid population growth.",
        "distractor1": "states in the Southwest were losing population.",
        "distractor2": "the Midwest became the fastest-growing region in the country.",
        "distractor3": "the Frostbelt had begun to gain population again.",
        "distractor4": "the Pacific Coast states were the fastest-growing region of the country. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ occurs after every census to reallocate the 435 seats in the United States House ofRepresentatives, reflecting shifts in the population of the states and, thus, how many seatseach state is allotted.",
        "correct_answer": "Reapportionment",
        "distractor1": "Equalization",
        "distractor2": "Restructuring",
        "distractor3": "Political socialization",
        "distractor4": "Demography "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reapportionment occurs after every census to reallocate seats in",
        "correct_answer": "the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "the president's cabinet.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "both the House of Representatives and the Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nationwide, the fastest growing age group is composed of",
        "correct_answer": "those over 65 years old.",
        "distractor1": "those under 13 years old.",
        "distractor2": "one-year-olds.",
        "distractor3": "those between 13-21 years old.",
        "distractor4": "those between 21-30 years old. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following states has increased its representation in the House from just seven in1900 to 53 today?",
        "correct_answer": "California",
        "distractor1": "Florida",
        "distractor2": "Texas",
        "distractor3": "New York",
        "distractor4": "Georgia "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reapportionment",
        "correct_answer": "can dramatically shift political power between the regions.",
        "distractor1": "affects how much federal aid population groups can receive.",
        "distractor2": "changes the states ยน number of representatives in the United States Senate.",
        "distractor3": "has most recently increased congressional representation for New England.",
        "distractor4": "rarely occurs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The process through which an individual acquires his or her particular political orientations,including his or her knowledge, feelings, and evaluations regarding his or her political world,is known as",
        "correct_answer": "political socialization.",
        "distractor1": "political orientation.",
        "distractor2": "demography.",
        "distractor3": "political ideology.",
        "distractor4": "political indoctrination. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One can predict how the majority of young people will vote simply by",
        "correct_answer": "knowing the political leaning of their parents.",
        "distractor1": "knowing the political leaning of their friends.",
        "distractor2": "knowing their race.",
        "distractor3": "knowing the political leaning of their teachers.",
        "distractor4": "knowing their age. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Both authoritarian and democratic political systems seek to teach citizens, especially youth, thepositive aspects of their political systems because",
        "correct_answer": "youth will then grow up to be supportive citizens.",
        "distractor1": "youth are most gullible.",
        "distractor2": "it enhances ruling elite's political power over the citizenry.",
        "distractor3": "both types of political systems rely directly on citizen support.",
        "distractor4": "youth think alike. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to many observers,   the new parent   in the socialization process has become",
        "correct_answer": "the mass media.",
        "distractor1": "schools.",
        "distractor2": "interest groups.",
        "distractor3": "the mother.",
        "distractor4": "friends and peers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most obvious intrusion of the government into America's socialization is through",
        "correct_answer": "schooling.",
        "distractor1": "political parties.",
        "distractor2": "the family.",
        "distractor3": "the mass media.",
        "distractor4": "criminal laws. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Governments throughout the world use the schools to help with the ________ of youngpeople.",
        "correct_answer": "political socialization",
        "distractor1": "random sampling",
        "distractor2": "voter registration",
        "distractor3": "civil disobedience",
        "distractor4": "demography "
    },
    {
        "question": "As one becomes more socialized with age, one's political orientations",
        "correct_answer": "grow firmer.",
        "distractor1": "become less important.",
        "distractor2": "change as one's position in the aging order changes their life conditions.",
        "distractor3": "lack commitment.",
        "distractor4": "fluctuate more. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the effects of growing older on political learning and political behavior is that",
        "correct_answer": "political participation increases with age.",
        "distractor1": "people become more liberal with age.",
        "distractor2": "interest in politics decreases with age.",
        "distractor3": "the strength of one's party attachment declines with age.",
        "distractor4": "political ignorance increases with age. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion polling was first begun in 1932 by",
        "correct_answer": "George Gallup.",
        "distractor1": "the Democratic party.",
        "distractor2": "Louis Harris.",
        "distractor3": "the Associated Press.",
        "distractor4": "Henry Luce. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The key to the accuracy of public opinion polls is",
        "correct_answer": "random sampling. ",
        "distractor1": "political ideology.",
        "distractor2": "polygraphs.",
        "distractor3": "sampling error.",
        "distractor4": "the larger the size of the sample, the better."
    },
    {
        "question": "Sampling error describes",
        "correct_answer": "how close a sample estimate is to the real population value.",
        "distractor1": "how many samples a survey estimate is based on.",
        "distractor2": "what percentage of the sample provided answers to the questions.",
        "distractor3": "how often a sample statistic is correct.",
        "distractor4": "how many samples are incorrect. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Random sampling in public opinion polling operates on the principle that",
        "correct_answer": "everyone should have an equal probability of being selected.",
        "distractor1": "which answers to include in aggregate poll results must be selected by chance in order to maximize accuracy.",
        "distractor2": "the questions to be asked of a given respondent must be selected randomly so that all respondents are asked the same question the same number of times.",
        "distractor3": "the larger the number of people who are polled, the greater accuracy of the poll.",
        "distractor4": "both B and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "Random sampling is considered",
        "correct_answer": "the key to the accuracy of opinion polls.",
        "distractor1": "desirable, but not necessary, for an accurate poll of public opinion.",
        "distractor2": "an unsophisticated way of measuring public opinion, but one that sometimes yields accurate results.",
        "distractor3": "highly unreliable, but the cheapest way to measure public opinion.",
        "distractor4": "a dangerous way to measure public opinion. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The level of confidence about a public opinion poll is referred to as",
        "correct_answer": "sampling error.",
        "distractor1": "the confidence index.",
        "distractor2": "the sample.",
        "distractor3": "random sampling.",
        "distractor4": "demographic certainty. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion polls are only estimates because",
        "correct_answer": "all surveys have a sampling error.",
        "distractor1": "samples of fewer then one million people are too small.",
        "distractor2": "pollsters sometimes have to make educated guesses about the results.",
        "distractor3": "random digit dialing has replaced person-to-person interviewing.",
        "distractor4": "samples are not representative. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A pollster using a representative sample of 1,500 Americans finds that 52 percent supportcandidate X and 48 percent support candidate Y. The pollster's conclusion should be that",
        "correct_answer": "the race is too close to call because of a possible sampling error.",
        "distractor1": "the poll should be retaken using random digit dialing.",
        "distractor2": "the poll should be retaken with a larger sample.",
        "distractor3": "polls are unreliable predictors of political outcomes.",
        "distractor4": "X is likely to win. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A random sample of 1500-2000 respondents will produce results far off the mark about________ of the time.",
        "correct_answer": "5 percent",
        "distractor1": "10 percent",
        "distractor2": "25 percent",
        "distractor3": "35 percent",
        "distractor4": "1 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1936 Literary Digest poll underestimated the vote for President Franklin Roosevelt by 19percent because",
        "correct_answer": "the sample was drawn from telephone books and motor-vehicle records.",
        "distractor1": "the literary intelligentsia as a group never did like Roosevelt.",
        "distractor2": "the sample was too small.",
        "distractor3": "not enough women were interviewed.",
        "distractor4": "people did not tell the truth. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most polling today is done",
        "correct_answer": "by phone. ",
        "distractor1": "by mail.",
        "distractor2": "by computer modem and fax.",
        "distractor3": "at shopping malls.",
        "distractor4": "in person."
    },
    {
        "question": "Samples of public opinion today are usually selected through",
        "correct_answer": "random digit dialing.",
        "distractor1": "voter registration lists.",
        "distractor2": "cities and towns throughout the country believed to be   bellwethers,   which accurately represent the entire nation.",
        "distractor3": "selective respondent profiles.",
        "distractor4": "phone books. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a criticism of modern polling?",
        "correct_answer": "Polls are subject to very wide margins of error, yet are treated as accurate measurements of public opinion.",
        "distractor1": "Careful attention to polls is unwise, as polls only reflect the passive attitudes of voters.",
        "distractor2": "Politicians use polls to follow the crowd rather than to assert bold leadership.",
        "distractor3": "Polls can distort the election process by creating a bandwagon effect, where people want to follow the crowd.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, most polling is done through",
        "correct_answer": "random digit dialing.",
        "distractor1": "entry polls.",
        "distractor2": "door-to-door interviewing.",
        "distractor3": "man-on-the-street interviewing.",
        "distractor4": "exit polls. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerns about reliance of pollsters on telephone surveys have recently been caused by",
        "correct_answer": "increased use of cell phones.",
        "distractor1": "decreased chances of finding people at home.",
        "distractor2": "increased use of random digit dialing.",
        "distractor3": "increased non-listing of phone numbers.",
        "distractor4": "a decrease in no-call lists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion polls can weaken democracy by",
        "correct_answer": "drowning out election issues with a steady flood of poll results.",
        "distractor1": "undermining the bandwagon effect and encouraging voters to support candidates without regard for the opinions of others.",
        "distractor2": "predicting the wrong winner in a close election.",
        "distractor3": "misleading politicians with delayed and outdated information about changing opinions of the public.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of polling think",
        "correct_answer": "it makes politicians more concerned with following than leading.",
        "distractor1": "it gives politicians the wrong information.",
        "distractor2": "the public's opinion should not be taken into account.",
        "distractor3": "it could lead to a tyranny of the majority.",
        "distractor4": "B and D only "
    },
    {
        "question": "A disadvantage of telephone public opinion surveys is",
        "correct_answer": "both B and C ",
        "distractor1": "that they cost more than face-to-face surveys.",
        "distractor2": "that they have a lower response rate than face-to-face interviews.",
        "distractor3": "that some individuals do not own phones.",
        "distractor4": "that they have a lower response rate than mail interviews."
    },
    {
        "question": "An exit poll is taken",
        "correct_answer": "on election day, by interviewing voters as they leave the polling place.",
        "distractor1": "just prior to the election, in order to get a last reading of the public's views.",
        "distractor2": "to measure an officeholder's popularity as he or she is leaving office.",
        "distractor3": "as people leave supermarkets, shopping malls, sporting events, or movies, and are thus available for interviews.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "For ________, voting places are randomly selected around the country, and interviewers askevery tenth person how they voted.",
        "correct_answer": "an exit poll ",
        "distractor1": "absentee balloting",
        "distractor2": "a referendum",
        "distractor3": "preventing voting fraud",
        "distractor4": "reapportionment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about exit polls?",
        "correct_answer": "Most people are contacted by the random digit dialing method.",
        "distractor1": "People are asked how they voted rather than how they plan to vote.",
        "distractor2": "They are used by the media to project election winners before most votes have been counted except in close races.",
        "distractor3": "They have been criticized in presidential elections for declaring a winner before voting is completed in the West.",
        "distractor4": "They are being used more today than they were in the 1970s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Poll results can vary widely if",
        "correct_answer": "a question is altered, even slightly.",
        "distractor1": "based on exit polls.",
        "distractor2": "random sampling is used.",
        "distractor3": "the sample is too large.",
        "distractor4": "political socialization is not considered. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2000, exit polls received much of the blame for the media's inaccurate call of the Floridaresult, but blame could also be placed on",
        "correct_answer": "both A and B",
        "distractor1": "mistakes in early reporting of vote results in some counties.",
        "distractor2": "underestimates of the absentee vote.",
        "distractor3": "the incompetence of news anchorpersons.",
        "distractor4": "both A and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion analysts agree that the level of public knowledge about politics is",
        "correct_answer": "dismally low.",
        "distractor1": "pretty good.",
        "distractor2": "constantly fluctuating.",
        "distractor3": "fair.",
        "distractor4": "surprisingly sharp and sophisticated. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If public opinion analysts agree about anything it is that",
        "correct_answer": "the level of public knowledge about politics is dismally low.",
        "distractor1": "people have something to say about almost every issue.",
        "distractor2": "people's views on politics are coherent and consistent.",
        "distractor3": "people do not have opinions on most current public policy issues.",
        "distractor4": "people think about politics in very meaningful and abstract ways. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public opinion polls have shown that",
        "correct_answer": "people are more likely to recognize slogans from TV commercials than famous political figures.",
        "distractor1": "most people can name their representatives, but do not know how they generally vote in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "most people are well-informed about politics, but know little about geography.",
        "distractor3": "only during an international crisis are people able to locate specific countries involved in the crisis.",
        "distractor4": "political knowledge is higher now than it was forty years ago. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Russell Neuman, the paradox of mass politics is that the American politicalsystem works as well as it does given",
        "correct_answer": "the discomforting lack of public knowledge about politics. ",
        "distractor1": "the fact that elected officials tend to ignore public opinion.",
        "distractor2": "the inaccuracy of public opinion polls giving politicians false information about what people want.",
        "distractor3": "the inability of people to express their opinion on issues and candidates.",
        "distractor4": "that most people do not even know what basic values they want upheld."
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the 1960s, Americans ยน trust in government has",
        "correct_answer": "decreased.",
        "distractor1": "increased.",
        "distractor2": "stayed the same.",
        "distractor3": "been erratic.",
        "distractor4": "disappeared. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ is a coherent set of values and beliefs about public policy.",
        "correct_answer": "political ideology",
        "distractor1": "policy agenda",
        "distractor2": "demography",
        "distractor3": "public opinion",
        "distractor4": "political socialization "
    },
    {
        "question": "Following the 1964 election,",
        "correct_answer": "public trust in government dropped significantly.",
        "distractor1": "public interest in government dropped slightly for a brief period.",
        "distractor2": "public knowledge about political affairs improved significantly.",
        "distractor3": "public interest in campaigns increased.",
        "distractor4": "presidential approval increased significantly. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1980, about what percentage of the American public thought they could trust governmentmost of the time or always?",
        "correct_answer": "25 percent",
        "distractor1": "75 percent",
        "distractor2": "33 percent",
        "distractor3": "50 percent",
        "distractor4": "60 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Marc Hetherington, what is the largest impact of declining political trust?",
        "correct_answer": "decreased support for programs that address poverty and racial inequality",
        "distractor1": "decreased respect of American politicians in the foreign pres",
        "distractor2": "higher taxes",
        "distractor3": "increased political ignorance",
        "distractor4": "the inability of the president to address pressing foreign policy concerns "
    },
    {
        "question": "A political ideology is",
        "correct_answer": "a coherent set of values and beliefs about public policy. ",
        "distractor1": "the process through which an individual acquires his or her political skills.",
        "distractor2": "a relatively small proportion of people who are chosen as representative of the whole.",
        "distractor3": "the distribution of the population's beliefs about politics and policy issues.",
        "distractor4": "the set of courses that a political science student must complete to attain a degree."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about most liberals in American politics?",
        "correct_answer": "They believe we should guard carefully the rights of defendants in criminal cases.",
        "distractor1": "They favor keeping taxes and government spending low.",
        "distractor2": "They are supportive of prayer in public schools.",
        "distractor3": "They oppose abortion.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE of most conservatives in American politics?",
        "correct_answer": "They favor free market solutions to problems rather than looking to the government for regulating business.",
        "distractor1": "They believe we should spend much less on the military budget.",
        "distractor2": "They are in favor of affirmative action programs.",
        "distractor3": "They are opposed to prayer in public schools.",
        "distractor4": "They oppose high levels of foreign aid. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A political figure who is in favor of increased military spending, supported freedom of choiceon abortion, opposed affirmative action programs, wanted to tax the rich more, and felt thecourts should stop coddling criminals is a",
        "correct_answer": "mixture of liberal and conservative.",
        "distractor1": "socialist.",
        "distractor2": "liberal.",
        "distractor3": "conservative.",
        "distractor4": "populist. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, liberal ideology supports",
        "correct_answer": "a strong central government that sets policies to promote equality.",
        "distractor1": "individuals responding generously to each other to solve society's problems without looking to government to do so.",
        "distractor2": "a small, less active government that gives freer reign to the private sector.",
        "distractor3": "public and government ownership of the means of production.",
        "distractor4": "strong local and state governments that are closer to the people. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Liberals tend to",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "support lower taxation.",
        "distractor2": "favor maintaining peace through strength.",
        "distractor3": "support lower government spending.",
        "distractor4": "support school prayer."
    },
    {
        "question": "Conservatives would tend to favor each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "affirmative action.",
        "distractor1": "low taxes.",
        "distractor2": "increased military spending.",
        "distractor3": "free-market solutions.",
        "distractor4": "the right to life. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Historically disadvantaged groups tend to",
        "correct_answer": "vote Democratic.",
        "distractor1": "vote Republican.",
        "distractor2": "vote for Green candidates.",
        "distractor3": "vote Libertarian.",
        "distractor4": "vote as Independents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to men, women are more likely to",
        "correct_answer": "both A and B ",
        "distractor1": "oppose higher levels of military spending.",
        "distractor2": "support spending on social services.",
        "distractor3": "be indifferent to issues of government spending.",
        "distractor4": "support military intervention around the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "The term gender gap refers to",
        "correct_answer": "stable pattern where women tend to be more likely than men to vote Democratic.",
        "distractor1": "greater success of men than women when running for office.",
        "distractor2": "greater poverty of women than of men.",
        "distractor3": "higher political contributions made by women than of men.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most liberal religious group in America are",
        "correct_answer": "Jews.",
        "distractor1": "Christian Right.",
        "distractor2": "Catholics.",
        "distractor3": "Protestants.",
        "distractor4": "Muslims. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the classic study, The American Voter, done in the 1950s, most Americans fell intothe category of",
        "correct_answer": "group benefits voters.",
        "distractor1": "ideologues.",
        "distractor2": "no-issue-content voters.",
        "distractor3": "anti-ideologues.",
        "distractor4": "nature-of-the-times voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Voter study on ideological sophistication among voters in the 1950s showed thatonly a small percentage of Americans",
        "correct_answer": "had a coherent political ideology.",
        "distractor1": "had no coherent political ideology.",
        "distractor2": "identified with groups reflecting their own interests.",
        "distractor3": "had ever taken a government or civics course.",
        "distractor4": "linked their own economic well-being with the party in power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American Voter study on ideological sophistication among voters in the 1950s showed thata plurality of Americans were",
        "correct_answer": "group benefits voters.",
        "distractor1": "ideologues.",
        "distractor2": "nature-of-the-times voters.",
        "distractor3": "authoritarian personalities.",
        "distractor4": "no-issue-content voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the categories used in the classic study, The American Voter, those who voted for aparty out of routine, or judged candidates strictly by their personalities were classified as",
        "correct_answer": "no-issue-content voters. ",
        "distractor1": "group benefits voters.",
        "distractor2": "nature-of-the-times voters.",
        "distractor3": "ideologues.",
        "distractor4": "personalistic voters."
    },
    {
        "question": "If the exact same methods are used to update the analysis of The American Voter study, onefinds",
        "correct_answer": "only some increase in the percentage of ideologues in 1988 compared to 1956.",
        "distractor1": "there are more no-issue-content voters than group benefit voters in 1988.",
        "distractor2": "a dramatic increase in the number of authoritarian personalities since 1956.",
        "distractor3": "half as many nature-of-the-times voters in 1988 than in 1956.",
        "distractor4": "ideologues became a plurality in 1988. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The authors of The American Voter would agree with each of the following statements EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "People who think in ideological terms are most likely to switch parties from one election to the next.",
        "distractor1": "It is a misnomer to speak of election results as indicating a movement of the public either left or right.",
        "distractor2": "For most people, the terms liberal and conservative are not as important as they are for the political elite.",
        "distractor3": "Eisenhower's two election victories represented a shift in the conservative direction during the 1950s.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "When people vote according to the nature of the times,",
        "correct_answer": "they are more interested in results than ideology and judge presidents by results.",
        "distractor1": "partisan identification becomes an even stronger influence on aggregate voting.",
        "distractor2": "they are not voting wisely.",
        "distractor3": "they are not making rational choices.",
        "distractor4": "their opinions are not clearly heard. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Recent presidential elections have shown",
        "correct_answer": "that voters are less interested in ideology or issue positions than in candidate traits such as competence and integrity.",
        "distractor1": "a sharp turn in public thinking to more conservative positions on issues.",
        "distractor2": "a sharp turn in public thinking to more liberal positions on issues.",
        "distractor3": "a dramatic growth of ideological voters.",
        "distractor4": "that voters are more interested in issue positions than in candidate ideology. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the presidential election of 2004, ________ of Americans voted.",
        "correct_answer": "55 percent",
        "distractor1": "69 percent",
        "distractor2": "39 percent",
        "distractor3": "59 percent",
        "distractor4": "45 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about political participation is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Political activity is an important part of the everyday life of most Americans.",
        "distractor1": "The mass protests throughout Eastern Europe in 1989 were an avalanche of political participation.",
        "distractor2": "Political participation can be organized or individual.",
        "distractor3": "Generally, the United States has a participatory political culture.",
        "distractor4": "Voting is one type of participation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common form of political participation in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "voting in presidential elections.",
        "distractor1": "voting in local elections.",
        "distractor2": "belonging to a political party.",
        "distractor3": "writing letters to public officials.",
        "distractor4": "working on a political campaign. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Sidney Verba and his colleagues found that while voter turnout declined between 1967 and1987,",
        "correct_answer": "contacting government officials and giving money to candidates increased.",
        "distractor1": "writing letters to the editor and contacting government officials increased.",
        "distractor2": "participating in non-political activities increased.",
        "distractor3": "protesting and giving money to candidates increased.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Protest",
        "correct_answer": "is designed to achieve policy change through dramatic and unconventional tactics.",
        "distractor1": "involves consciously breaking a law thought to be unjust.",
        "distractor2": "usually involves the use of violence, even murder, to achieve desired results.",
        "distractor3": "is considered a conventional form of political participation.",
        "distractor4": "requires civil disobedience to be effective. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Civil disobedience necessarily involves",
        "correct_answer": "consciously breaking a law thought to be unjust.",
        "distractor1": "non-violent protests to achieve desired results.",
        "distractor2": "working within the laws to achieve objectives.",
        "distractor3": "rioting and violence to achieve desired results.",
        "distractor4": "A and D only "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most famous practitioner of civil disobedience in the United States during the twentiethcentury was this Nobel Peace Prize winner,",
        "correct_answer": "Martin Luther King, Jr. ",
        "distractor1": "Robert F. Kennedy.",
        "distractor2": "Mother Jones.",
        "distractor3": "John F. Kennedy.",
        "distractor4": "Jesse Jackson."
    },
    {
        "question": "Civil disobedience",
        "correct_answer": "is intentionally violating a law believed to be unjust in order to bring about change.",
        "distractor1": "usually involves the use of violence.",
        "distractor2": "was first used by Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., to call attention to the injustice of segregation laws.",
        "distractor3": "occurs whenever a person violates a law and seeks to avoid the consequences.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE in regard to the voting habits of African Americans andHispanic Americans?",
        "correct_answer": "Members of these groups are more likely to vote than whites of the same income level.",
        "distractor1": "They have always voted about as much as whites despite legal barriers.",
        "distractor2": "The gap between their voter turnout and that of whites has widened considerably over the past thirty years.",
        "distractor3": "Members of these groups are less likely to vote the higher their income.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups would be LEAST likely to vote in a typical election?",
        "correct_answer": "poor white voters",
        "distractor1": "middle-class minority voters",
        "distractor2": "rich white voters",
        "distractor3": "poor minority voters",
        "distractor4": "rich minority voters "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the reasons why the participation gap between minority groups and the nationalaverage is no longer enormous is because",
        "correct_answer": "minorities have a group consciousness that gives them an extra incentive to vote. ",
        "distractor1": "minorities are now the majority, and their average is the national average.",
        "distractor2": "the education and income levels of minorities are no longer significantly lower than that of whites.",
        "distractor3": "large numbers of minorities are now running for important political offices.",
        "distractor4": "education and income are no longer considered good predictors of voting behavior."
    },
    {
        "question": "There is evidence that when incomes and educational levels are equal",
        "correct_answer": "members of minority groups tend to participate more than members of the majority.",
        "distractor1": "members of the majority tend to be more politically active than minorities.",
        "distractor2": "Hispanics participate more than whites and African Americans participate less than whites.",
        "distractor3": "Hispanics, African Americans, and women tend to be less politically active than white males.",
        "distractor4": "the political participation of members of minority groups and the majority are also equal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A media event is",
        "correct_answer": "staged primarily for the purpose of being covered by the press.",
        "distractor1": "a news event deemed of such importance to break into regular programming on television and radio.",
        "distractor2": "a gathering of people working in the media industry, often an awards ceremony.",
        "distractor3": "some newsworthy occurrence covered by reporters of the various media.",
        "distractor4": "a setup by the media to ambush or embarrass a prominent person. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ is staged by a campaign primarily for the purpose of being covered on televisionand in the press.",
        "correct_answer": "media event",
        "distractor1": "TV commercial",
        "distractor2": "political incident",
        "distractor3": "  Get Out the Vote   effort",
        "distractor4": "political play "
    },
    {
        "question": "Media events are",
        "correct_answer": "purposely staged events held in front of the media.",
        "distractor1": "spontaneous occurrences such as train wrecks or assassinations that we normally think of as news.",
        "distractor2": "monopolized by political elites.",
        "distractor3": "spontaneous events used to enhance image.",
        "distractor4": "ineffective when used by political radicals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Purposely staged activities held in front of the media are called",
        "correct_answer": "media events.",
        "distractor1": "trial balloons.",
        "distractor2": "political dramas.",
        "distractor3": "press conferences.",
        "distractor4": "news. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately ________ of presidential campaign spending is for TV ads.",
        "correct_answer": "60 percent",
        "distractor1": "40 percent",
        "distractor2": "20 percent",
        "distractor3": "80 percent",
        "distractor4": "90 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, Ronald Reagan's presidency was characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "more concern and energy devoted to the president's media appearances than in any other administration.",
        "distractor1": "a number of spontaneous media appearances by the president designed to take advantage of his Hollywood experience.",
        "distractor2": "considerable animosity between the media and the administration.",
        "distractor3": "Reagan's frequent false statements which were later documented by reporters to be either errors or deliberate lies.",
        "distractor4": "attempts to avoid media appearances by the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "News management in the Reagan White House operated on each of the following principlesEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "expand reporters ยน access to the president.",
        "distractor1": "talk about the issues you want to talk about.",
        "distractor2": "control the flow of information.",
        "distractor3": "revving helicopter engines so the president would not be able to hear reporters ยน questions and not have to answer them.",
        "distractor4": "stay on the offense. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Up until the presidency of Franklin Roosevelt,",
        "correct_answer": "reporters submitted their questions to presidents in writing.",
        "distractor1": "reporters did not ask presidents questions, they simply reported what presidents did.",
        "distractor2": "presidents held daily press conferences.",
        "distractor3": "presidents held private chats with reporters in a very informal setting rather than hold public press conferences.",
        "distractor4": "reporters had fireside chats with presidents in the White House. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first president to manipulate media politics with many press conferences and firesidechats successfully was",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt.",
        "distractor1": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor2": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor3": "Abraham Lincoln.",
        "distractor4": "John F. Kennedy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In what was a very different era, the press chose not to point out to readers or to photographthe fact that President ________ was confined to a wheelchair.",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt ",
        "distractor1": "Warren Harding",
        "distractor2": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor3": "Dwight Eisenhower",
        "distractor4": "Lyndon Johnson"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did President Roosevelt become silent during the last minute of a radio address during areelection campaign?",
        "correct_answer": "He wanted to reduce the size of his opponent's audience.",
        "distractor1": "Political pranksters from the Republican party disabled the power supply to the radio station.",
        "distractor2": "The radio station director disliked the positions Roosevelt was taking and cut him off.",
        "distractor3": "He talked for so long that he lost his voice.",
        "distractor4": "The radio station cut him off because he had exceeded his time limit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which president held one thousand press conferences, far more than any other?",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt",
        "distractor1": "John F. Kennedy",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor4": "Bill Clinton "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first president to successfully utilize media politics was",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt. ",
        "distractor1": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor3": "George Washington.",
        "distractor4": "Abraham Lincoln."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Franklin Roosevelt and the news media is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The press often reported on Roosevelt's health and confinement to a wheelchair.",
        "distractor1": "Roosevelt used presidential wrath to warn reporters off material he did not want covered.",
        "distractor2": "The press revered Roosevelt.",
        "distractor3": "Roosevelt knew how to feed the right story to the right reporter.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The cozy relationship between politicians and the press in the twentieth century lasted until",
        "correct_answer": "the Vietnam War and Watergate. ",
        "distractor1": "the Iranian Hostage Crisis.",
        "distractor2": "World War II.",
        "distractor3": "the commercialization of television.",
        "distractor4": "the beginning of Franklin Roosevelt's presidency."
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of detective-like reporting methods to unearth scandals is known as",
        "correct_answer": "investigative journalism.",
        "distractor1": "yellow journalism.",
        "distractor2": "trial balloons.",
        "distractor3": "scientific journalism.",
        "distractor4": "print journalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The cozy relationship between politicians and the press ended when",
        "correct_answer": "the Vietnam War and Watergate soured the press on government.",
        "distractor1": "the press discovered John F. Kennedy in a compromising situation with a woman other than his wife.",
        "distractor2": "Franklin Roosevelt chastised the news reports he deemed inaccurate.",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan began to manipulate the press to his advantage.",
        "distractor4": "Abraham Lincoln nationalized major Union newspapers during the Civil War. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today's news people work in an environment of ________ toward government.",
        "correct_answer": "cynicism",
        "distractor1": "friendship",
        "distractor2": "hostility",
        "distractor3": "trust",
        "distractor4": "acceptance "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the turn of the century, newspaper magnates Joseph and William Randolph Hearst usheredin the era of",
        "correct_answer": "yellow journalism.",
        "distractor1": "nickel tabloids.",
        "distractor2": "newspaper chains.",
        "distractor3": "penny press.",
        "distractor4": "political advertising. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first daily newspaper in America was",
        "correct_answer": "printed in Philadelphia in 1783.",
        "distractor1": "the Associated Press established in 1841.",
        "distractor2": "The New York Times established in 1800.",
        "distractor3": "the Colonial Gazette printed in 1607.",
        "distractor4": "Common Sense printed in 1776. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Associated Press is an example of a",
        "correct_answer": "wire service.",
        "distractor1": "high-technology medium.",
        "distractor2": "newspaper chain.",
        "distractor3": "massive media conglomerate.",
        "distractor4": "trade association acting as an interest group for newspapers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "With over 2,700 reporters, photographers and editors, ________ has more news gatheringability than any other news organization.",
        "correct_answer": "the Associated Press",
        "distractor1": "Gannett",
        "distractor2": "The New York Times",
        "distractor3": "Columbia Broadcasting System",
        "distractor4": "King Features Syndicate "
    },
    {
        "question": "The nation's most influential newspaper and its unofficial   newspaper of record   is",
        "correct_answer": "The New York Times.",
        "distractor1": "Congressional Quarterly.",
        "distractor2": "USA Today.",
        "distractor3": "the Wall Street Journal.",
        "distractor4": "the Washington Post. "
    },
    {
        "question": "For most newspapers in medium-sized cities and small towns, their principal source forreporting national and world news is",
        "correct_answer": "The Associated Press.",
        "distractor1": "USA Today.",
        "distractor2": "The New York Times.",
        "distractor3": "Cable News Network.",
        "distractor4": "The Washington Post. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In a famous, televised speech in 1952 to save his vice -presidential candidacy, ________ deniedhaving received illegal gifts and payments, and declared that the family dog, Checkers, thougha gift, would not be returned.",
        "correct_answer": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor1": "John Sparkman",
        "distractor2": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor3": "Spiro Agnew",
        "distractor4": "Dwight Eisenhower "
    },
    {
        "question": "Serious magazines of political news and opinion are",
        "correct_answer": "basically reserved for the educated elite in America.",
        "distractor1": "almost nonexistent in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "a principle source of news and information for most Americans.",
        "distractor3": "rapidly dying out in the United States, but remain very healthy in Europe and Latin America.",
        "distractor4": "a more common source for national and international news than newspapers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle source of news and information in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "the broadcast media. ",
        "distractor1": "the print media.",
        "distractor2": "magazines and radio.",
        "distractor3": "newspapers.",
        "distractor4": "radio talk shows."
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, magazines are",
        "correct_answer": "not a major source of news in the United States.",
        "distractor1": "politically conservative.",
        "distractor2": "basically reserved for the educated elite.",
        "distractor3": "not read very widely in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "a major source of news in the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Newspaper magnates Joseph Pulitzer and William Randolph Hearst tried to outdo oneanother in sensational reporting of wars, violence, corruption, and gossip around the turn ofthe twentieth century in what is now remembered as the era of",
        "correct_answer": "yellow journalism.",
        "distractor1": "investigative journalism.",
        "distractor2": "tabloid journalism.",
        "distractor3": "scandalism.",
        "distractor4": "hyperjournalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Television became extremely important in political campaigns beginning in",
        "correct_answer": "1960.",
        "distractor1": "1948.",
        "distractor2": "1952.",
        "distractor3": "1972.",
        "distractor4": "1984. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard Nixon believed he lost the 1960 presidential election because",
        "correct_answer": "he was sweating and had an ugly beard stubble during a debate with Kennedy. ",
        "distractor1": "news coverage of his campaign was consistently biased against him.",
        "distractor2": "the Cuban Missile Crisis stole media attention from his campaign.",
        "distractor3": "of voter fraud in New York City.",
        "distractor4": "of Kennedy's dramatic pledge not to raise taxes."
    },
    {
        "question": "The first televised ________ occurred during the 1960 presidential campaign.",
        "correct_answer": "presidential debate",
        "distractor1": "election returns",
        "distractor2": "national political convention",
        "distractor3": "political commercial",
        "distractor4": "presidential press conference "
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1960 presidential debate between Richard Nixon and John F. Kennedy illustrates the",
        "correct_answer": "power of television in American politics. ",
        "distractor1": "propagandistic nature of American presidential campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "role of radio broadcasting in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "importance of experience in presidential politics.",
        "distractor4": "importance of issues in presidential debates."
    },
    {
        "question": "Television became especially important in bringing the reality of ________ home to America asits first heavily televised war.",
        "correct_answer": "the Vietnam War",
        "distractor1": "the Korean War",
        "distractor2": "World War I",
        "distractor3": "the war in Iraq",
        "distractor4": "World War II "
    },
    {
        "question": "Narrowcasting refers to",
        "correct_answer": "media programming aimed at a particular (narrow) audience.",
        "distractor1": "media programming focused entirely on media events.",
        "distractor2": "the technical ability to block access to broadcast signals.",
        "distractor3": "media programming delivered in brief program segments.",
        "distractor4": "political advertising being developed for homogeneous audiences. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the military campaign in Afghanistan, President Bush and the White House frequentlywatched ________ to see events as they happened.",
        "correct_answer": "CNN",
        "distractor1": "Nightline",
        "distractor2": "Good Morning America",
        "distractor3": "closed circuit, top-secret Pentagon video relays",
        "distractor4": "The MacNeil/Lehrer Newshour "
    },
    {
        "question": "Cable News Network (CNN)",
        "correct_answer": "has brought television into a new era of bringing the news to people and political leaders as it happens.",
        "distractor1": "has taken the place of the three major networks as Americans ยน primary source for news.",
        "distractor2": "specializes in after-the-fact news summaries and in-depth analysis.",
        "distractor3": "is a government-owned news agency that specializes in international news.",
        "distractor4": "has had more effect on the mass public than it has had on political elites. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To a large extent, television networks define news as what is ________ to viewers.",
        "correct_answer": "entertaining",
        "distractor1": "informative",
        "distractor2": "vital information",
        "distractor3": "thought-provoking",
        "distractor4": "yet unknown "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most news organizations assign their best reporters to particular ________, which are specificlocations where news frequently emanates.",
        "correct_answer": "beats",
        "distractor1": "digs",
        "distractor2": "  theaters  ",
        "distractor3": "  lighthouses  ",
        "distractor4": "chains "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today's massive media conglomerates control newspapers with over ________ of the nation'sdaily circulation.",
        "correct_answer": "80 percent",
        "distractor1": "53 percent",
        "distractor2": "30 percent",
        "distractor3": "50 percent",
        "distractor4": "33 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The bottom line that shapes how journalists define the news, where they get the news, andhow they present it is",
        "correct_answer": "profits.",
        "distractor1": "their personal ideology.",
        "distractor2": "the First Amendment right to freedom of the press.",
        "distractor3": "government regulations.",
        "distractor4": "their professional values. "
    },
    {
        "question": "News is what",
        "correct_answer": "is timely and different.",
        "distractor1": "the public believes are the most important political issues facing the country.",
        "distractor2": "government officials want it to be.",
        "distractor3": "has the greatest impact on the most people.",
        "distractor4": "journalism professors say it is. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Television news programs are tailored to",
        "correct_answer": "a fairly low level of audience sophistication.",
        "distractor1": "a highly educated audience.",
        "distractor2": "male audiences in their twenties and thirties with high disposable incomes.",
        "distractor3": "white middle-class America.",
        "distractor4": "an urban population. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reporters and their official sources usually have a(n) ________ relationship.",
        "correct_answer": "symbiotic ",
        "distractor1": "hostile",
        "distractor2": "disinterested",
        "distractor3": "adversarial",
        "distractor4": "conspiratorial"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most news coverage is perhaps best described as",
        "correct_answer": "superficial.",
        "distractor1": "thorough.",
        "distractor2": "complex.",
        "distractor3": "superlative.",
        "distractor4": "metacognitive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most television news analysis reports",
        "correct_answer": "last less than a minute.",
        "distractor1": "run over ten minutes.",
        "distractor2": "run about five minutes.",
        "distractor3": "run about seven minutes.",
        "distractor4": "run about two minutes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "News coverage by the print and broadcast media is generally",
        "correct_answer": "superficial. ",
        "distractor1": "very ideologically biased.",
        "distractor2": "comprehensive.",
        "distractor3": "detailed.",
        "distractor4": "controversial."
    },
    {
        "question": "Television news coverage characteristically",
        "correct_answer": "lacks in-depth analysis.",
        "distractor1": "has little impact on shaping political opinions.",
        "distractor2": "emphasizes policy issues.",
        "distractor3": "focuses on Congressional politics more than presidential politics.",
        "distractor4": "focuses on what elites think is important. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As technology has enabled the media to pass along information with greater speed, newscoverage has become",
        "correct_answer": "less complete.",
        "distractor1": "less biased.",
        "distractor2": "randomized.",
        "distractor3": "more biased.",
        "distractor4": "more complete. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Sound bites are",
        "correct_answer": "short clips of a political speech lasting fifteen seconds or less.",
        "distractor1": "leaks by official sources used to test the political waters.",
        "distractor2": "negative news coverage received by a public figure. They hurt!",
        "distractor3": "a form of censorship widely used in Great Britain.",
        "distractor4": "negative political advertisements that offer quick attacks on one's opponent. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A catchy line is what is most important for a",
        "correct_answer": "sound bite.",
        "distractor1": "beat.",
        "distractor2": "leak.",
        "distractor3": "trial balloon.",
        "distractor4": "presidential press conference. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1992 election campaign, CBS News promised to ________, but then changed itspolicy when it proved to be unworkable.",
        "correct_answer": "reform the sound bite process",
        "distractor1": "follow campaign ads with factual analysis",
        "distractor2": "ban coverage of polls",
        "distractor3": "float no trial balloons",
        "distractor4": "give equal time to each candidate on each news broadcast "
    },
    {
        "question": "Rather than cover entire speeches by political figures, television news typically provides________ of fifteen seconds or less.",
        "correct_answer": "sound bites",
        "distractor1": "trial balloons",
        "distractor2": "beats",
        "distractor3": "leaks",
        "distractor4": "news snacks "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2004, the average sound bite of a presidential candidate shown talking on the nightly newsaveraged",
        "correct_answer": "less than ten seconds.",
        "distractor1": "about thirty seconds.",
        "distractor2": "about two minutes.",
        "distractor3": "about ninety seconds.",
        "distractor4": "about a minute. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The average amount of air time that a presidential candidate has been given to talkuninterrupted on the TV news",
        "correct_answer": "has declined dramatically since the 1960s.",
        "distractor1": "has increased dramatically since 1960.",
        "distractor2": "has increased dramatically since 1980.",
        "distractor3": "has been remarkably consistent over the years.",
        "distractor4": "has increased slightly since 1970. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about television news is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Television analysis of news events has been rapidly increasing.",
        "distractor1": "The only highly regarded in-depth news shows on television are watched by very few viewers.",
        "distractor2": "Studies have shown that television gives only skimpy attention to the issues during a presidential campaign.",
        "distractor3": "The complex issues of today are difficult to treat in a short news clip.",
        "distractor4": "Television news is less detailed than that presented in newspapers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A 2002 survey of 1,149 journalists found that, compared to the general public, journalists weretwice as likely to consider themselves",
        "correct_answer": "Democrats.",
        "distractor1": "radicals.",
        "distractor2": "Republicans.",
        "distractor3": "conservatives.",
        "distractor4": "policy entrepreneurs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One survey of journalists in 2002 found that ________ were Democrats.",
        "correct_answer": "37 percent",
        "distractor1": "29 percent",
        "distractor2": "60 percent",
        "distractor3": "45 percent",
        "distractor4": "85 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "A study by the Los Angeles Times in the mid-1980s found that reporters were ________ as likelyto call themselves liberal as the general public.",
        "correct_answer": "twice",
        "distractor1": "half",
        "distractor2": "one-third",
        "distractor3": "just",
        "distractor4": "not "
    },
    {
        "question": "The overriding bias in the news is toward stories that",
        "correct_answer": "draw large audiences.",
        "distractor1": "include talking heads.",
        "distractor2": "are triangular.",
        "distractor3": "are liberal.",
        "distractor4": "target-specific audiences. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to fascinate television news viewers?",
        "correct_answer": "a talking head",
        "distractor1": "violence",
        "distractor2": "scandal",
        "distractor3": "disaster",
        "distractor4": "a breaking crime story "
    },
    {
        "question": "The news does not mirror reality because",
        "correct_answer": "journalists must select stories that will draw the largest audience.",
        "distractor1": "journalists are more liberal than most people.",
        "distractor2": "the number of potential news stories is limited.",
        "distractor3": "journalists are more conservative than most people.",
        "distractor4": "the news media are biased toward the coverage of political events. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When journalists select stories to cover, the overriding bias is toward",
        "correct_answer": "stories that will draw the largest audience.",
        "distractor1": "stories about the personality quirks of political celebrities.",
        "distractor2": "international and foreign policy stories.",
        "distractor3": "stories involving the most important policy issues of the day.",
        "distractor4": "stories that target specific audiences. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A talking head is a reference to",
        "correct_answer": "a shot of a person's face talking directly to the camera.",
        "distractor1": "a television talk show host.",
        "distractor2": "a news leak that is discretely passed to a reporter in a public washroom.",
        "distractor3": "a television news anchor.",
        "distractor4": "a television talk show. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The earliest survey studies of the effect of the media on public opinion, which evaluated itsimpact on voting behavior, offered",
        "correct_answer": "the minimal effects hypothesis.",
        "distractor1": "much evidence that media action influenced political campaign outcomes.",
        "distractor2": "a policy agenda interpretation.",
        "distractor3": "the observation that Democratic control of Congress was partly due to media bias in news coverage.",
        "distractor4": "the hypodermic needle model. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of the   minimal effects hypothesis   about the media's effect on public opinion point tothe media's role in",
        "correct_answer": "shaping what priority Americans attach to problems.",
        "distractor1": "how voters cast their ballots.",
        "distractor2": "concealing problems that exist by ignoring them.",
        "distractor3": "whether people choose to vote.",
        "distractor4": "mobilizing voter turnout. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the list of subjects or problems to which government officials, and peopleoutside of government closely associated with those officials, are paying some seriousattention to at any given time.",
        "correct_answer": "policy agenda ",
        "distractor1": "A-List",
        "distractor2": "plum book",
        "distractor3": "prioritization schedule",
        "distractor4": "catalog of current issues"
    },
    {
        "question": "Agenda-setting effects on public opinion are an example of how",
        "correct_answer": "the media cue individuals about what political issues are important to think about.",
        "distractor1": "the media influence individual's vote choices.",
        "distractor2": "the media have a bias in favor of the status quo.",
        "distractor3": "the media have a liberal bias.",
        "distractor4": "the media have no bias. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Agenda setting effects are especially strong for the",
        "correct_answer": "politically knowledgeable who trust the media.",
        "distractor1": "younger generation who distrust the media.",
        "distractor2": "politically ignorant who trust the media.",
        "distractor3": "television audience who trusts the media.",
        "distractor4": "older, more politically experienced individuals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The impact of TV news is that it",
        "correct_answer": "alters the priorities Americans attach to a circumscribed set of problems.",
        "distractor1": "familiarizes the public with issues through its emphasis on headline reading.",
        "distractor2": "influences the governmental agenda because policymakers and policy entrepreneurs depend on it.",
        "distractor3": "has little influence on the public agenda because most viewers are less educated.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The policy agenda is",
        "correct_answer": "a list of priorities to which government officials address their time and energies.",
        "distractor1": "a set of issues or problems that the public considers important.",
        "distractor2": "a schedule of bills before Congress.",
        "distractor3": "a linkage institution between people and government.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "People who invest their political   capital   in a particular issue are often called",
        "correct_answer": "policy entrepreneurs.",
        "distractor1": "talking heads.",
        "distractor2": "policy wonks.",
        "distractor3": "political investors.",
        "distractor4": "policy specialists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are NOT normally policy entrepreneurs?",
        "correct_answer": "mass media",
        "distractor1": "appointed government officials",
        "distractor2": "interest groups",
        "distractor3": "elected government officials",
        "distractor4": "political parties "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about policy agendas is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Only government officials develop policy priorities.",
        "distractor1": "Interest groups, political parties, and the president are all examples of those who push for their priorities to take precedence.",
        "distractor2": "Scores of issues compete for attention from the government.",
        "distractor3": "The policy agenda receives some serious attention at any given time.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "A policy entrepreneur is",
        "correct_answer": "someone who works to get ideas on the government's policy agenda.",
        "distractor1": "an elected or appointed public official.",
        "distractor2": "a candidate seeking a career in elective office.",
        "distractor3": "a knowledge specialist in a policy area.",
        "distractor4": "someone who uses politics for self-gain. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The media usually report on America's social problems in a manner that",
        "correct_answer": "encourages government to take on more and more tasks.",
        "distractor1": "suggests government can really not be trusted to take on more tasks.",
        "distractor2": "is neither critical nor positive.",
        "distractor3": "displays a lack of real sensitivity.",
        "distractor4": "has often been described as benign neglect. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about the media in America?",
        "correct_answer": "Their skepticism about governmental honesty and efficiency leads them to oppose giving government greater responsibilities.",
        "distractor1": "The media argue that if their news is superficial, it is because that is what people want.",
        "distractor2": "The media do a better job covering the   horse race   aspect of politics than of covering substantive issues.",
        "distractor3": "Reporters often see themselves in a reformism role, crusading against foul play and unfairness.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "More than any other development in the twentieth century, the rise of television broadcastinghas reinforced ________ in the American political process.",
        "correct_answer": "individualism",
        "distractor1": "interest",
        "distractor2": "behavioralism",
        "distractor3": "participation",
        "distractor4": "democratization "
    },
    {
        "question": "The watchdog orientation of the press helps to",
        "correct_answer": "restrict politicians.",
        "distractor1": "increase confidence in government.",
        "distractor2": "de-emphasize individualism.",
        "distractor3": "educate the mass public.",
        "distractor4": "assist politicians in leading the mass public. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The watchdog orientation of the press can be characterized as",
        "correct_answer": "reformist.",
        "distractor1": "liberal.",
        "distractor2": "libertarian.",
        "distractor3": "conservative.",
        "distractor4": "partisan. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The media inevitably encourage the growth of government when they",
        "correct_answer": "focus on injustice in society. ",
        "distractor1": "focus on policy issues.",
        "distractor2": "reapply for their broadcast licenses.",
        "distractor3": "uncover government waste.",
        "distractor4": "act as a watchdog."
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest segment of an American political party is described as",
        "correct_answer": "the party-in-the-electorate.",
        "distractor1": "the party-out-of-power.",
        "distractor2": "the party-in-government.",
        "distractor3": "the party volunteers.",
        "distractor4": "the party organization. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the description of political parties as   three-headed political giants,   which of the followingis NOT considered one of those three heads?",
        "correct_answer": "the party-out-of-power",
        "distractor1": "the party-in-government",
        "distractor2": "the party-in-the-electorate",
        "distractor3": "the party as an organization",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE of political parties in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "To be a member of a party, all you have to do is claim to be one.",
        "distractor1": "Parties require dues.",
        "distractor2": "They are more powerful than their European counterparts.",
        "distractor3": "Parties issue membership cards to all members.",
        "distractor4": "Party members agree on all major issues or they will be expelled from the party. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The key spokespersons for political parties come from which of its major components?",
        "correct_answer": "the party-in-government ",
        "distractor1": "the party-in-the-electorate",
        "distractor2": "the party as an organization",
        "distractor3": "the party-out-of-power",
        "distractor4": "the leaders-of-the-party-organization"
    },
    {
        "question": "A political party is best defined as",
        "correct_answer": "a team of men and women seeking control of the governing apparatus by gaining office in a duly constituted election.",
        "distractor1": "a group of men and women organized for the sole purpose of influencing public policy.",
        "distractor2": "an organized team of men and women with a political agenda.",
        "distractor3": "any group of men and women with a formal membership and a political or social purpose stated in their by-laws.",
        "distractor4": "a coalition of interests trying to influence government policies for their benefit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the   three-headed political giant   model of political parties, the largestcomponent of an American party is the",
        "correct_answer": "party-in-the-electorate.",
        "distractor1": "party as an organization.",
        "distractor2": "party-in-the-states.",
        "distractor3": "party Congress.",
        "distractor4": "party-in-government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, to become a member of a political party you need to",
        "correct_answer": "claim to be a member. ",
        "distractor1": "pay annual dues.",
        "distractor2": "officially join that party by attending a party meeting.",
        "distractor3": "hold a membership card.",
        "distractor4": "register with that party at your precinct office."
    },
    {
        "question": "The people who keep the party running between elections and make its rules are members ofwhich   head   of the party?",
        "correct_answer": "party as an organization",
        "distractor1": "party-in-the-electorate",
        "distractor2": "permanent party",
        "distractor3": "party-in-government",
        "distractor4": "party-in-the-states "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   party-in-government   refers to",
        "correct_answer": "winning candidates who become the main spokespersons for the party that nominated them.",
        "distractor1": "registered party voters who hold civil service jobs in the government and are influencing policy.",
        "distractor2": "coalitions of interests and ideologies that support a party's candidates.",
        "distractor3": "party workers who hold patronage jobs in the government and can influence policy.",
        "distractor4": "party members who perpetuate the party, make its rules, and keep it running. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a linkage institution?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Supreme Court",
        "distractor2": "Executive Office of the President",
        "distractor3": "Congress",
        "distractor4": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "A party's endorsement to officially run for office as the candidate of that party is called",
        "correct_answer": "a nomination.",
        "distractor1": "a ballot.",
        "distractor2": "a ticket.",
        "distractor3": "a confirmation.",
        "distractor4": "an appointment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political parties perform all of the following tasks EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "enforce rigid adherence to their policy positions.",
        "distractor1": "pick policymakers and run campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "advocate public policies.",
        "distractor3": "coordinate policymaking.",
        "distractor4": "give cues to voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As ________, political parties serve the role of translating inputs from the public into outputsfrom policymakers.",
        "correct_answer": "linkage institutions ",
        "distractor1": "coalitions",
        "distractor2": "superdelegates",
        "distractor3": "political converters",
        "distractor4": "machines"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rational-choice theory asserts that",
        "correct_answer": "the wise party selects policies that are widely favored.",
        "distractor1": "the parties should not be expected to differentiate themselves in any way.",
        "distractor2": "more extremist party positions give the public a sense that things can really be changed, and usually win elections.",
        "distractor3": "the wise party selects policies in which it truly believes, and gives the voters a chance to vote them up or down on principle.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The theory that seeks to explain political processes and outcomes as consequences ofpurposive behavior is called the",
        "correct_answer": "rational-choice theory.",
        "distractor1": "behaviorism.",
        "distractor2": "means-ends theory.",
        "distractor3": "cognitive theory.",
        "distractor4": "goals theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to 1952, recent polls on party identification have shown that",
        "correct_answer": "there are more independents than there are Democrats or Republicans.",
        "distractor1": "more people today identify themselves as Democrats.",
        "distractor2": "the percentage of Democrats has increased only slightly, while the percentage of Republicans has declined.",
        "distractor3": "both the percentages of both Democrats and Republicans in the country have increased.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ticket-splitting is best understood as",
        "correct_answer": "voting with one party for one office and another for other offices.",
        "distractor1": "voting for Democratic candidates for president and Republican candidates for Congress.",
        "distractor2": "a tactic used to commit voter fraud, which enables a voter to cast multiple ballots.",
        "distractor3": "staying with the same party in an election, voting down the party's line for every race.",
        "distractor4": "voting for Republican candidates for president and Democratic candidates for Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The upsurge of partisan independence among Americans since 1952",
        "correct_answer": "has come mostly at the expense of the Democrats.",
        "distractor1": "has come mostly at the expense of the Republicans.",
        "distractor2": "has not harmed either party.",
        "distractor3": "has occurred mostly among minor party identifiers.",
        "distractor4": "has harmed both parties equally. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2004, Americans were most likely to consider themselves ________, and least likely toconsider themselves ________.",
        "correct_answer": "Independents; Republicans",
        "distractor1": "Independents; Democrats",
        "distractor2": "Republicans; Democrats",
        "distractor3": "Democrats; Independents",
        "distractor4": "Democrats; Republicans "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most Americans are",
        "correct_answer": "moderate.",
        "distractor1": "liberal.",
        "distractor2": "moderate-liberals.",
        "distractor3": "conservative.",
        "distractor4": "non-ideological. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In recent elections, the trends in party identification in the United States have been",
        "correct_answer": "a decrease in the percentage of Democrats and an increase in the percentage of Independents.",
        "distractor1": "an increase in the percentage of Democrats and a decline in the percentage of Independents.",
        "distractor2": "an increase in the percentages of Democrats and Republicans and a decline in the percentage of Independents.",
        "distractor3": "an increase in the percentage of Democrats and a decline in the percentage of Republicans.",
        "distractor4": "a fairly constant percentage of Democrats, Republicans, and Independents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ticket-splitting refers to",
        "correct_answer": "voting for one party for one office, and another party for other offices.",
        "distractor1": "switching membership in political parties.",
        "distractor2": "the procedure used to conduct computerized, automated vote counting.",
        "distractor3": "voting with one party in one presidential election, and another party in the next presidential election.",
        "distractor4": "voting for a party other than the one you identify with. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of organizational structure, American political parties are",
        "correct_answer": "decentralized and fragmented.",
        "distractor1": "organized more by regions of the country than at the state or national level.",
        "distractor2": "tightly controlled organisms that exert tremendous control over candidates.",
        "distractor3": "operated on the principle of democratic centralism: Local and state organizations control the national organizations.",
        "distractor4": "centralized and hierarchical. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Power in the major United States political parties is",
        "correct_answer": "fragmented among local, state, and national party organizations.",
        "distractor1": "concentrated in the state parties, with national and local organizations playing only minor roles.",
        "distractor2": "hierarchically distributed from the national to local levels.",
        "distractor3": "centralized in national party organizations.",
        "distractor4": "concentrated in party machines at the local level. "
    },
    {
        "question": "From the late-nineteenth century through the New Deal years, many of America's largestcities were dominated by",
        "correct_answer": "corrupt but popular party machines.",
        "distractor1": "the Socialist party.",
        "distractor2": "the Communist party.",
        "distractor3": "mayors who refused to allow elections.",
        "distractor4": "super delegates who controlled everything. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Party machines in large cities relied primarily on ________ to reward friends and punishenemies.",
        "correct_answer": "patronage",
        "distractor1": "local judges",
        "distractor2": "city police departments",
        "distractor3": "the civil service merit system",
        "distractor4": "third parties "
    },
    {
        "question": "A party machine is a kind of local party organization that",
        "correct_answer": "uses specific and material inducements to win party loyalty and power.",
        "distractor1": "threatens the efficiency of state and national party organizations.",
        "distractor2": "specializes in computerized mass mailings both to raise funds and influence voters on behalf of their candidates.",
        "distractor3": "remains strong in most large American cities.",
        "distractor4": "has recently come to depend heavily on ethnic group support. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since 1960, state party organizations",
        "correct_answer": "have become much more powerful and organized. ",
        "distractor1": "have begun selecting candidates for state offices.",
        "distractor2": "have been established for the first time as the national organizations have weakened.",
        "distractor3": "have virtually disappeared as the national units have taken on their functions.",
        "distractor4": "have begun selecting candidates for Congress."
    },
    {
        "question": "About which state has it been said that the political parties are so weak as to be almostnonexistent?",
        "correct_answer": "California ",
        "distractor1": "Pennsylvania",
        "distractor2": "New York",
        "distractor3": "Texas",
        "distractor4": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "In closed primaries,",
        "correct_answer": "only voters who have registered in advance with the party can vote.",
        "distractor1": "voters may vote for candidates from either party.",
        "distractor2": "voters may choose on election day which party primary they want to participate in.",
        "distractor3": "voters may vote for multiple candidates.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In open primaries,",
        "correct_answer": "voters may choose on election day which party primary they want to participate in.",
        "distractor1": "voters may vote for candidates from either party.",
        "distractor2": "only voters who have registered in advance with the party can vote.",
        "distractor3": "voters may vote for multiple candidates.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In blanket primaries,",
        "correct_answer": "voters may vote for candidates from either party.",
        "distractor1": "voters may choose on election day which party primary they want to participate in.",
        "distractor2": "only voters who have registered in advance with the party can vote.",
        "distractor3": "voters may vote for multiple candidates.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Closed primaries",
        "correct_answer": "encourage party loyalty.",
        "distractor1": "depress voter turnout.",
        "distractor2": "discourage party loyalty.",
        "distractor3": "cost less than open primaries.",
        "distractor4": "have fewer undercounts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Blanket primaries",
        "correct_answer": "encourage party loyalty.",
        "distractor1": "cost less than open primaries.",
        "distractor2": "discourage party loyalty.",
        "distractor3": "depress voter turnout.",
        "distractor4": "have fewer undercounts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "American national parties are best described as",
        "correct_answer": "loose aggregations of state parties.",
        "distractor1": "controlled from the bottom (local level) up.",
        "distractor2": "bicameral in nature.",
        "distractor3": "centralized organizations based in Congress.",
        "distractor4": "powerful, centralized organizations based in Washington, D.C. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Each party holds a national convention every",
        "correct_answer": "four years.",
        "distractor1": "six years.",
        "distractor2": "year.",
        "distractor3": "five years.",
        "distractor4": "two years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The supreme power within each of the parties is",
        "correct_answer": "the national convention.",
        "distractor1": "the state party organizations.",
        "distractor2": "the president.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Party Court.",
        "distractor4": "the national committee. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Keeping the party operating between conventions is the job of the",
        "correct_answer": "national committee.",
        "distractor1": "regional offices.",
        "distractor2": "elected officials.",
        "distractor3": "congressional leadership.",
        "distractor4": "majority or minority whip. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The chairperson of the party that controls the White House is normally selected by",
        "correct_answer": "the president.",
        "distractor1": "members of the party in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "a committee of state chairpersons.",
        "distractor3": "closed primary.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Every political party depends upon what the text calls a ________ , meaning a set ofindividuals or groups supporting it.",
        "correct_answer": "coalition",
        "distractor1": "system of patronage",
        "distractor2": "set of super delegates",
        "distractor3": "power base",
        "distractor4": "linkage institution "
    },
    {
        "question": "The party national committees",
        "correct_answer": "keep the party operating between conventions. ",
        "distractor1": "select the party's presidential candidate.",
        "distractor2": "are composed of each party's members of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "meet once every four years.",
        "distractor4": "write and approve the party's platform."
    },
    {
        "question": "The day-to-day activities of the national party are the responsibility of the",
        "correct_answer": "national chairperson.",
        "distractor1": "congressional party leaders.",
        "distractor2": "president.",
        "distractor3": "national committee.",
        "distractor4": "national convention. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Voters and coalitions of voters are attracted to different parties largely by",
        "correct_answer": "their performance and policies.",
        "distractor1": "selective perception.",
        "distractor2": "the charisma of their candidates.",
        "distractor3": "tradition.",
        "distractor4": "their socio-economic status. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political candidates make many promises when running for office. In electing one, the publiccan expect",
        "correct_answer": "that for every broken promise, many more will be kept.",
        "distractor1": "specific implementation of the promise to differ from the general promise made during the campaign.",
        "distractor2": "few to be carried out because political promises are made to be broken.",
        "distractor3": "a significant gap between party platform and political performance.",
        "distractor4": "both A and D. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American political parties fall far short of the responsible party model for all of thefollowing reasons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "their presidential candidates ignore the party platform.",
        "distractor1": "they are too decentralized.",
        "distractor2": "there is no mechanism for the parties to discipline officeholders.",
        "distractor3": "their candidates are usually self-selected.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "A study of major party platforms by Gerald Pomper found that the parties broke theirpromises",
        "correct_answer": "ten percent of the time.",
        "distractor1": "half the time.",
        "distractor2": "two-thirds of the time.",
        "distractor3": "over ninety percent of the time.",
        "distractor4": "a third of the time. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A critical election involves and accelerates a process called",
        "correct_answer": "party realignment.",
        "distractor1": "partisan transformation.",
        "distractor2": "electoral examination.",
        "distractor3": "proportional representation.",
        "distractor4": "democratic rejuvenation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first party system in the United States consisted of the",
        "correct_answer": "Federalists and Democratic-Republicans.",
        "distractor1": "Democrats and Whigs.",
        "distractor2": "Federalists and Whigs.",
        "distractor3": "Democrats and Republicans.",
        "distractor4": "Democratic-Republicans and Whigs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The dominant political party in America's first party system was the",
        "correct_answer": "Democratic-Republicans.",
        "distractor1": "Whigs.",
        "distractor2": "Republicans.",
        "distractor3": "Democrats.",
        "distractor4": "Federalists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Democratic-Republicans were also known as the",
        "correct_answer": "Jeffersonians.",
        "distractor1": "Madisonians.",
        "distractor2": "Whigs.",
        "distractor3": "Federalists.",
        "distractor4": "Hamiltonians. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The last Federalist president was",
        "correct_answer": "John Adams.",
        "distractor1": "Alexander Hamilton.",
        "distractor2": "Andrew Jackson.",
        "distractor3": "Abraham Lincoln.",
        "distractor4": "Thomas Jefferson. "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the beginning of party development in the United States,",
        "correct_answer": "parties sought to destroy each other.",
        "distractor1": "parties tried to defeat each other in elections.",
        "distractor2": "there were many small parties, each representing a narrow interest.",
        "distractor3": "we had a one-party system where one powerful party dominated the government and blocked the creation of new parties.",
        "distractor4": "parties were merely the personal following of certain charismatic individuals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first American political party evolved",
        "correct_answer": "out of Alexander Hamilton's efforts to get Congress to establish a national bank. ",
        "distractor1": "from the supporters of George Washington's first campaign for president.",
        "distractor2": "out of Thomas Jefferson's efforts to get the Declaration of Independence adopted.",
        "distractor3": "out of public disgust over the duel between Aaron Burr and Alexander Hamilton, leading to calls to solve conflicts through peaceful party competition.",
        "distractor4": "during the Constitutional Convention."
    },
    {
        "question": "  Critical elections   always result in the",
        "correct_answer": "formation of new coalitions for each political party. ",
        "distractor1": "widespread public questioning of the American election process accompanied by calls for its reform.",
        "distractor2": "displacement of the minority party by the majority party.",
        "distractor3": "formation of new political parties.",
        "distractor4": "successful bid by a third political party."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about party realignment is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Party realignments were associated with the Civil War and with the Great Depression.",
        "distractor1": "Party realignments are typically associated with a major crisis or trauma.",
        "distractor2": "Party realignments transform the party system.",
        "distractor3": "Party realignment involves a reconfiguration of the demographic groups supporting the parties.",
        "distractor4": "Party realignments occur often in American political life. "
    },
    {
        "question": "America's first and shortest-lived major political party was the",
        "correct_answer": "Federalist party.",
        "distractor1": "Anti-Federalist party.",
        "distractor2": "Whig party.",
        "distractor3": "Democratic-Republican party.",
        "distractor4": "Independence party. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first party system (1796-1824) was characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "the dominance of the Democratic-Republican party. ",
        "distractor1": "professional politicians running for office.",
        "distractor2": "the dominance of the presidency by the Federalist party.",
        "distractor3": "the dominance of the Republican party.",
        "distractor4": "the dominance of the northern capitalist states."
    },
    {
        "question": "Andrew Jackson was the first president identified as a(n)",
        "correct_answer": "Democrat.",
        "distractor1": "Independent.",
        "distractor2": "Republican.",
        "distractor3": "Democratic-Republican.",
        "distractor4": "Whig. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the second party system in United States history, the election contests were between whichtwo major parties?",
        "correct_answer": "Democrats and Whigs",
        "distractor1": "Democrats and Republicans",
        "distractor2": "Federalists and Whigs",
        "distractor3": "Republicans and Whigs",
        "distractor4": "Federalists and Anti-Federalists "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republican party began as the",
        "correct_answer": "principal anti-slavery party.",
        "distractor1": "party of big business interests.",
        "distractor2": "principal pro-slavery party.",
        "distractor3": "party of states ยน rights and silver money.",
        "distractor4": "party of the New Deal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republicans had a long period as the country's dominant majority party, which ended",
        "correct_answer": "in 1932.",
        "distractor1": "in 1992.",
        "distractor2": "in 1980.",
        "distractor3": "with the Civil War.",
        "distractor4": "in 1896. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Depression of the 1930s gave rise to what is called",
        "correct_answer": "the New Deal coalition.",
        "distractor1": "econo-politics.",
        "distractor2": "party competition.",
        "distractor3": "the Era of Divided Government.",
        "distractor4": "the Republican resurgence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The New Deal coalition was responsible for electing and reelecting",
        "correct_answer": "Democrats.",
        "distractor1": "Socialist party candidates.",
        "distractor2": "Republicans.",
        "distractor3": "Whigs.",
        "distractor4": "Democratic-Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the president who brought together the original New Deal coalition in support of hiscandidacy?",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "distractor1": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "distractor2": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor3": "John F. Kennedy",
        "distractor4": "Herbert Hoover "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republican party rose to prominence in the late 1850s as the",
        "correct_answer": "Anti-slavery party.",
        "distractor1": "Free Silver party.",
        "distractor2": "Party Of The Wealthy Elite.",
        "distractor3": "Gold Standard party.",
        "distractor4": "Party of Rural Farmers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups was NOT part of the New Deal coalition?",
        "correct_answer": "wealthy New Englanders",
        "distractor1": "African Americans",
        "distractor2": "Southerners",
        "distractor3": "members of labor unions",
        "distractor4": "Catholics and Jews "
    },
    {
        "question": "Between the 1930s and the 1960s, people attracted to the Democratic party included",
        "correct_answer": "urban working classes and intellectuals.",
        "distractor1": "Protestants and Jews.",
        "distractor2": "northerners and the rich.",
        "distractor3": "farmers and rural dwellers.",
        "distractor4": "the college-educated and business owners. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The New Deal coalition made the ________ party the minority party for decades.",
        "correct_answer": "Republican",
        "distractor1": "Socialist",
        "distractor2": "Federalist",
        "distractor3": "Whig",
        "distractor4": "Democratic "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since 1968, American politics has been characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "divided government.",
        "distractor1": "the New Deal coalition.",
        "distractor2": "Republican control of both the Congress and presidency.",
        "distractor3": "Democratic control of the presidency and Republican control of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "Democratic control of both the Congress and presidency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Party dealignment is symbolized by",
        "correct_answer": "the recent pattern of divided government.",
        "distractor1": "the 1992 election of a president and Congress of the same party.",
        "distractor2": "the recent pattern of one-party control.",
        "distractor3": "a renewed commitment to America's two major political parties.",
        "distractor4": "the Republican takeover of Congress in 1994. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Loyalty to a political party has ________ over the past thirty years.",
        "correct_answer": "decreased",
        "distractor1": "increased slightly",
        "distractor2": "increased significantly",
        "distractor3": "remained about the same",
        "distractor4": "virtually disappeared "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the past thirty years, there has been a marked rise in",
        "correct_answer": "party neutrality. ",
        "distractor1": "support for both the major and minor parties.",
        "distractor2": "support for the Democratic party.",
        "distractor3": "support for both the Democratic and Republican parties.",
        "distractor4": "support for minor parties."
    },
    {
        "question": "What sort of realignment has occurred in the current party era?",
        "correct_answer": "a Southern realignment",
        "distractor1": "a rural/urban realignment",
        "distractor2": "a cultural realignment",
        "distractor3": "an entire realignment",
        "distractor4": "an age-based realignment "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1968 the Democratic party was torn apart, leaving the door to the presidency open forRepublican Richard Nixon primarily due to",
        "correct_answer": "President Johnson's Vietnam War policies.",
        "distractor1": "the failure of President Johnson's War on Poverty.",
        "distractor2": "the sudden evaporation of the New Deal coalition.",
        "distractor3": "the abandonment of the Democratic party by African Americans.",
        "distractor4": "the severity of the mid-60's recession. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about third parties in the United States is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Third parties are a rare phenomena in American history.",
        "distractor1": "Third parties often bring new issues to the political agenda.",
        "distractor2": "Third parties have brought new groups into the electorate.",
        "distractor3": "Third-party candidates almost never win office in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "Third parties have had important effects on American politics. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Ross Perot's candidacies for president in 1992 and 1996 were an example of what type ofthird-party campaign?",
        "correct_answer": "a party serving as an extension of one individual's candidacy",
        "distractor1": "a split-level party",
        "distractor2": "a party espousing an extreme ideological position",
        "distractor3": "a splinter party",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2000, Green party candidate Ralph Nader forced more attention on ________ issues anddrew away a small percentage of votes from Al Gore.",
        "correct_answer": "environmental",
        "distractor1": "budgetary",
        "distractor2": "health",
        "distractor3": "national security",
        "distractor4": "welfare "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about most third-party campaigns in American history?",
        "correct_answer": "They almost never win office.",
        "distractor1": "They occasionally succeed.",
        "distractor2": "They usually become major political parties over time.",
        "distractor3": "They have been most successful at promoting party dealignment.",
        "distractor4": "They frequently are successful. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a splinter party would be",
        "correct_answer": "George Wallace's American Independents. ",
        "distractor1": "the Prohibitionist party.",
        "distractor2": "the Poor Man's party of 1952.",
        "distractor3": "the Libertarian party.",
        "distractor4": "Ross Perot's United We Stand."
    },
    {
        "question": "Critically affecting the electoral college vote, bringing new issues to the public agenda, andventing popular discontent are important roles played by",
        "correct_answer": "third parties in a two-party system.",
        "distractor1": "intra-party factions.",
        "distractor2": "splinter groups in a multiparty system.",
        "distractor3": "the two-party system in thwarting extreme or unconventional views.",
        "distractor4": "parties based on a single issue in a multiple-issue society. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first true anti-slavery party was the",
        "correct_answer": "Free Soil party.",
        "distractor1": "Anti-slavery party.",
        "distractor2": "Populist party.",
        "distractor3": "Progressive party.",
        "distractor4": "Republican party. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In many other democracies, the system of awarding seats in the national legislature, unlike inthe United States, is one of",
        "correct_answer": "proportional representation. ",
        "distractor1": "single-member districts.",
        "distractor2": "intellectual merit alone.",
        "distractor3": "winner-take-all.",
        "distractor4": "virtual representation."
    },
    {
        "question": "A proportional representation system for electing members to a nation's legislature is morelikely to lead to a",
        "correct_answer": "greater number of political parties holding seats. ",
        "distractor1": "situation like that of the United States, with only two major parties as rivals.",
        "distractor2": "centralization and unification of political forces within the nation.",
        "distractor3": "single party holding all the seats.",
        "distractor4": "moderating of political conflict."
    },
    {
        "question": "If the United States had a multiparty system,",
        "correct_answer": "each party would have more distinct policy positions.",
        "distractor1": "third parties would come to dominate politics.",
        "distractor2": "the necessity for coalitions would be eliminated.",
        "distractor3": "people would have to pay dues to belong to a party.",
        "distractor4": "each party would move to the ideological center. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The American two-party system promotes",
        "correct_answer": "moderation in conflict and ambiguous policy positions.",
        "distractor1": "the organization of political parties around special interests.",
        "distractor2": "the weakness of centrist positions on policy issues.",
        "distractor3": "greater conflict, but clear policy choices.",
        "distractor4": "competitive elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Advocates of the ________ believe that parties should present distinct, comprehensiveprograms for governing the nation and carry them out.",
        "correct_answer": "responsible party model",
        "distractor1": "differentiation approach",
        "distractor2": "McGovern-Fraser Commission",
        "distractor3": "rational-choice theory",
        "distractor4": "party realignment "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   responsible party   model holds that parties should",
        "correct_answer": "present clear alternatives to voters.",
        "distractor1": "not use wedge issues that cause the other party's supporters to fight with each other during the campaign.",
        "distractor2": "avoid making promises.",
        "distractor3": "keep to middle-of-the-road positions.",
        "distractor4": "avoid ideological stands. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In what way do weak political parties affect the scope of government?",
        "correct_answer": "Since it is harder for them to enact legislation, it is hard for them to either expand or decrease the scope of government.",
        "distractor1": "They make it difficult for politicians to help their constituents.",
        "distractor2": "They allow presidents to expand the scope of foreign policy, while they decrease the domestic scope of government.",
        "distractor3": "Being weak, they are unable to counteract the power of government so the scope of government grows.",
        "distractor4": "They have had no real effect on the size and power of government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The weakening of party control over American politics",
        "correct_answer": "is in part due to the increasing influence of the media.",
        "distractor1": "is leading to a multiparty system in this country.",
        "distractor2": "threatens democracy.",
        "distractor3": "threatens the very existence of political parties.",
        "distractor4": "leads to fewer differences between party platforms. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In most advanced industrialized countries, election campaigns are",
        "correct_answer": "limited by law to no more than two months.",
        "distractor1": "endless affairs, sometimes lasting a year or more.",
        "distractor2": "not limited by law.",
        "distractor3": "limited by law to two weeks.",
        "distractor4": "limited by law to three months. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nomination for public office is",
        "correct_answer": "a party's selection of a candidate.",
        "distractor1": "being appointed to a government post.",
        "distractor2": "a win in key state primaries.",
        "distractor3": "a victory in the general election.",
        "distractor4": "the incumbent's selection of a candidate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The way in which candidates attempt to manipulate money, the media, and momentum toachieve the nomination is through",
        "correct_answer": "campaign strategy.",
        "distractor1": "primaries.",
        "distractor2": "charisma.",
        "distractor3": "propaganda.",
        "distractor4": "party support. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In most advanced industrialized countries, national campaigns",
        "correct_answer": "are limited by law to no more than two months.",
        "distractor1": "are even less dignified than in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "occur once every four years.",
        "distractor3": "are longer than American elections.",
        "distractor4": "occur only once every seven years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The specific goal of the presidential nomination game is to",
        "correct_answer": "win the majority of delegate votes in order to win the party nomination.",
        "distractor1": "win the majority of votes cast in presidential primaries.",
        "distractor2": "win the majority of votes cast in presidential caucuses.",
        "distractor3": "win a majority of votes in the electoral college.",
        "distractor4": "beat the other party's candidate in the general election. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Democratic and Republican candidates for president are formally nominated by the",
        "correct_answer": "national party conventions.",
        "distractor1": "presidential caucuses.",
        "distractor2": "presidential primaries.",
        "distractor3": "electoral college.",
        "distractor4": "national committees. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To be the presidential candidate of a major political party, a person must",
        "correct_answer": "win a majority of the delegates at the party's national convention.",
        "distractor1": "win a majority of party primaries in the states.",
        "distractor2": "first be nominated by the electoral college.",
        "distractor3": "win a majority of the delegates elected from state caucuses.",
        "distractor4": "have the endorsement of incumbent party leaders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first presidential caucus of the campaign season is traditionally held in",
        "correct_answer": "Iowa. ",
        "distractor1": "Delaware.",
        "distractor2": "California.",
        "distractor3": "Minnesota.",
        "distractor4": "New Hampshire."
    },
    {
        "question": "Caucuses are usually organized like",
        "correct_answer": "pyramids.",
        "distractor1": "bi-legislatures.",
        "distractor2": "the original Constitutional Convention.",
        "distractor3": "winner-take-all election systems.",
        "distractor4": "the electoral college. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The presidential primary was begun in the early twentieth century, most strongly pushed by",
        "correct_answer": "political reformers who wanted to take nominations out of the hands of party bosses.",
        "distractor1": "Democratic party leaders in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "Republican party leaders in Congress.",
        "distractor3": "party bosses who wanted to take nominations out of the hands of political reformers.",
        "distractor4": "the members of the electoral college. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Democratic National Convention in ________ led to serious reforms in the methods it usedto choose its convention delegates.",
        "correct_answer": "1968",
        "distractor1": "1936",
        "distractor2": "1952",
        "distractor3": "1984",
        "distractor4": "1992 "
    },
    {
        "question": "In states with caucuses,",
        "correct_answer": "supporters of candidates try to get elected as delegates through a pyramid of meetings.",
        "distractor1": "the state legislature selects the state's delegates to the national conventions.",
        "distractor2": "party leaders select delegates according to their own candidate preferences.",
        "distractor3": "candidates appoint supporters to serve as delegates.",
        "distractor4": "delegates are chosen through general election of a candidate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Today, a majority of the delegates to the national convention are selected through",
        "correct_answer": "presidential primaries.",
        "distractor1": "state party conventions.",
        "distractor2": "party caucuses.",
        "distractor3": "local party conventions.",
        "distractor4": "state legislatures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The McGovern-Fraser Commission",
        "correct_answer": "had a mandate to make the Democratic party conventions more democratic.",
        "distractor1": "chose presidential candidates for the Democratic party.",
        "distractor2": "investigated violations of campaign finance law in 1968.",
        "distractor3": "established the dates of presidential primaries.",
        "distractor4": "strengthened the role of the party's national committee. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The McGovern-Fraser Commission was set up to reform",
        "correct_answer": "the rules for selecting delegates to the Democratic National Convention.",
        "distractor1": "the financing of federal election campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "the rules for selecting delegates to both the Democratic and Republican National Conventions.",
        "distractor3": "party fund-raising.",
        "distractor4": "the rules for selecting delegates to the Republican National Convention. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The McGovern-Fraser Commission made the delegate selection process of the Democraticparty more democratic by",
        "correct_answer": "weakening the power of party leaders to choose convention delegates.",
        "distractor1": "giving the power of selecting delegates to party officials.",
        "distractor2": "increasing the number of delegates chosen.",
        "distractor3": "encouraging the use of presidential caucuses rather than primaries.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The opening up of the process to choose delegates to the Democratic National Convention inthe immediate aftermath of 1968 was spearheaded by",
        "correct_answer": "the McGovern-Fraser Commission.",
        "distractor1": "the Kerner Commission.",
        "distractor2": "an act of Congress.",
        "distractor3": "President Johnson.",
        "distractor4": "the Warren Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The addition of superdelegates to the Democratic national conventions was spearheaded by",
        "correct_answer": "those who felt the McGovern-Fraser Commission had opened up the delegate selection process too much.",
        "distractor1": "those who felt the Warren Commission had led to unrepresentative delegate selection.",
        "distractor2": "President Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor3": "the McGovern-Fraser Commission.",
        "distractor4": "the Warren Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Few developments have changed American politics as much as",
        "correct_answer": "the proliferation of presidential primaries.",
        "distractor1": "campaign finance reforms in the 1970s.",
        "distractor2": "the creation of PACs.",
        "distractor3": "expanded number of TV news shows.",
        "distractor4": "talk radio. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a reason for the Democratic party adding superdelegates toits national nominating conventions?",
        "correct_answer": "the insistence of the McGovern-Fraser Commission to have superdelegates play a major veto-like role",
        "distractor1": "the sense that party insiders and elected officials would be more likely to support the most electable candidate",
        "distractor2": "the need for establishing a   peer review   to the process, with input from politicians who often know the candidates best",
        "distractor3": "the feeling that earlier reforms had given too little say to the party's state and national leaders, with disastrous election results",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The dates of the different presidential primaries and delegate allocations are established by",
        "correct_answer": "state laws. ",
        "distractor1": "the national parties.",
        "distractor2": "the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "federal law.",
        "distractor4": "a joint agreement made by the major candidates in both parties, usually following a great deal of rancor."
    },
    {
        "question": "For a candidate, the most important and desirable result of the early nomination contests is",
        "correct_answer": "doing better than expected, thus winning an image as the party's frontrunner and holder of momentum.",
        "distractor1": "doing well in a state highly representative of the entire United States population.",
        "distractor2": "winning the highest number of national convention delegates.",
        "distractor3": "winning all of its electoral votes.",
        "distractor4": "winning the highest number of votes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Running for the Republican presidential nomination in 1980, George Bush, announced in theearly going that he had the   big MO  รฎโฌโa reference to the fact that",
        "correct_answer": "he had the momentum having won in Iowa.",
        "distractor1": "he had won more delegates in Missouri.",
        "distractor2": "financial contributors were heavily on his side.",
        "distractor3": "he had been endorsed by Moe Shepp, traditionally one of the Republican party's biggest campaign contributors.",
        "distractor4": "he had won more votes in New Hampshire. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2004 almost three-fourths of the Republican and Democrat delegates were chosen within________ of the New Hampshire primary.",
        "correct_answer": "six weeks",
        "distractor1": "six months",
        "distractor2": "two weeks",
        "distractor3": "two months",
        "distractor4": "four weeks "
    },
    {
        "question": "The New Hampshire primary is important because",
        "correct_answer": "it is the first primary.",
        "distractor1": "New Hampshire has a very large number of delegates.",
        "distractor2": "New Hampshire is a particularly typical state.",
        "distractor3": "it is the primary held closest to the time of the convention.",
        "distractor4": "it involves the first caucuses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The rules determining the way in which the primaries are set up and the delegates areallocated are made by",
        "correct_answer": "state legislatures and state parties. ",
        "distractor1": "the electoral college.",
        "distractor2": "the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "Congress.",
        "distractor4": "the Federal Election Commission."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the New Hampshire presidential primary is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Considerable amount of money and time is spent on politicking in New Hampshire prior to the primary.",
        "distractor2": "There is tremendous media coverage of the New Hampshire primary.",
        "distractor3": "New Hampshire holds the first presidential primary of the year.",
        "distractor4": "All the presidential candidates spend considerable time in New Hampshire prior to primary day."
    },
    {
        "question": "The state that has disproportionate power because it holds the first presidential primary eachelection year is",
        "correct_answer": "New Hampshire.",
        "distractor1": "New York.",
        "distractor2": "California.",
        "distractor3": "Iowa.",
        "distractor4": "Rhode Island. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   Big Mo   refers to",
        "correct_answer": "achieving momentum in the nomination campaign.",
        "distractor1": "the path-breaking presidential campaign of Morris   Mo   Udall.",
        "distractor2": "the overwhelming need for money in a presidential campaign.",
        "distractor3": "the importance of the Missouri primary in the presidential nomination campaign.",
        "distractor4": "the moment in which a candidate receives enough delegates to receive the nomination. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In achieving   momentum,   nothing helps a candidate more than",
        "correct_answer": "early unexpected primary and caucus victories.",
        "distractor1": "winning where a win was expected.",
        "distractor2": "a unanimous vote at the national nominating convention.",
        "distractor3": "closing the gap in the last stages of the campaign.",
        "distractor4": "strong competition. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a criticism of the current system of presidential primaries andcaucuses?",
        "correct_answer": "The media do not have enough of a role in this process.",
        "distractor1": "Prominent officeholders find it difficult to take time out from their current duties to run.",
        "distractor2": "Too much attention is paid to the early ones.",
        "distractor3": "Money plays too big a role.",
        "distractor4": "Many candidates drop out early before most states have held their primary or caucus. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Iowa and New Hampshire have been especially important in the nomination process over thepast several decades because they help candidates to",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above",
        "distractor1": "build momentum.",
        "distractor2": "generate media attention.",
        "distractor3": "generate money.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately ________ of eligible voters cast ballots in presidential primaries.",
        "correct_answer": "20 percent ",
        "distractor1": "75 percent",
        "distractor2": "65 percent",
        "distractor3": "35 percent",
        "distractor4": "50 percent"
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of the primary and caucus system point to the fact that",
        "correct_answer": "participation in primaries and caucuses is unrepresentative of the public at large.",
        "distractor1": "disproportionate attention goes to the later caucuses and primaries.",
        "distractor2": "no precedent for them is written into the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "only the best known candidates have a chance of winning the primaries and caucuses.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Voters in primaries and caucuses tend to be representative of voters at large.",
        "distractor1": "About 5 percent of registered voters typically show up for caucuses.",
        "distractor2": "About 50 percent of the population votes in the November presidential election.",
        "distractor3": "About 20 percent of the population votes in presidential primaries.",
        "distractor4": "More people vote in primaries than attend caucuses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of primaries and caucuses contend that the presidential   kingmakers   are now",
        "correct_answer": "the media.",
        "distractor1": "party bosses.",
        "distractor2": "the few who vote in the caucuses and primaries.",
        "distractor3": "interest groups.",
        "distractor4": "state party organizations. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Proponents of a national primary argue that it would do each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "lengthen the time of the campaign.",
        "distractor1": "bring directness and simplicity to the nomination process.",
        "distractor2": "no longer allow votes in one state to have more political impact than votes in another.",
        "distractor3": "concentrate media coverage and increase interest and understanding.",
        "distractor4": "increase interest in more states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of a national primary argue that",
        "correct_answer": "no candidate would receive a majority, thus a run-off election would be needed.",
        "distractor1": "the campaign would be lengthened.",
        "distractor2": "obscure candidates would receive too much of an advantage.",
        "distractor3": "the media would have little impact.",
        "distractor4": "All of these could happen. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Conventions are not as important as they once were in that",
        "correct_answer": "we know who is going to win the presidential nomination before the convention meets.",
        "distractor1": "there is less drama and fanfare.",
        "distractor2": "rousing credentials fights and keynote speeches are a thing of the past.",
        "distractor3": "they have not taken more than one ballot to nominate a president since 1952.",
        "distractor4": "they no longer adopt party platforms. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the years, television coverage of national party conventions has",
        "correct_answer": "been scaled back.",
        "distractor1": "received increasingly high Nielsen ratings.",
        "distractor2": "become more dramatic.",
        "distractor3": "shifted to local affiliate reporters focusing on their state delegations and away from the national network anchors.",
        "distractor4": "steadily increased. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One way in which conventions are more important than they once were is that they",
        "correct_answer": "develop the party's policy positions.",
        "distractor1": "place limits on political representation.",
        "distractor2": "choose the party's organizational leadership for the next four years.",
        "distractor3": "now decide during the week of the convention, and through much political bickering, who their presidential nominee will be.",
        "distractor4": "involve more money and greater numbers of people. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The party's platform is drafted",
        "correct_answer": "before the convention, by a committee whose members are chosen in rough proportion to each candidate's strength.",
        "distractor1": "after the convention, by a committee made up exclusively of supporters of the winning nominee.",
        "distractor2": "after the convention, by a committee of party members chosen in rough proportion to each candidate's strength.",
        "distractor3": "during the convention, usually in the morning hours when cameras are not rolling.",
        "distractor4": "by the party's presidential nominee in the days after the convention is over. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By custom, the vice-presidential nominee is chosen",
        "correct_answer": "on the basis of the presidential nominee's recommendation.",
        "distractor1": "through a competitive wide open roll-call vote on the final day.",
        "distractor2": "on the basis of the second largest number of delegates.",
        "distractor3": "by the electoral college.",
        "distractor4": "by the platform committee. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Providing select information and a request for money to lists of people who have supportedcandidates of similar views in the past is a frequently used political technique known as",
        "correct_answer": "direct mail.",
        "distractor1": "soft money.",
        "distractor2": "conversion.",
        "distractor3": "fundraising.",
        "distractor4": "caucusing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most effective methods of raising money for an election campaign has been the useof",
        "correct_answer": "direct mail.",
        "distractor1": "1-800 numbers.",
        "distractor2": "mass meetings.",
        "distractor3": "door-to-door solicitation.",
        "distractor4": "television advertising. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest expenditure in a campaign budget for the presidency or a statewide office todaywould almost certainly be",
        "correct_answer": "television advertising.",
        "distractor1": "travel, hotels, and food for the candidate and campaign staff.",
        "distractor2": "the salaries of the campaign manager, pollster, counsel, and other staff.",
        "distractor3": "direct mail.",
        "distractor4": "buttons, signs, car bumper stickers, billboards, and brochures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most political coverage by the media during a presidential campaign",
        "correct_answer": "deals with the campaign game: who's ahead in the polls, what candidate X's new strategy will be, and speculation.",
        "distractor1": "is the result of successful manipulation by the campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "focuses on the substance of the key issues voters care about, and how the candidates stand on them.",
        "distractor3": "is analysis of the interest groups and campaign contributors who are backing each candidate, and why they are backing them.",
        "distractor4": "deals with the candidates ยน personal character flaws and family. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the money spent on presidential campaigns these days is spent on",
        "correct_answer": "the media. ",
        "distractor1": "computer services.",
        "distractor2": "air travel, hotels, and meals.",
        "distractor3": "direct mail.",
        "distractor4": "printing."
    },
    {
        "question": "News coverage of presidential campaigns tends to emphasize",
        "correct_answer": "campaign strategies and poll results.",
        "distractor1": "the candidates ยน positions on the issues.",
        "distractor2": "the voting and performance records of the candidates in their current offices.",
        "distractor3": "fair coverage of all the candidates.",
        "distractor4": "debates between the candidates. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Media coverage of a candidate's campaign is a function of",
        "correct_answer": "both A and B",
        "distractor1": "how candidates spend their advertising budget.",
        "distractor2": "the   free   attention they get as newsmakers.",
        "distractor3": "the nature of their policy agenda",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the major functions of policy advisors in a campaign is to",
        "correct_answer": "keep the candidate informed on the issues.",
        "distractor1": "manage the campaign finances.",
        "distractor2": "plan ad campaigns.",
        "distractor3": "handle the details of candidate scheduling.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The member of a presidential campaign who helps reporters make their deadlines with storiesthat the campaign would like to see reported is the",
        "correct_answer": "press secretary.",
        "distractor1": "media liaison.",
        "distractor2": "propagandist.",
        "distractor3": "director of public relations.",
        "distractor4": "media consultant. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Election Campaign Act",
        "correct_answer": "required all candidates for federal office to disclose all contributions made to their campaigns.",
        "distractor1": "provided public financing for Senate and House races.",
        "distractor2": "required broadcasters to provide free air time to each major candidate for federal office.",
        "distractor3": "ended public financing for presidential campaigns.",
        "distractor4": "removed spending limits from presidential campaigns. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did the Federal Election Campaign Act NOT do?",
        "correct_answer": "provide public financing of House and Senate races",
        "distractor1": "require disclosure of campaign contributions by all candidates for federal offices",
        "distractor2": "provide public financing for the presidential nominees of both major parties",
        "distractor3": "limit presidential campaign spending",
        "distractor4": "provide public financing of Senate races "
    },
    {
        "question": "The group responsible for administering and enforcing the Federal Election Campaign Act isthe",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Election Commission (FEC).",
        "distractor1": "National Committee for an Effective Congress.",
        "distractor2": "Political Action Committee (PAC).",
        "distractor3": "Federal Unethical Campaign Kommisars.",
        "distractor4": "electoral college. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Federal Election Campaign Act, candidates must",
        "correct_answer": "disclose who contributed to their campaigns, and how the money was spent.",
        "distractor1": "reject any contributions of Political Action Committees that exceed $1,000.",
        "distractor2": "apply for federal funds if they are running in a presidential election.",
        "distractor3": "raise their own campaign funds.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1974 Federal Election Campaign Act",
        "correct_answer": "placed legal limits on presidential campaign spending.",
        "distractor1": "placed legal limits on total campaign contributions.",
        "distractor2": "required private rather than public financing of primaries and elections.",
        "distractor3": "prohibited disclosure of campaign fund sources.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Donating $200,000 to a political party to help its presidential nominee in somewhat indirectways is",
        "correct_answer": "illegal under the McCain-Feingold Act.",
        "distractor1": "legal, and known as soft money.",
        "distractor2": "of unclear legality and the subject of a controversial and vague Supreme Court ruling.",
        "distractor3": "legal, and known as a PAC contribution.",
        "distractor4": "illegal under the Federal Election Campaign Act (FECA). "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the provisions of the McCain-Feingold Act of 2002 was to",
        "correct_answer": "increase the limit on individual contributions from $1,000 to $2,000.",
        "distractor1": "increase the limit on individual contributions to $5,000.",
        "distractor2": "increase the amount of federal money presidential candidates can spend.",
        "distractor3": "increase the limit on   soft money   contributions.",
        "distractor4": "increase the limit on individual contributions to $10,000. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic theory says that money always finds a way to get around legal obstacles. Thus,when the soft money loophole was closed, how did money continue to find its way intopolitical campaigns?",
        "correct_answer": "through 527 Groups",
        "distractor1": "through the McCain-Feingold loophole",
        "distractor2": "through dense money",
        "distractor3": "through the garden hose loophole",
        "distractor4": "through buying bulk purchases of books to avoid limits on campaign contributions "
    },
    {
        "question": "PAC is an acronym for",
        "correct_answer": "political action committee.",
        "distractor1": "the Partisan Activities Commission.",
        "distractor2": "political access conveyance.",
        "distractor3": "power-as-cash.",
        "distractor4": "positive action campaign. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The McCain-Feingold Act of 2002 did all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "barred groups from running   issue ad   within 60 days of a general election if they refer to a federal candidate and are not funded through a PAC.",
        "distractor2": "banned soft money contributions.",
        "distractor3": "increased the amount that individuals could give to candidates form $1,000 to $2,000.",
        "distractor4": "indexed the limit on individual contributions to inflation in future years."
    },
    {
        "question": "A very important ground rule concerning the behavior of political action committees is",
        "correct_answer": "all expenditures must be meticulously accounted for to the FEC.",
        "distractor1": "they are not allowed to contribute to presidential campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "there are strict limits on the number of candidates each PAC can contribute to.",
        "distractor3": "they can only contribute to political parties or general funds, not to specific candidates.",
        "distractor4": "both A and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "Critics of the PAC system are concerned that",
        "correct_answer": "PACs may control what the electoral winners do once in office. ",
        "distractor1": "PACs are not regulated.",
        "distractor2": "they tend to support only Republican candidates.",
        "distractor3": "PACs are too weak and ineffective to contribute to a strong democracy.",
        "distractor4": "only the largest and most powerful interest groups can afford to form PACs."
    },
    {
        "question": "Defenders of PACs point out that they",
        "correct_answer": "tend to support those who agree with them in the first place.",
        "distractor1": "are limited to contributing only $1,000 per candidate.",
        "distractor2": "can potentially buy votes.",
        "distractor3": "have been very effective at enforcing campaign reform laws and reducing unethical campaign practices.",
        "distractor4": "give most of their money to challengers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most PACs give money to",
        "correct_answer": "candidates who already agree with them in the first place.",
        "distractor1": "candidates who disagree with them, but who are likely to be   bought.  ",
        "distractor2": "candidates of only one political party.",
        "distractor3": "the parties and let them distribute money among their candidates as they see fit.",
        "distractor4": "challengers trying to unseat incumbents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to political scientist Gary Jacobson's research, a Congressional incumbent whospends a tremendous amount of money to get reelected",
        "correct_answer": "is more likely to lose.",
        "distractor1": "is more likely to win.",
        "distractor2": "is likely to win by a landslide of over 70 percent of the vote.",
        "distractor3": "is likely to get a higher percentage of the vote.",
        "distractor4": "is no more or less likely to win than a candidate spending little money. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Political Action Committees (PACs) is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The influence of PACs is particularly important in presidential campaigns.",
        "distractor1": "All PAC expenditures must be meticulously accounted for to the FEC.",
        "distractor2": "PACs have proliferated in recent years.",
        "distractor3": "Candidates need PACs because high-tech campaigning is expensive.",
        "distractor4": "PACs contribute money before and after elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of PAC money in presidential campaigns is",
        "correct_answer": "less important than in Congressional campaigns.",
        "distractor1": "particularly influential.",
        "distractor2": "able to   throw   the victory in the New Hampshire primary to the candidate favored by the most PACs.",
        "distractor3": "unregulated.",
        "distractor4": "illegal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Research has shown that the cost of American election campaigns is",
        "correct_answer": "per person, about the same as a DVD movie.",
        "distractor1": "high compared to other countries.",
        "distractor2": "decreasing when the rising cost of living is taken into account.",
        "distractor3": "only about 25 cents per voter.",
        "distractor4": "a national scandal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What bothers politicians most about the rising costs of high-tech campaigning is",
        "correct_answer": "that fund-raising has come to take up so much of their precious time, distracting them from legislation.",
        "distractor1": "that so many good people can not afford to run for reelection.",
        "distractor2": "they feel like whores who will do anything for a campaign contribution.",
        "distractor3": "the increasing influence of PACs.",
        "distractor4": "the declining number of PACs that they relied on for large campaign contributions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The relationship between campaign spending and electoral success is that",
        "correct_answer": "spending more than your opponent does not assure victory.",
        "distractor1": "the candidate who spends the most is sure to win.",
        "distractor2": "the more incumbents spend, the more likely they are to be reelected.",
        "distractor3": "the amount of money spent and winning are entirely unrelated.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who opposes public financing of campaigns the most?",
        "correct_answer": "incumbents",
        "distractor1": "liberals",
        "distractor2": "conservatives",
        "distractor3": "challengers",
        "distractor4": "independents "
    },
    {
        "question": "Campaigns strengthen voter commitment to the usual party or the candidate they previouslysupported by emphasizing ________ as part of their campaign strategy.",
        "correct_answer": "reinforcement",
        "distractor1": "conversion",
        "distractor2": "activation",
        "distractor3": "persuasion",
        "distractor4": "direct mail "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following have been found to be most successfully affected by campaigns?",
        "correct_answer": "reinforcement and activation",
        "distractor1": "conversion",
        "distractor2": "reinforcement, activation, and conversion",
        "distractor3": "reinforcement and conversion",
        "distractor4": "activation and conversion "
    },
    {
        "question": "Campaigns are most effective in",
        "correct_answer": "reinforcing existing preferences toward candidates.",
        "distractor1": "getting people to contribute time and money.",
        "distractor2": "converting voters from one candidate to another.",
        "distractor3": "educating people on the issues.",
        "distractor4": "shaping how the media will portray a candidate to the public. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most people pay little attention to campaigns,",
        "correct_answer": "and have a selective perception about events and candidates.",
        "distractor1": "and are as unfamiliar with the names of incumbents, as with the names of challengers.",
        "distractor2": "and do not care about party identification of candidates.",
        "distractor3": "but are quite subject to having their minds changed by a strong campaign.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors weaken political campaigns ยน effects on voters?",
        "correct_answer": "selective perception, party identification, and incumbent name recognition",
        "distractor1": "negative advertising, party identification, and incumbent name recognition",
        "distractor2": "campaign expenditures, party identification, and incumbent name recognition",
        "distractor3": "selective mobilization, party identification, and incumbent name recognition",
        "distractor4": "selective mobilization, negative advertising and incumbent name recognition "
    },
    {
        "question": "The selective perception of most voters means that they",
        "correct_answer": "pay most attention to things they already agree with, and interpret events according to their own predispositions.",
        "distractor1": "are susceptible to having their minds changed fairly easily by effective campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "make rational choices about the purposive benefits to themselves of voting for a particular candidate.",
        "distractor3": "keep a fairly open mind regarding the candidates during the election campaign, and choose based on rational analysis.",
        "distractor4": "are skeptical of all candidates and view all campaigning as suspect. "
    },
    {
        "question": "America's party nomination system could best be described as",
        "correct_answer": "open and entrepreneurial.",
        "distractor1": "rational and bureaucratized.",
        "distractor2": "informal, but rational.",
        "distractor3": "a meritocracy.",
        "distractor4": "an apprenticeship system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of selecting America's leaders has almost no downtime before it revs up all overagain. This is referred to as",
        "correct_answer": "the permanent campaign.",
        "distractor1": "the revolving door.",
        "distractor2": "revolving elections.",
        "distractor3": "election mania.",
        "distractor4": "accountability. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Throughout American history, presidential campaigns have become",
        "correct_answer": "more and more democratic.",
        "distractor1": "dirtier and dirtier.",
        "distractor2": "shorter and shorter.",
        "distractor3": "more and more secretive.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to most other democratic systems, nominations and campaigns in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "tend to be more open.",
        "distractor1": "require less commitment of time on the part of the candidate.",
        "distractor2": "are decided more by party bosses than the general public.",
        "distractor3": "tend to be shorter.",
        "distractor4": "involve less money. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Party outsiders have ________ getting elected in the United States than in other countries.",
        "correct_answer": "a much easier time",
        "distractor1": "about the same chance of",
        "distractor2": "no chance of",
        "distractor3": "a somewhat more difficult time",
        "distractor4": "a much less likely chance of "
    },
    {
        "question": "Elections in the United States perform which of the following functions?",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above ",
        "distractor1": "make or ratify legislation",
        "distractor2": "select party nominees",
        "distractor3": "select officeholders from among party nominees",
        "distractor4": "both B and C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following functions do elections LEAST serve?",
        "correct_answer": "making and coordinating public policy",
        "distractor1": "selecting public officials",
        "distractor2": "providing regular access to political power",
        "distractor3": "providing legitimacy to the political system",
        "distractor4": "connecting citizens to government officials "
    },
    {
        "question": "California's famous Proposition 13, in which voters frustrated by a lack of action by theirlegislature forced an issue on the ballot and voted to limit the rise in property taxes, was anexample of",
        "correct_answer": "an initiative.",
        "distractor1": "a direct primary.",
        "distractor2": "an indirect primary.",
        "distractor3": "a referendum.",
        "distractor4": "a voter override. "
    },
    {
        "question": "California's Proposition 209, which intended to end affirmative action programs in the state, isan example of",
        "correct_answer": "an initiative.",
        "distractor1": "a direct primary.",
        "distractor2": "an indirect primary.",
        "distractor3": "a referendum.",
        "distractor4": "a voter override. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Daniel Smith argues that initiatives typically stem from",
        "correct_answer": "the actions of a dedicated policy entrepreneur.",
        "distractor1": "broad public demand for the policy.",
        "distractor2": "the natural emergence of policy issues.",
        "distractor3": "responsive elected officials, working in coalition.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The initiative is put on the ballot as a result of",
        "correct_answer": "a petition signed by a certain percentage of the voters in the previous election.",
        "distractor1": "the governor's order.",
        "distractor2": "a Supreme Court ruling.",
        "distractor3": "public opinion polls showing strong support for a certain measure not acted upon by the legislature.",
        "distractor4": "a special, legally constituted convention voting to place it there. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following, which is the most direct form of democracy?",
        "correct_answer": "initiative",
        "distractor1": "referendum",
        "distractor2": "direct primary",
        "distractor3": "presidential election",
        "distractor4": "recall "
    },
    {
        "question": "An election whereby voters are given the chance to approve or disapprove some legislative actor constitutional amendment is called",
        "correct_answer": "a referendum.",
        "distractor1": "an initiative petition.",
        "distractor2": "a direct primary.",
        "distractor3": "a direct election.",
        "distractor4": "a ratification election. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1800 election presidential candidates were nominated by",
        "correct_answer": "their parties ยน elected representatives in Congress.",
        "distractor1": "their parties ยน nominating convention.",
        "distractor2": "their parties ยน voters in primary elections.",
        "distractor3": "the electoral college.",
        "distractor4": "the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The election of 1800 was",
        "correct_answer": "decided by the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "decided by the direct vote of the people.",
        "distractor2": "decided by the electoral college.",
        "distractor3": "overturned by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "decided by the full Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The presidential election of 1800 was",
        "correct_answer": "the first transition of power between parties accomplished by voters ยน ballots in the history of the world.",
        "distractor1": "the first use of direct primaries in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "decided by the House of Representatives after a tie in the electoral college.",
        "distractor3": "notable for the importance of key convention speeches to swing the votes in the electoral eollege.",
        "distractor4": "influenced by media intent on forcing incumbent out of office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The presidential election of 1800 represents the first",
        "correct_answer": "peaceful transfer of power in the world between parties via the electoral process.",
        "distractor1": "use of party nominating conventions.",
        "distractor2": "time the Senate elected the president.",
        "distractor3": "use of the electoral college.",
        "distractor4": "time the voters directly elected the presidential electors. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the original constitutional system,",
        "correct_answer": "each presidential elector cast two ballots and the top vote-getter was named president and the runner-up became vice president.",
        "distractor1": "the Senate elected the president and the House of Representatives elected the vice president.",
        "distractor2": "each presidential elector cast one ballot for one of the president/vice president teams running.",
        "distractor3": "the state legislatures elected the president and vice president, with the candidate getting the second most votes becoming vice president.",
        "distractor4": "the president, once elected by the electoral college, chose the vice president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE of the presidential election of 1800?",
        "correct_answer": "It was the first peaceful transfer of power between parties via the electoral process in the history of the world.",
        "distractor1": "The candidates traveled throughout the smaller number of United States at the time to campaign for votes.",
        "distractor2": "It was a gentlemanly contest in which partisans on both sides showed respect for the opposition.",
        "distractor3": "It was carefully and objectively covered in the newspapers of the day, with logical reasoning and respect for both candidates in articles and editorials.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the electoral college vote in the election of 1800, there was a tie between",
        "correct_answer": "Thomas Jefferson and Aaron Burr.",
        "distractor1": "Thomas Jefferson and John Adams.",
        "distractor2": "John Adams and James Madison.",
        "distractor3": "John Adams and Aaron Burr.",
        "distractor4": "George Washington and Thomas Jefferson. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The issue of free silver (to increase the amount of currency in circulation) was championed inthe election of 1896 by ________, whose most famous oration was his   Cross of Gold   speech atthe Democratic national convention.",
        "correct_answer": "William Jennings Bryan",
        "distractor1": "Grover Cleveland",
        "distractor2": "William McKinley",
        "distractor3": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "distractor4": "Woodrow Wilson "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1896, who liked silver money?",
        "correct_answer": "debtors",
        "distractor1": "bankers",
        "distractor2": "exporters",
        "distractor3": "Eastern manufacturers",
        "distractor4": "coin collectors and dealers "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first peaceful transfer of power between parties via the electoral process in the history ofthe world occurred as a result of the presidential election of",
        "correct_answer": "1800.",
        "distractor1": "1796.",
        "distractor2": "1860.",
        "distractor3": "1896.",
        "distractor4": "1789. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The election of 1896 was largely fought over the issue of",
        "correct_answer": "economics.",
        "distractor1": "war.",
        "distractor2": "race relations.",
        "distractor3": "government corruption.",
        "distractor4": "the ownership of land in the west. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the election of 1896 is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The election resulted in the Democrats becoming firmly entrenched as the majority party in the Northeast and Midwest.",
        "distractor1": "The main issue in the election of 1896 was the gold standard and tariffs.",
        "distractor2": "William Jennings Bryan broke with tradition and campaigned extensively in person.",
        "distractor3": "Nearly 80 percent of the eligible electorate voted in 1896.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The winner of the presidential election of 1896 was",
        "correct_answer": "William McKinley.",
        "distractor1": "Theodore Roosevelt.",
        "distractor2": "Grover Cleveland.",
        "distractor3": "William Jennings Bryan.",
        "distractor4": "Ulysses Grant. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The election of 1896 left a legacy of a political alignment that endured for several decades,wherein",
        "correct_answer": "the Democrats won the South and West, while the Republicans won in the more populous Northeast and Midwest.",
        "distractor1": "the Democrats won the more populous Northeast and Midwest, and the Republicans won in the South and West.",
        "distractor2": "the Democrats won the Midwest and the South, while the Republicans won in the Northeast and West.",
        "distractor3": "the Democrats won in the Northeast and West, while the Republicans won in the Northeast and South.",
        "distractor4": "the Republicans swept the South, and the Democrats won in all other regions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Because Bush's lead over Gore in the initial count was less than one-tenth of one percent,Florida law mandated",
        "correct_answer": "an automatic recount.",
        "distractor1": "that the Florida state legislature vote to declare Bush the winner.",
        "distractor2": "the outcome of the election be determined by the Florida Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "the Secretary of State to certify the results.",
        "distractor4": "a thirty-day extension for absentee ballots. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In Bush v. Gore (2000), the United States Supreme Court ruled that",
        "correct_answer": "although a recount was legal, the same (or more precise) standards for evaluating ballots would have to be applied in all counties.",
        "distractor1": "the Florida Supreme Court did not have jurisdiction over the presidential election legal issues.",
        "distractor2": "the butterfly ballot was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "the time used to recount ballots could extend past December 12, when the Florida electors would meet.",
        "distractor4": "punch card ballots were illegal if not used in all counties. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to exit polls, ________ was a major reason voters selected Bush in 2004.",
        "correct_answer": "the war on terrorism",
        "distractor1": "welfare reform",
        "distractor2": "health care reform",
        "distractor3": "freedom of speech",
        "distractor4": "strategic voting "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 2004 election, John Kerry won votes among those most concerned with",
        "correct_answer": "the economy, health care, and education.",
        "distractor1": "the fairness of the tax system.",
        "distractor2": "the environment, the economy, and transportation issues.",
        "distractor3": "the environment and urban affairs.",
        "distractor4": "civil rights, the environment, and the economy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Suffrage means",
        "correct_answer": "the right to vote.",
        "distractor1": "turning out to vote.",
        "distractor2": "voting for the winner.",
        "distractor3": "voting for the loser.",
        "distractor4": "the struggle for equal rights for women. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about American elections over the past 100 years?",
        "correct_answer": "The suffrage has broadened, and the turnout has decreased.",
        "distractor1": "The suffrage has broadened, and the turnout has increased.",
        "distractor2": "The suffrage has narrowed, and the turnout has increased.",
        "distractor3": "The suffrage has narrowed, and the turnout has decreased.",
        "distractor4": "Suffrage has broadened, but there has been no change in turnout. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Suffrage refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the right to vote.",
        "distractor1": "a type of election unique to the United States.",
        "distractor2": "a voter registration system.",
        "distractor3": "voter turnout rates.",
        "distractor4": "voting procedures in the electoral college. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As the right to vote has been extended,",
        "correct_answer": "proportionately fewer of those eligible have chosen to vote.",
        "distractor1": "voter turnout has increased proportionately.",
        "distractor2": "the number of candidates running for office has increased.",
        "distractor3": "voter turnout has actually remained about the same.",
        "distractor4": "the scope of American government has shrunk. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The nearly two centuries of American electoral history has been characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "expansion of the right to vote.",
        "distractor1": "consistently close elections.",
        "distractor2": "increasing voter turnouts.",
        "distractor3": "a proliferation of presidential candidates.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The high point of voter turnout in the United States was in",
        "correct_answer": "1896.",
        "distractor1": "1932.",
        "distractor2": "1972.",
        "distractor3": "1968.",
        "distractor4": "1960. "
    },
    {
        "question": "People are more likely to vote for all of the following reasons EXCEPT if they",
        "correct_answer": "believe that some policies of one party are balanced by other policies of the other party.",
        "distractor1": "have a high sense of civic duty.",
        "distractor2": "have a high sense of political efficacy.",
        "distractor3": "are able to see policy differences that affect their interests.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Anthony Downs ยน theory of rational voting behavior predicts that people will vote if they",
        "correct_answer": "think one party will give them more policy benefits than the other.",
        "distractor1": "can afford the time and energy to do so.",
        "distractor2": "think their vote will make the difference for a particular candidate.",
        "distractor3": "identify with a particular candidate, even though they doubt that one vote can make a difference.",
        "distractor4": "feel obligated to do so. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Those largely indifferent to the results of an election, but who decide to vote anyway to showsupport for democratic government are called ________ voters.",
        "correct_answer": "civic-duty",
        "distractor1": "guilt-driven",
        "distractor2": "regime-maintenance",
        "distractor3": "patriotic disaffected",
        "distractor4": "disaffected "
    },
    {
        "question": "The greater one's sense of political efficacy, the",
        "correct_answer": "more likely one is to vote.",
        "distractor1": "less likely one is to vote.",
        "distractor2": "greater one's chance of being defeated in an election.",
        "distractor3": "less likely one is to view the election process in the United States as legitimate.",
        "distractor4": "more likely one is to see differences between the parties. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political efficacy refers to the belief that",
        "correct_answer": "ordinary people can influence the government.",
        "distractor1": "the costs of voting outweigh the benefits.",
        "distractor2": "significant policy differences exist between the parties.",
        "distractor3": "one should always support democratic government.",
        "distractor4": "government is very inefficient and needs to be streamlined. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Largely to prevent corruption associated with stuffing ballot boxes, states adopted ________around the turn of the twentieth century.",
        "correct_answer": "voter registration",
        "distractor1": "the electoral college",
        "distractor2": "primary elections",
        "distractor3": "voting machines",
        "distractor4": "the secret ballot "
    },
    {
        "question": "Voter registration was begun around the turn of the twentieth century",
        "correct_answer": "to make elections more ethical.",
        "distractor1": "to encourage voting through advance notice.",
        "distractor2": "by party bosses to discourage people from voting.",
        "distractor3": "to allow for the secret ballot.",
        "distractor4": "to discourage patronage. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A major reason cited for America's level of voter turnout compared to other industrializedcountries is",
        "correct_answer": "registration is more cumbersome in the United States.",
        "distractor1": "bad weather in certain parts of the United States on election day.",
        "distractor2": "greater interest in democracy in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "registration is more cumbersome in other nations.",
        "distractor4": "Americans ยน high sense of political efficacy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to other industrialized democracies, the United States has a ________ voter turnout.",
        "correct_answer": "much lower",
        "distractor1": "much higher",
        "distractor2": "slightly higher",
        "distractor3": "slightly lower",
        "distractor4": "rising "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countries has a lower voter turnout rate than the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Switzerland",
        "distractor1": "Australia",
        "distractor2": "Great Britain",
        "distractor3": "Italy",
        "distractor4": "France "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countries has the lowest voter turnout rate?",
        "correct_answer": "United States",
        "distractor1": "Australia",
        "distractor2": "Italy",
        "distractor3": "France",
        "distractor4": "Bulgaria "
    },
    {
        "question": "Voter turnout in the United States is much lower than in other countries in part because",
        "correct_answer": "of the unique American requirement of voter registration.",
        "distractor1": "Americans are asked to vote less often and do not sustain interest in the electoral process.",
        "distractor2": "Americans vote for fewer political offices and lack a sense of political efficacy.",
        "distractor3": "the choice offered Americans is greater than in other countries, which confuses potential voters.",
        "distractor4": "of the strident positions taken by the parties, which alienate middle-of-the-road voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Americans are expected to vote for a much narrower range of political offices than most democracies.",
        "distractor1": "Unlike the United States, the governments of most democracies take the responsibility of seeing to it that all of their eligible citizens are on the voting lists.",
        "distractor2": "American government asks citizens to vote far more often than most democracies.",
        "distractor3": "The choice offered Americans at elections is not as great as in other democracies.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these would be most likely to vote?",
        "correct_answer": "a well-educated, middle-aged government worker",
        "distractor1": "a young southerner without a high school diploma",
        "distractor2": "a well-educated senior citizen who used to work for a big corporation",
        "distractor3": "a young southern high school teacher",
        "distractor4": "a middle-aged professor at a private university "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is INCORRECT?",
        "correct_answer": "Congress requires voter registration nationwide.",
        "distractor1": "The Motor Voter Act allows eligible voters to register by checking a box on their driver's license application.",
        "distractor2": "In North Dakota, you don ยนt have to register to vote.",
        "distractor3": "In a few states, you can register to vote on election day.",
        "distractor4": "Some states let you register at supermarkets. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the states that allow voter registration at the polls on election day, voter turnout ratesare",
        "correct_answer": "higher than in other states.",
        "distractor1": "impossible to compute.",
        "distractor2": "no different than in other states.",
        "distractor3": "lower than the national average.",
        "distractor4": "declining over time and at a higher rate than in other states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately how many states allow voters to register at the polls on election day?",
        "correct_answer": "6",
        "distractor1": "14",
        "distractor2": "34",
        "distractor3": "44",
        "distractor4": "49 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The group of people with the lowest voter turnout rate is",
        "correct_answer": "young people.",
        "distractor1": "college graduates.",
        "distractor2": "women.",
        "distractor3": "senior citizens over 70.",
        "distractor4": "union members. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, the most important factor affecting voter turnout is",
        "correct_answer": "education.",
        "distractor1": "gender.",
        "distractor2": "ideology.",
        "distractor3": "race.",
        "distractor4": "geography. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Highly educated individuals are more likely to vote because",
        "correct_answer": "they see more policy differences between candidates.",
        "distractor1": "they are smarter.",
        "distractor2": "they have a lower sense of political efficacy.",
        "distractor3": "most of them are white males.",
        "distractor4": "they have more influence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about voter participation is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Men are more likely to vote than women.",
        "distractor1": "As people age, their likelihood of voting increases.",
        "distractor2": "Minority groups with high levels of income and education have a higher turnout rate than whites with comparable status.",
        "distractor3": "Individuals who have lived at the same address longer are more likely to vote than those who have moved.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following characteristics would make one more likely to vote in an election?",
        "correct_answer": "having a college degree",
        "distractor1": "being a young adult",
        "distractor2": "having a low income",
        "distractor3": "being a college student",
        "distractor4": "bring a welfare recipient "
    },
    {
        "question": "The mandate theory of elections is most often cited as the proper way to view elections by",
        "correct_answer": "the winning candidate.",
        "distractor1": "the defeated candidate.",
        "distractor2": "political scientists.",
        "distractor3": "everybody.",
        "distractor4": "the media. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The mandate theory of elections is the idea that",
        "correct_answer": "the election winner has authorization from the voters to carry out his or her promised policies.",
        "distractor1": "a candidate must get at least sixty percent of the vote to win.",
        "distractor2": "a candidate must get a majority of the votes cast (fifty percent plus one) in order to take office.",
        "distractor3": "in order to improve turnout rates in the United States, voting must be made a legal requirement of all citizens, with the failure to vote resulting in a small fine.",
        "distractor4": "a candidate must get at least seventy-five percent of the vote to win. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ are crucial for many voters because they provide a regular perspective throughwhich voters can view the political world.",
        "correct_answer": "Party identifications",
        "distractor1": "Civic duties",
        "distractor2": "Direct primary elections",
        "distractor3": "Initiative petitions",
        "distractor4": "Party platforms "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political scientists tend to focus on each of the following major elements of voters ยน decisionsEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "voters ยน ideology and world view.",
        "distractor1": "voters ยน party identification.",
        "distractor2": "voters ยน evaluation of the candidates.",
        "distractor3": "the match between voters ยน policy positions and those of the candidates and parties.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the least important dimension of a candidate's image?",
        "correct_answer": "intelligence",
        "distractor1": "integrity",
        "distractor2": "reliability",
        "distractor3": "competence",
        "distractor4": "experience "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ occurs when people base their choices in an election on their own issue preferences.",
        "correct_answer": "Policy voting",
        "distractor1": "Civic duty",
        "distractor2": "Suffrage",
        "distractor3": "Retrospective voting",
        "distractor4": "Agenda setting "
    },
    {
        "question": "A voter supporting a candidate based specifically on comparing the candidate's stances on theissues of abortion rights, health care, and government aid to education to the voter's ownpreferences on such issues is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "policy voting.",
        "distractor1": "retrospective voting.",
        "distractor2": "civic duty.",
        "distractor3": "initiative.",
        "distractor4": "agenda setting. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Research has found that those most likely to view the candidates in terms of their personalattributes are",
        "correct_answer": "college-educated voters.",
        "distractor1": "minority voters.",
        "distractor2": "low-income voters.",
        "distractor3": "women voters.",
        "distractor4": "non-voters. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the electoral college?",
        "correct_answer": "On very rare occasions, an elector has voted differently from the popular vote winner of his state.",
        "distractor1": "It is scheduled to be phased out in 2006, though some still argue its usefulness and want to rescind the phase-out.",
        "distractor2": "It is used in nearly half of the democratic nations around the world.",
        "distractor3": "An elector has never voted differently from the popular vote winner of his state.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "As provided in the Constitution, how are electoral votes allocated for each state?",
        "correct_answer": "Each state has as many electoral votes as it has members in the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "Each state has as many electoral votes as it has members in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor2": "Each state has as many electoral votes as it has members in both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "Each state is proportioned to their population, with all states having at least one vote.",
        "distractor4": "Each state casts two electoral votes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the electoral college is FALSE? w",
        "correct_answer": "Every state has a winner-take-all system where electors vote as a bloc for the winner.",
        "distractor1": "Each state has as many electoral votes as it has United States senators and representatives.",
        "distractor2": "Electors meet in their states in December and mail their votes to the vice president.",
        "distractor3": "If no candidate receives an electoral majority, then the election is thrown into the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor4": "Some states have a winner take all system where electors vote as a bloc for the winner. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If a presidential candidate does not receive a majority of electoral college votes, then thepresident is chosen",
        "correct_answer": "by the House with one vote for each state.",
        "distractor1": "by popular vote.",
        "distractor2": "by the Justices of the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "by the Senate with two votes for each state.",
        "distractor4": "by majority vote of the entire Congress in a joint session. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Research on voting behavior has shown that",
        "correct_answer": "policy voting has become somewhat easier than in the past.",
        "distractor1": "a candidate's image is not as important today as it was in the past.",
        "distractor2": "Americans tend to identify with the underdog.",
        "distractor3": "party identification has become more important in voting decisions.",
        "distractor4": "policy voting has become harder than in the past. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The greater the policy differences between the candidates,",
        "correct_answer": "the more likely voters will be able to steer government policies by their choices.",
        "distractor1": "the closer the election.",
        "distractor2": "the lower the turnout in the general election.",
        "distractor3": "the more likely voters will make choices based on personality traits.",
        "distractor4": "the higher the voter turnout in the election. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In ________, incumbents who provide desired results are rewarded; those who fail to do so arepunished.",
        "correct_answer": "retrospective voting",
        "distractor1": "indirect primaries",
        "distractor2": "initiatives",
        "distractor3": "referendums",
        "distractor4": "incentive voting "
    },
    {
        "question": "If engaged in retrospective voting, an individual would ask:",
        "correct_answer": "What have you done for me lately?",
        "distractor1": "Who will do more for me next year?",
        "distractor2": "Who is the more attractive candidate?",
        "distractor3": "Why should I vote at all?",
        "distractor4": "Who will be lowering taxes? "
    },
    {
        "question": "When President Herbert Hoover and the Republicans were crushed in the election of 1932,voters were responding to the severity of the Great Depression under Hoover's presidency by",
        "correct_answer": "retrospective voting.",
        "distractor1": "indirect primary voting.",
        "distractor2": "direct primary voting.",
        "distractor3": "initiative.",
        "distractor4": "irrational choice voting. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Elections have a tendency to expand the scope of government because",
        "correct_answer": "voters like to feel that they are sending a message to government to accomplish something.",
        "distractor1": "so many people become involved in the process.",
        "distractor2": "so much money is involved in campaigns.",
        "distractor3": "elections open opportunities for more government employment.",
        "distractor4": "because they are so expensive to conduct. "
    },
    {
        "question": "While the threat of electoral punishment constrains policymakers, it also helps to increasegeneralized support for",
        "correct_answer": "government and its powers.",
        "distractor1": "the private sector.",
        "distractor2": "individualistic, rather than, collective policy solutions.",
        "distractor3": "incumbents who have done a good job.",
        "distractor4": "unelected government officials in the bureaucracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to James Madison in Federalist Paper No. 1, the way to prevent any one group fromhaving too much power is to",
        "correct_answer": "increase the scope and number of groups.",
        "distractor1": "eliminate most groups.",
        "distractor2": "strictly regulate them.",
        "distractor3": "make them unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the 1960s, the number of interest groups has",
        "correct_answer": "risen rapidly.",
        "distractor1": "remained constant.",
        "distractor2": "declined slightly.",
        "distractor3": "declined sharply.",
        "distractor4": "fluctuated up and down as new issues developed and others faded away. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The right of interest groups to organize is",
        "correct_answer": "protected by the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor1": "protected by the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "protected by the Federal Election Campaign Act.",
        "distractor3": "protected by state laws.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT typical of American interest groups?",
        "correct_answer": "They run their own slate of candidates for office in many parts of the country.",
        "distractor1": "They frequently look to the bureaucracy or the judicial process to achieve their policy goals.",
        "distractor2": "Most have a handful of key policies to push, and are policy experts in those areas.",
        "distractor3": "Unlike political parties, they are not faced with the constraint of trying to appeal to everyone.",
        "distractor4": "They mostly represent diffuse, non-economic interests. "
    },
    {
        "question": "American political parties differ from interest groups in that parties",
        "correct_answer": "are policy generalists.",
        "distractor1": "are policy specialists.",
        "distractor2": "are policy-driven.",
        "distractor3": "do not take positions on policy issues.",
        "distractor4": "have a narrower scope than interest groups. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the main differences between American political parties and interest groups is that",
        "correct_answer": "political parties run candidates for office.",
        "distractor1": "interest groups are concerned with more issues.",
        "distractor2": "interest groups concentrate on only one policy arena.",
        "distractor3": "interest groups limit their membership.",
        "distractor4": "political parties are policy specialists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An interest group is more likely to form its own political party where",
        "correct_answer": "voters choose their legislators using proportional representation.",
        "distractor1": "voters choose their legislators in single-member districts.",
        "distractor2": "voters choose their legislators in dual-member districts.",
        "distractor3": "the government has a bicameral legislature.",
        "distractor4": "there is a strong two-party system, and the major parties ignore their demands. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to ________ theorists, interest groups compete and counterbalance one another inthe political marketplace.",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist",
        "distractor1": "elitist",
        "distractor2": "hyperelitist",
        "distractor3": "hyperpluralist",
        "distractor4": "free market "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Green parties in Europe have never been able to win enough votes to enter the national legislature.",
        "distractor1": "With proportional representation systems, all it takes is between one and five percent of the vote for a party to win seats in the national legislature.",
        "distractor2": "In many Scandinavian countries, farmers ยน parties have long been in existence.",
        "distractor3": "Many new interest groups in Europe have formed parties on the basis of shared values.",
        "distractor4": "Parties are more like interest groups in Europe than in the U.S. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The successes of civil rights and women's rights groups in redirecting the course of publicpolicy, once they were organized, is pointed to as evidence to support the ________ theory thatAmerican politics is open and not a problem.",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist",
        "distractor1": "hyperpluralist",
        "distractor2": "elite",
        "distractor3": "hyperelitist",
        "distractor4": "free market "
    },
    {
        "question": "The group theory of politics offered by pluralist theorists argues all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "groups are all of equal strength.",
        "distractor1": "groups provide a key link between people and government.",
        "distractor2": "no one group is likely to become too dominant.",
        "distractor3": "groups usually play by the rules of the game.",
        "distractor4": "different groups win at different times. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The idea that just a few groups have all the power is associated with",
        "correct_answer": "elite theory.",
        "distractor1": "pluralist theory.",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor3": "democratic theory.",
        "distractor4": "syndicalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The idea that interest group activity brings representation to all is associated with",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist theory.",
        "distractor1": "elite theory.",
        "distractor2": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor3": "democratic theory.",
        "distractor4": "republicanism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following theories offers the most positive interpretation of the effect of interestgroups on American democracy?",
        "correct_answer": "pluralist",
        "distractor1": "hyperpluralist",
        "distractor2": "elite",
        "distractor3": "hyperelitist",
        "distractor4": "free market "
    },
    {
        "question": "Pluralists argue that lobbying",
        "correct_answer": "is open to all and is therefore not to be regarded as a problem.",
        "distractor1": "is dominated by wealthy corporations and the wealthiest individuals and is a danger to the democratic system.",
        "distractor2": "by so many interest groups who get what they want indicates that the relation between groups and government has grown too cozy.",
        "distractor3": "must be suspended until tighter regulations can be put into place to protect the public interest.",
        "distractor4": "has no effect on policymaking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ theorists are impressed by how insignificant most organized interest groups are.",
        "correct_answer": "Elitist",
        "distractor1": "Pluralist",
        "distractor2": "Hyperpluralist",
        "distractor3": "Pluralist and hyperpluralist",
        "distractor4": "Deconstruction "
    },
    {
        "question": "Elite theorists emphasize the power of",
        "correct_answer": "business leaders.",
        "distractor1": "subgovernments.",
        "distractor2": "congressional staff members.",
        "distractor3": "public interest lobbies.",
        "distractor4": "presidents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Interest group liberalism is promoted by",
        "correct_answer": "subgovernments.",
        "distractor1": "ideologically liberal interest groups and not conservative groups.",
        "distractor2": "one group winning and another losing in the competition for government action or funding.",
        "distractor3": "hyperpluralists.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The criticism that government refuses to make tough choices between X or Y, insteadpretending there is no need to choose and trying to favor both is most often made by ________theorists.",
        "correct_answer": "hyperpluralist",
        "distractor1": "pluralist",
        "distractor2": "elitist",
        "distractor3": "hyperelitist",
        "distractor4": "rational choice "
    },
    {
        "question": "The idea that too many groups are getting too much of what they want is associated with",
        "correct_answer": "hyperpluralist theory.",
        "distractor1": "elite theory.",
        "distractor2": "pluralist theory.",
        "distractor3": "democratic theory.",
        "distractor4": "proliferation theory. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Subgovernments are composed of key interest group leaders interested in policy X, thegovernment agency in charge of administering policy X, and the ________ handling policy X.",
        "correct_answer": "congressional committees and subcommittees",
        "distractor1": "federal courts",
        "distractor2": "public relations officers",
        "distractor3": "political candidates",
        "distractor4": "local governments "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the major elements of the subgovernment system at thenational level?",
        "correct_answer": "federal court",
        "distractor1": "interest group",
        "distractor2": "congressional committee",
        "distractor3": "federal agency",
        "distractor4": "bureaucrats "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ideas is NOT associated with hyperpluralism?",
        "correct_answer": "Political power is highly concentrated.",
        "distractor1": "Groups have become too powerful in the political process.",
        "distractor2": "Interest group liberalism is aggravated by numerous subgovernments.",
        "distractor3": "Trying to please every group results in contradictory and confusing policy.",
        "distractor4": "The dominance of an economic elite. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A(n) ________ group is composed of all people who might be group members because theyshare some common interest.",
        "correct_answer": "potential",
        "distractor1": "interest",
        "distractor2": "actual",
        "distractor3": "single-issue",
        "distractor4": "latent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The free-rider problem refers to",
        "correct_answer": "potential members of a group failing to join the actual group, as they know they will receive the same benefits whether they are active members or not.",
        "distractor1": "unrelated amendments being added to a piece of legislation in order to bypass usual procedures.",
        "distractor2": "legislators who face no election opponents, and thus are automatically reelected.",
        "distractor3": "mass transit scofflaws who endanger government aid to subways, buses, and commuter trains by not being officially counted.",
        "distractor4": "welfare fraud and the costs it imposes on government and taxpayers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Part of Olson's Law of Large Groups is the argument that",
        "correct_answer": "the larger the potential group, the less likely potential members are to contribute.",
        "distractor1": "the larger the potential group, the more likely potential members are to contribute.",
        "distractor2": "potential group size does not have any measurable affect on the willingness of potential members to contribute.",
        "distractor3": "an actual group and a potential group are virtually the same when it comes to effectiveness.",
        "distractor4": "the smaller the group the less likely the potential members are to contribute. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Olson's Law of Large Groups,",
        "correct_answer": "the larger the group, the further it will fall short of providing an optimal amount of a collective good.",
        "distractor1": "the smaller the group, the further it will fall short of providing an optimal amount of a collective good.",
        "distractor2": "the more levels of authority within a group, the more faith its members will have in it.",
        "distractor3": "the more levels of authority within a group, the less faith its members will have in it.",
        "distractor4": "the larger the group, the more likely it is to win. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ helps to explain why public interest lobbies have relatively small proportions ofactual members.",
        "correct_answer": "The free-rider problem",
        "distractor1": "Special interest liberalism",
        "distractor2": "The rise of political action committees",
        "distractor3": "Tougher regulation of all lobbyists",
        "distractor4": "Olson's Law of Large Groups "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Olson's Law of Large Groups,",
        "correct_answer": "the smaller the group, the more effective it will be.",
        "distractor1": "the larger the group, the more effective it will be.",
        "distractor2": "the size of a group does not determine its effectiveness, the leadership structure is the key.",
        "distractor3": "all groups have a life cycle of birth, growth, maintenance, and decline, although many never decline completely.",
        "distractor4": "large groups are more democratic. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Consumer organizations suffer from",
        "correct_answer": "Olson's Law of Large Groups.",
        "distractor1": "amicus curiae briefs.",
        "distractor2": "class action suits.",
        "distractor3": "right-to-work laws.",
        "distractor4": "hyperpluralism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The biggest obstacle to the effectiveness of large groups is the",
        "correct_answer": "problem of raising funds and attracting government support.",
        "distractor1": "difficulty of finding effective leadership.",
        "distractor2": "formation of counter-groups to oppose them.",
        "distractor3": "discrepancy between potential and actual membership.",
        "distractor4": "government regulations on lobbying activities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All people who might be group members because they share some common interest make up",
        "correct_answer": "a potential group.",
        "distractor1": "an actual group.",
        "distractor2": "a collective group.",
        "distractor3": "an interest group.",
        "distractor4": "a probable group. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups has the largest potential membership?",
        "correct_answer": "National Organization for Women",
        "distractor1": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People",
        "distractor2": "American Medical Association",
        "distractor3": "Air Transport Association of America",
        "distractor4": "American Political Science Association "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following groups claims the smallest share of its potential members?",
        "correct_answer": "National Consumers League",
        "distractor1": "United States Savings and Loan League",
        "distractor2": "Tobacco Institute",
        "distractor3": "Air Transport Association",
        "distractor4": "American Medical Association "
    },
    {
        "question": "A   collective good   refers to",
        "correct_answer": "something of value that benefits both the actual and potential members of a group.",
        "distractor1": "goods and services that are publicly owned.",
        "distractor2": "benefits that accrue to the group that sought them.",
        "distractor3": "a public policy that is in the public interest.",
        "distractor4": "goods and services collected for the needy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a collective good is",
        "correct_answer": "clean air.",
        "distractor1": "food.",
        "distractor2": "employment.",
        "distractor3": "housing.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The free-rider problem refers to the difficulty of",
        "correct_answer": "groups in organizing all their potential members.",
        "distractor1": "small groups in raising enough money to influence policy.",
        "distractor2": "actual groups in collecting dues from members.",
        "distractor3": "potential groups in receiving their share in collective goods.",
        "distractor4": "all taxpayers having to pay for public services and payments that go only to the poor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Mancur Olson, small interest groups generally are ________ compared to allother groups.",
        "correct_answer": "less focused",
        "distractor1": "insignificant",
        "distractor2": "incoherent",
        "distractor3": "more effective",
        "distractor4": "more democratic "
    },
    {
        "question": "An advantage of single-issue groups is their",
        "correct_answer": "intensity.",
        "distractor1": "financial resources.",
        "distractor2": "pool of potential members.",
        "distractor3": "pool of actual members.",
        "distractor4": "diversity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A single-issue group is one that is all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "organizes on the national level only.",
        "distractor1": "focused on narrow interest.",
        "distractor2": "unable to compromise.",
        "distractor3": "single-mindedly in pursuing its goal.",
        "distractor4": "intensely committed to a policy goal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Single-issue groups",
        "correct_answer": "include members with narrow, uncompromising interests.",
        "distractor1": "have had little effect on the outcomes of elections.",
        "distractor2": "mainly focus on the issue of abortion.",
        "distractor3": "are not taken seriously because they lack a large constituency.",
        "distractor4": "tend to focus on their specific economic interest rather than on collective social issues. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Single-issue group politics has been especially emotional over the issue of",
        "correct_answer": "abortion.",
        "distractor1": "consumerism.",
        "distractor2": "equality.",
        "distractor3": "foreign policy.",
        "distractor4": "affirmative action. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the major inducements of the American interest group system is that it",
        "correct_answer": "is biased toward the wealthy.",
        "distractor1": "provides too much representation.",
        "distractor2": "distracts government officials.",
        "distractor3": "stifles the expression of new interests.",
        "distractor4": "is dominated by single-issue groups. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By 2000, the number of groups listed in the Encyclopedia of Associations was over",
        "correct_answer": "20,000.",
        "distractor1": "5,000.",
        "distractor2": "1,000.",
        "distractor3": "10,000.",
        "distractor4": "50,000. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about interest groups is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The growth rate of interest groups has slowed in recent years.",
        "distractor1": "The majority of groups now have their headquarters in Washington, D.C.",
        "distractor2": "There are an enormous number of highly specialized and seemingly trivial groups.",
        "distractor3": "Almost every group has a staff and publications.",
        "distractor4": "Groups are more diverse today than in past decades. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Technological improvements in communication have caused interest groups to",
        "correct_answer": "sharply increase in number.",
        "distractor1": "consolidate.",
        "distractor2": "sharply decline in number.",
        "distractor3": "move out of Washington, D.C.",
        "distractor4": "form broad coalitions to expand their clout. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is a communication by someone other than a citizen acting on his or her own behalf,directed to a government decision maker, particularly in the legislative and executive branch,with the hope of influencing his or her decision.",
        "correct_answer": "Lobbying",
        "distractor1": "Electioneering",
        "distractor2": "An amicus curiae brief",
        "distractor3": "Litigation",
        "distractor4": "Campaigning "
    },
    {
        "question": "Three basic strategies employed by interest groups are all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "implementation.",
        "distractor1": "lobbying.",
        "distractor2": "electioneering.",
        "distractor3": "litigation.",
        "distractor4": "going public. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the basic interest group strategies in America?",
        "correct_answer": "running candidates for office",
        "distractor1": "lobbying",
        "distractor2": "litigation",
        "distractor3": "electioneering",
        "distractor4": "implementation "
    },
    {
        "question": "A   communication by someone other than a citizen acting on his or her own behalf, directed toa governmental decision maker with the hope of influencing his or her decision   is a definitionof",
        "correct_answer": "lobbying.",
        "distractor1": "campaigning.",
        "distractor2": "electioneering.",
        "distractor3": "litigation.",
        "distractor4": "a policy output. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a way in which a lobbyist can help a member of Congress?",
        "correct_answer": "introducing legislation in Congress",
        "distractor1": "obtaining group support for the politician's reelection",
        "distractor2": "providing valuable information on specialized policy areas",
        "distractor3": "helping with political strategy",
        "distractor4": "assisting with the cost of traveling between their home district and Washington, D.C. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, one of the most common function of lobbyists is to",
        "correct_answer": "provide information and ideas to members of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "recruit former officeholders to help with public relations.",
        "distractor2": "convert members of Congress to the point of view the lobbyists represent.",
        "distractor3": "actually introduce new legislation.",
        "distractor4": "raise funds for preferred political candidates. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The text identifies two types of lobbyists,",
        "correct_answer": "full-time employees and consultants.",
        "distractor1": "policy experts and legal specialists.",
        "distractor2": "attorneys and non-attorneys.",
        "distractor3": "those based in Washington, D.C., and those based elsewhere.",
        "distractor4": "  old school   and   modern style   lobbyists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Many interest groups involve themselves in ________ to help get those they consider to be theright people into office or to keep them there.",
        "correct_answer": "electioneering",
        "distractor1": "lobbying",
        "distractor2": "litigation",
        "distractor3": "policymaking",
        "distractor4": "recruitment "
    },
    {
        "question": "Lobbyists provide members of Congress all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "None of the above; lobbyists provide all of the above to members of Congress. ",
        "distractor1": "help with accomplishing their legislative goals.",
        "distractor2": "information.",
        "distractor3": "campaign strategy and organizational help.",
        "distractor4": "ideas and innovations."
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, the least effective activity of lobbyists in Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "converting members of Congress to the lobbyists ยน positions.",
        "distractor1": "contributing to campaigns.",
        "distractor2": "providing information.",
        "distractor3": "activating members of Congress to vote on legislation.",
        "distractor4": "both A and B "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, lobbying works best",
        "correct_answer": "on people already committed to the lobbyist's policy position.",
        "distractor1": "with people who are undecided about a policy.",
        "distractor2": "when large amounts of money are involved.",
        "distractor3": "when the lobbyist uses pressure tactics.",
        "distractor4": "when the lobbyist starts crying and pleading. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political action committee (PAC) money goes overwhelmingly to",
        "correct_answer": "incumbents.",
        "distractor1": "Independents.",
        "distractor2": "challengers.",
        "distractor3": "Democrats.",
        "distractor4": "Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Political Action Committees are primarily a means used by interest groups for",
        "correct_answer": "electioneering.",
        "distractor1": "lobbying.",
        "distractor2": "litigation.",
        "distractor3": "policymaking.",
        "distractor4": "political action. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Interest groups seeking to exert influence on the electoral process can honestly and openlyfunnel money into the campaign coffers of their supporters through",
        "correct_answer": "Political Action Committees.",
        "distractor1": "lobbying.",
        "distractor2": "electioneering.",
        "distractor3": "subgovernments.",
        "distractor4": "electronic banking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most PAC money goes overwhelmingly to incumbents because incumbents",
        "correct_answer": "are the most likely to be able to return the investment.",
        "distractor1": "need more money due to the restraints of being in office.",
        "distractor2": "have already been   bought off   by interest groups.",
        "distractor3": "have already become friends and supporters of lobbyists.",
        "distractor4": "have the need for large amounts of money to maintain themselves in power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about Political Action Committees?",
        "correct_answer": "Most PAC money goes to challengers rather than incumbents.",
        "distractor1": "There are far more PACs now than there were in 1974.",
        "distractor2": "Some PACs contribute to both challenger and incumbent, playing it safe.",
        "distractor3": "Only a handful of candidates have completely resisted the lure of PAC money.",
        "distractor4": "PACs contribute before and after elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ are written arguments submitted to the courts in support of one side of a case.",
        "correct_answer": "Amicus curiae briefs",
        "distractor1": "Class action lawsuits",
        "distractor2": "Litigations",
        "distractor3": "Public interest lobbies",
        "distractor4": "Opening arguments "
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight attendants won a(n) ________ against the airline industry's regulation that allstewardesses had to be unmarried.",
        "correct_answer": "class action lawsuit",
        "distractor1": "amicus curiae brief",
        "distractor2": "writ of habeas corpus",
        "distractor3": "bill of attainder",
        "distractor4": "administrative appeal "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about interest groups going public is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The public relations of most groups tend to be characterized by hard sell and bias.",
        "distractor1": "Interest groups carefully cultivate their public images.",
        "distractor2": "Interest groups market not only their stand on issues but their reputations as well.",
        "distractor3": "More and more organizations have launched expensive public relations efforts.",
        "distractor4": "A and C only "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "In the American economy, government directly determines wages, prices, and profits.",
        "distractor1": "Public policy in America has economic effects through regulations, tax advantages, subsidies and contracts, and international trade.",
        "distractor2": "Even a minor change in government regulatory policy can cost industries a great deal or bring increased profits.",
        "distractor3": "How the tax code is written determines whether people and producers pay a lot or a little of their incomes to the government.",
        "distractor4": "B and D only "
    },
    {
        "question": "Economic groups",
        "correct_answer": "are those groups interested in wages, prices, and profits.",
        "distractor1": "are those which require individuals to pay dues to be members.",
        "distractor2": "consist only of corporations, rather than individuals, as members.",
        "distractor3": "lobby on behalf of all consumers.",
        "distractor4": "are those groups that provide information to Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Right-to-work laws are most strongly supported by",
        "correct_answer": "business groups.",
        "distractor1": "unemployed citizens.",
        "distractor2": "union officials.",
        "distractor3": "the feminist and civil rights movements.",
        "distractor4": "illegal immigrants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The union shop",
        "correct_answer": "requires that all employees in a unionized business join the union.",
        "distractor1": "serves as the headquarters of an organized labor group.",
        "distractor2": "sells only goods made by laborers affiliated with a union.",
        "distractor3": "is a retail store whose employees are unionized.",
        "distractor4": "both B and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "Right-to-work laws ________ the union shop.",
        "correct_answer": "outlaw",
        "distractor1": "take a neutral stance toward",
        "distractor2": "require",
        "distractor3": "legalize",
        "distractor4": "regulate "
    },
    {
        "question": "Business PACs",
        "correct_answer": "have increased more dramatically than any other category of PACs.",
        "distractor1": "have so far been associated only with multinational corporations.",
        "distractor2": "are the most visible of Washington lobbies.",
        "distractor3": "have not been as effective as labor and consumer PACs.",
        "distractor4": "contribute more to Democrats than to Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Environmental groups",
        "correct_answer": "grew dramatically after the first Earth Day in 1970.",
        "distractor1": "are an example of an economic interest group.",
        "distractor2": "support nuclear power as a clean alternative to coal mining.",
        "distractor3": "have had very little influence on Congress and state legislatures.",
        "distractor4": "tend to avoid energy issues, while concentrating on the preservation of wilderness. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the reasons that   business   does not always get what it wants is",
        "correct_answer": "business groups often have different interests and want different things.",
        "distractor1": "it has limited resources to spend on influencing government policy.",
        "distractor2": "it has often used ineffective lobbying techniques.",
        "distractor3": "it is a relatively   weak   cluster of interest groups.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first ________ in April 1970 helped to spur on a number of environmental groups.",
        "correct_answer": "Earth Day",
        "distractor1": "smog alert",
        "distractor2": "serious oil spill",
        "distractor3": "nuclear power plant accident",
        "distractor4": "nuclear plant explosion "
    },
    {
        "question": "Public interest lobbies are those organizations that",
        "correct_answer": "seek a collective good, the achievement of which will not selectively and materially benefit members or activists.",
        "distractor1": "emphasize equal rights and equality of opportunity in America.",
        "distractor2": "eschew the subgovernment system and operate within view of the public, often through town meetings.",
        "distractor3": "have large memberships, usually a million or more.",
        "distractor4": "focus exclusively on public expenditures directed toward Social Security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Environmental groups have been most successful at",
        "correct_answer": "thwarting the expansion of the nuclear power industry.",
        "distractor1": "stopping strip mining.",
        "distractor2": "halting the trans-Alaskan pipeline.",
        "distractor3": "stopping the development of commercial supersonic aircraft.",
        "distractor4": "protecting the reefer toad and other endangered species. "
    },
    {
        "question": "That successful lobbying efforts by consumer groups benefits all consumers, and not justgroup members, is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "a free-rider problem.",
        "distractor1": "interest group liberalism.",
        "distractor2": "electioneering.",
        "distractor3": "lobbying.",
        "distractor4": "Olson's Law of Large Groups. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Organizations seeking a collective good that may not benefit them directly are called",
        "correct_answer": "public interest lobbies.",
        "distractor1": "commodity associations.",
        "distractor2": "protest groups.",
        "distractor3": "single-issue groups.",
        "distractor4": "altruistic lobbies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the oldest and largest of the African -American groups which have fought forequality at the polls, in housing, on the job, in education, and in all other facets of Americanlife.",
        "correct_answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People",
        "distractor1": "Urban League",
        "distractor2": "Congress of Racial Equality",
        "distractor3": "Rainbow Coalition",
        "distractor4": "National African-American Organization "
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to fighting segregation and discrimination, civil rights interest groups have alsofocused on",
        "correct_answer": "broader economic problems.",
        "distractor1": "the environment.",
        "distractor2": "transportation.",
        "distractor3": "housing quality.",
        "distractor4": "gender equality. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ movement was spurred by a single person: Ralph Nader.",
        "correct_answer": "consumer",
        "distractor1": "American labor",
        "distractor2": "modern civil rights movement",
        "distractor3": "anti-Vietnam War",
        "distractor4": "gay rights "
    },
    {
        "question": "Common Cause is an example of",
        "correct_answer": "a public interest lobby.",
        "distractor1": "a subgovernment.",
        "distractor2": "interest group liberalism.",
        "distractor3": "a single-issue group.",
        "distractor4": "a for-profit lobby. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a public interest group is",
        "correct_answer": "Common Cause.",
        "distractor1": "American Medical Association.",
        "distractor2": "National Organization for Women.",
        "distractor3": "National Association of Manufacturers.",
        "distractor4": "National Rifle Association "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Robert Salisbury, the increase in lobbying activity has resulted in",
        "correct_answer": "less clout overall for interest groups.",
        "distractor1": "greater clout for business and industry groups.",
        "distractor2": "less democracy.",
        "distractor3": "government by minority interests.",
        "distractor4": "elitist policymaking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The growth of both interest groups and the scope of government over the past several decadesrepresents",
        "correct_answer": "both A and B",
        "distractor1": "the former increasing the latter.",
        "distractor2": "the latter increasing the former.",
        "distractor3": "the latter decreasing the former.",
        "distractor4": "Neither A nor B; there is no relationship between the two. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The foremost attraction for the job of serving in Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "the power to make key public policy decisions.",
        "distractor1": "a salary four times the income of the typical American family.",
        "distractor2": "generous retirement benefits.",
        "distractor3": "travel benefits.",
        "distractor4": "employment opportunities after leaving office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the perquisites which go with the job of being a memberof Congress?",
        "correct_answer": "subsidized housing in the Virginia or Maryland suburbs of D.C.",
        "distractor1": "a salary of over $150,000",
        "distractor2": "free use of the mails to communicate with constituents",
        "distractor3": "free office space in Washington, D.C., and in the constituency from which elected",
        "distractor4": "a budget to support office staff "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ privileges refer to the free use of the mails enjoyed by Congress.",
        "correct_answer": "Franking",
        "distractor1": "Conmail",
        "distractor2": "Junket",
        "distractor3": "Procurement",
        "distractor4": "E-mail "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most prominent characteristic of a Congressperson's job is",
        "correct_answer": "hard work.",
        "distractor1": "prestige.",
        "distractor2": "high pay.",
        "distractor3": "travel.",
        "distractor4": "the 30-hour work week. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A myth about members of Congress is that they",
        "correct_answer": "are overpaid, underworked, corrupt, and ineffective.",
        "distractor1": "generally are educated and come from high-status occupations.",
        "distractor2": "tend to develop policy specialties.",
        "distractor3": "are especially effective in carrying out their constituent service.",
        "distractor4": "are overwhelmingly male. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States House of Representatives has ________ members.",
        "correct_answer": "435",
        "distractor1": "638",
        "distractor2": "100",
        "distractor3": "80",
        "distractor4": "535 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Senate has ________ members.",
        "correct_answer": "100",
        "distractor1": "50",
        "distractor2": "435",
        "distractor3": "438",
        "distractor4": "535 "
    },
    {
        "question": "How many senators are elected from each state?",
        "correct_answer": "two",
        "distractor1": "one",
        "distractor2": "four",
        "distractor3": "it depends on a state's population",
        "distractor4": "the same number as it has electors in the electoral college "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the minimum age requirements for members ofCongress set forth in the Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "One must be at least 30 years of age to serve in the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "One must be at least 21 years of age to serve in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor2": "One must be at least 35 years of age to serve in either the House or the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "There are no age requirements for members of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "The age requirements are the same for the House and the Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The members of the Senate closely reflect the nation in terms of",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "race.",
        "distractor2": "gender.",
        "distractor3": "economic status.",
        "distractor4": "prior occupation."
    },
    {
        "question": "The income and occupations of members of Congress",
        "correct_answer": "would, for the most part, make them members of the elite in American society.",
        "distractor1": "typically reflect the pluralistic nature of American society.",
        "distractor2": "are very close to the average found among their constituency.",
        "distractor3": "have no real impact on public policymaking.",
        "distractor4": "places over 90 percent of them in the millionaire businessperson class. "
    },
    {
        "question": "African Americans constitute ________ of the United States Senate.",
        "correct_answer": "less than 10 percent",
        "distractor1": "approximately 35 percent",
        "distractor2": "roughly half",
        "distractor3": "well over half",
        "distractor4": "about 20 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of religion, most members of Congress are",
        "correct_answer": "Protestant.",
        "distractor1": "Catholic.",
        "distractor2": "Jewish.",
        "distractor3": "born-again Christians.",
        "distractor4": "atheists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common prior occupation for members of Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "law.",
        "distractor1": "business.",
        "distractor2": "education.",
        "distractor3": "public service.",
        "distractor4": "state legislator. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative to the total population, the most underrepresented group in Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "women.",
        "distractor1": "African Americans.",
        "distractor2": "Hispanics.",
        "distractor3": "Jews.",
        "distractor4": "homosexuals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Overall, members of Congress can ________ of the American people.",
        "correct_answer": "possibly claim substantive representation, but not descriptive representation",
        "distractor1": "possibly claim descriptive representation, but not substantive representation",
        "distractor2": "claim both substantive and descriptive representation",
        "distractor3": "claim neither substantive nor descriptive representation",
        "distractor4": "possibly claim both substantive and descriptive representation "
    },
    {
        "question": "Millionaire Senator Edward Kennedy sponsoring a bill to help the poor and disadvantagedwould be an example of",
        "correct_answer": "substantive representation.",
        "distractor1": "descriptive representation.",
        "distractor2": "elite representation.",
        "distractor3": "constituent representation.",
        "distractor4": "franking privileges. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Incumbents are those",
        "correct_answer": "already holding office.",
        "distractor1": "running for office for the first time.",
        "distractor2": "who have been defeated in an election.",
        "distractor3": "retired members of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "running for an office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In most congressional elections, challengers",
        "correct_answer": "lose.",
        "distractor1": "outspend an incumbent.",
        "distractor2": "win.",
        "distractor3": "are better known than incumbents.",
        "distractor4": "spend roughly as much money as incumbents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The single most important advantage to someone trying to get elected to Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "being an incumbent.",
        "distractor1": "having more money to spend on campaigning.",
        "distractor2": "being charismatic and photogenic.",
        "distractor3": "having a clean record.",
        "distractor4": "winning the endorsement of the top leaders of their party. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparison between members of the House and Senate concerning the impact of incumbencyon their reelection chances shows that one of the reasons that senators have a smalleradvantage is because they",
        "correct_answer": "are more likely to be held accountable on controversial issues.",
        "distractor1": "have become over-specialized as policymakers.",
        "distractor2": "are less visible.",
        "distractor3": "have longer terms that increase the chance of scandal.",
        "distractor4": "represent more homogenous constituencies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reasons that incumbent senators have greater competition than incumbent members of theHouse include all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "voters are less likely to know the issue positions of their senators than their representatives.",
        "distractor1": "an entire state is more diverse than a congressional district, providing more of a base for opposition.",
        "distractor2": "senators have less personal contact with their constituencies.",
        "distractor3": "senators tend to draw more visible challengers.",
        "distractor4": "senate challengers are better funded than House challengers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these candidates would most likely get elected?",
        "correct_answer": "a representative running for reelection",
        "distractor1": "a senator running for reelection",
        "distractor2": "an incumbent representative challenging a senator",
        "distractor3": "a challenger",
        "distractor4": "an incumbent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to members of the House, senators are",
        "correct_answer": "more likely to face difficult reelection opponents.",
        "distractor1": "more likely to have personal contact with their constituents.",
        "distractor2": "less likely to face difficult reelection opponents.",
        "distractor3": "less likely to use television in their reelection campaigns.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Studies have shown that presidential ________ in an election have little effect on the success ofthe party's candidates for the House and Senate.",
        "correct_answer": "coattails",
        "distractor1": "junkets",
        "distractor2": "vetoes",
        "distractor3": "headwinds",
        "distractor4": "scandals "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the three primary activities that members of Congressengage in to increase the probability of their reelection?",
        "correct_answer": "oversight",
        "distractor1": "advertising",
        "distractor2": "credit-claiming",
        "distractor3": "position-taking",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; oversight is a form of position-taking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of casework by a member of Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "helping a constituent gain citizenship.",
        "distractor1": "writing a newsletter to send out to constituents.",
        "distractor2": "voting for a bill desired by constituents.",
        "distractor3": "working with a caucus on a public policy that affects his or her constituents.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The pork barrel and casework are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "opportunities for credit-claiming by members of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "advertising techniques.",
        "distractor2": "descriptive representation.",
        "distractor3": "position-taking.",
        "distractor4": "congressional continuity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An especially important asset for incumbents running for reelection is their",
        "correct_answer": "service to constituents.",
        "distractor1": "voting records.",
        "distractor2": "support by party leaders in Congress.",
        "distractor3": "presidential support.",
        "distractor4": "invisibility. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the list of federal projects, grants, and contracts available to cities, businesses,colleges, and institutions which members of Congress seek to locate in their district to promotethe interests of their constituency.",
        "correct_answer": "pork barrel",
        "distractor1": "casework",
        "distractor2": "frank",
        "distractor3": "junket",
        "distractor4": "Treasurer's register "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal grants and contracts that members of Congress try to obtain for their constituents arecollectively referred to as",
        "correct_answer": "the pork barrel.",
        "distractor1": "casework.",
        "distractor2": "public service.",
        "distractor3": "perquisites.",
        "distractor4": "affirmative action. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Members of Congress engage in each of the following activities that increase the probability oftheir reelections EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "party voting.",
        "distractor1": "advertising.",
        "distractor2": "credit-claiming.",
        "distractor3": "position taking.",
        "distractor4": "spend much of their time away from Congress and in their home districts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What accounts for the success of congressional candidates?",
        "correct_answer": "advertising, credit-claiming, and position-taking.",
        "distractor1": "their highly representative policy positions",
        "distractor2": "presidential coattails",
        "distractor3": "economic forces",
        "distractor4": "good looks "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about incumbents?",
        "correct_answer": "They usually face very tough challengers, especially in races for the House.",
        "distractor1": "They usually win elections.",
        "distractor2": "They usually have more money than their challengers.",
        "distractor3": "They usually have higher name recognition and visibility than their opponents.",
        "distractor4": "They usually have their party's endorsement. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about money in Congressional elections is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "It costs more money to elect a president than to elect a member of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "Most of the money spent in congressional elections comes from individuals.",
        "distractor2": "About a quarter of the funds raised in general election contests come from PACs.",
        "distractor3": "Political Action Committees often make contributions after the election.",
        "distractor4": "PACs often switch sides and give money to the candidate they originally opposed. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The role of party identification in voters ยน choices in congressional campaigns is",
        "correct_answer": "moderately important, even though party identification is not as strong as it used to be.",
        "distractor1": "extremely important, and increasingly so.",
        "distractor2": "slightly important in a few districts, not important in most others.",
        "distractor3": "not important at all, and never really has been.",
        "distractor4": "much less significant than in presidential campaigns. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Party loyalty at the voting booth is",
        "correct_answer": "still a good predictor of voting behavior.",
        "distractor1": "stronger than it was a generation ago.",
        "distractor2": "no longer a good indication of voting behavior.",
        "distractor3": "almost nonexistent today.",
        "distractor4": "greater among Democrats than among Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "House incumbents typically receive",
        "correct_answer": "generous support from their party campaign committees.",
        "distractor1": "about the same amount of contributions from PACs as challengers.",
        "distractor2": "less from PACs than challengers.",
        "distractor3": "much more from PACs as challengers.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above. "
    },
    {
        "question": "On average, most of the money raised by a candidate for Congress comes from",
        "correct_answer": "individual contributions.",
        "distractor1": "political parties.",
        "distractor2": "the candidate's own savings.",
        "distractor3": "Political Action Committees.",
        "distractor4": "loans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A single Political Action Committee",
        "correct_answer": "can at most account for only a small percentage of a winner's total spending.",
        "distractor1": "has no limit on the amount of money it can spend on a candidate.",
        "distractor2": "usually puts all its efforts into one candidate.",
        "distractor3": "can gain the most influence by giving money to candidates who disagree with them.",
        "distractor4": "can make or break a candidate in a particularly close congressional election. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When Political Action Committees contribute money to members of Congress they are usuallyseeking",
        "correct_answer": "access to policymakers.",
        "distractor1": "votes on specific legislation.",
        "distractor2": "to install a preferred challenger in office.",
        "distractor3": "to create a more pluralistic Congress.",
        "distractor4": "to literally buy opposing legislators ยน votes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the role of money in congressional elections isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Challengers usually outspend incumbents.",
        "distractor1": "Outspending your opponent by a large margin is no guarantee of success.",
        "distractor2": "The more challengers spend, the more votes they receive.",
        "distractor3": "In open seats, the candidate who spends the most usually wins.",
        "distractor4": "Incumbents benefit less from campaign spending than challengers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following may increase the likelihood that an incumbent is defeated EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "campaign funding.",
        "distractor1": "national political   tidal waves.  ",
        "distractor2": "redistricting.",
        "distractor3": "scandals.",
        "distractor4": "a strong challenger. "
    },
    {
        "question": "After each federal census,",
        "correct_answer": "the membership of the House is reapportioned",
        "distractor1": "the office of the Speaker of the House changes hands.",
        "distractor2": "the size of Congress increases.",
        "distractor3": "the Senate reapportions its membership.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Occasionally, a major political tidal wave rolls across the country and throws large numbers ofincumbents of a given party out of office. When did this last occur?",
        "correct_answer": "1994",
        "distractor1": "1980",
        "distractor2": "1974",
        "distractor3": "1964",
        "distractor4": "1954 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Congress is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Congress is a collection of generalists trying to make policy on specialized topics.",
        "distractor2": "Members of Congress are surrounded by people who know (or claim to know) more than they do.",
        "distractor3": "Members of Congress are often unsure of what is being voted on when a roll-call vote is called.",
        "distractor4": "Members frequently ask their colleagues how to vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "Nebraska's legislature is the only one in the United States that is NOT",
        "correct_answer": "bicameral.",
        "distractor1": "elected by the voters.",
        "distractor2": "unicameral.",
        "distractor3": "tricameral.",
        "distractor4": "under term limits. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Bicameralism means that a legislative body is one",
        "correct_answer": "with two houses, providing checks and balances on policymaking.",
        "distractor1": "in which each state has two senators, providing equal representation of the states.",
        "distractor2": "in which incumbents have a better chance of being reelected, providing continuity in policymaking.",
        "distractor3": "that must share power with a president, providing more efficient policymaking.",
        "distractor4": "in which there are only two political parties. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To be sent to the president, a bill must be passed by",
        "correct_answer": "both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "the House.",
        "distractor2": "the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "either the House or the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "a majority vote of Congress, regardless of which house the votes come from. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The House ________ Committee reviews most bills coming from other committees before theygo on to the full House, thus performing a traffic cop function.",
        "correct_answer": "Rules",
        "distractor1": "Appropriations",
        "distractor2": "Ways and Means",
        "distractor3": "Authorization",
        "distractor4": "Review "
    },
    {
        "question": "Articles of impeachment must be passed by",
        "correct_answer": "the House.",
        "distractor1": "either the House or the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "the Supreme Court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "House seats are up for election every",
        "correct_answer": "two years.",
        "distractor1": "four years.",
        "distractor2": "six years.",
        "distractor3": "eight years.",
        "distractor4": "five years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A Senate seat is up for election every",
        "correct_answer": "six years.",
        "distractor1": "two years.",
        "distractor2": "four years.",
        "distractor3": "eight years.",
        "distractor4": "five years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the Senate as compared to the House?",
        "correct_answer": "more influential in foreign affairs",
        "distractor1": "more centralized with stronger leadership",
        "distractor2": "seniority more important in determining power",
        "distractor3": "more influential on the budget",
        "distractor4": "smaller in number, less powerful and less prestigious "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution, revenue bills must originate in the",
        "correct_answer": "House.",
        "distractor1": "Internal Revenue Service.",
        "distractor2": "Federal Reserve System.",
        "distractor3": "Senate.",
        "distractor4": "Treasury Department. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nominees to the United States Supreme Court must be confirmed by",
        "correct_answer": "the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "the House.",
        "distractor2": "either the House or the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution, once impeached, federal officials are then tried in the",
        "correct_answer": "Senate.",
        "distractor1": "Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "House.",
        "distractor3": "Department of Justice.",
        "distractor4": "United States District Court for the District of Columbia. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The House Rules Committee",
        "correct_answer": "reviews most bills coming from committee before they go to the full House.",
        "distractor1": "has its members appointed by the House majority leader.",
        "distractor2": "is similar to the Senate Rules Committee.",
        "distractor3": "usually retains independence from the House leadership.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution gives the House of Representatives the power to",
        "correct_answer": "initiate all revenue bills.",
        "distractor1": "ratify all treaties.",
        "distractor2": "confirm presidential nominations.",
        "distractor3": "try impeached officials.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the key differences between the House and Senate is that the House",
        "correct_answer": "has more policy specialization.",
        "distractor1": "has weaker leadership.",
        "distractor2": "is more influential on foreign affairs.",
        "distractor3": "is less centralized.",
        "distractor4": "is less institutionalized. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the key differences between the House and Senate is that the Senate",
        "correct_answer": "is less dependent on seniority for determining power.",
        "distractor1": "is more centralized.",
        "distractor2": "has a lower turnover rate.",
        "distractor3": "has stronger leadership.",
        "distractor4": "has more anarchy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The real differences between the House and the Senate lie in their",
        "correct_answer": "organization and centralization of power.",
        "distractor1": "ideology.",
        "distractor2": "members ยน characteristics.",
        "distractor3": "role in policy.",
        "distractor4": "power relative to each other. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The filibuster",
        "correct_answer": "is unique to the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "is unique to the House.",
        "distractor2": "is allowed in both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "has been ruled unconstitutional.",
        "distractor4": "has been prohibited in both the House and Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ members present and voting can halt a filibuster by voting for cloture.",
        "correct_answer": "Sixty",
        "distractor1": "Seventy",
        "distractor2": "Eighty",
        "distractor3": "Fifty-one",
        "distractor4": "Seventy-five "
    },
    {
        "question": "The filibuster is a technique used in the",
        "correct_answer": "Senate to prolong debate in order to kill a bill.",
        "distractor1": "House to delay legislation until a full House can convene.",
        "distractor2": "Senate to bypass committees in voting on controversial issues.",
        "distractor3": "House to allow more time to debate controversial policies.",
        "distractor4": "House and Senate to prevent a vote on a bill. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To cut off debate and end a filibuster is known as",
        "correct_answer": "cloture.",
        "distractor1": "franking.",
        "distractor2": "coattails.",
        "distractor3": "overriding.",
        "distractor4": "hushing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To end a filibuster requires ________ members present and voting to cut off debate.",
        "correct_answer": "60",
        "distractor1": "50",
        "distractor2": "75",
        "distractor3": "99",
        "distractor4": "218 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following congressional offices is mandated by the Constitution?",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker of the House",
        "distractor1": "House and Senate Majority Leader",
        "distractor2": "President of the House",
        "distractor3": "President of the United States",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does the Speaker NOT play a role in?",
        "correct_answer": "recommending which members should be expelled from the House for failure to support the party's positions on bills",
        "distractor1": "making committee assignments",
        "distractor2": "presiding over the House when it is in session",
        "distractor3": "assigning most bills to committees",
        "distractor4": "appointing the party's legislative leaders "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is next in line after the vice president to succeed a president who resigns, dies inoffice, or is impeached.",
        "correct_answer": "Speaker of the House",
        "distractor1": "Senate majority leader",
        "distractor2": "Senate minority leader",
        "distractor3": "House majority leader",
        "distractor4": "Chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff "
    },
    {
        "question": "The minority whip",
        "correct_answer": "keeps a close head count on key votes, and attempts to keep party members in line.",
        "distractor1": "assists the majority leader in party-line votes.",
        "distractor2": "becomes the Speaker automatically if the Speaker resigns.",
        "distractor3": "represents African Americans, Hispanic Americans, and Asian Americans in each chamber of Congress.",
        "distractor4": "is used to punish members who do not vote with the rest of their party. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the majority leader of the House of Representatives isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The majority leader exercises substantial control over which bills get assigned to which committees.",
        "distractor1": "The majority leader is the main steppingstone to the job of Speaker of the House.",
        "distractor2": "The majority leader is responsible for scheduling bills in the House.",
        "distractor3": "The majority leader is responsible for rounding up votes on behalf of the party's position on legislation.",
        "distractor4": "He or she is the principal ally of the Speaker. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ has the job of presiding over the Senate, breaking ties when necessary.",
        "correct_answer": "vice president",
        "distractor1": "majority leader",
        "distractor2": "majority whip",
        "distractor3": "minority leader",
        "distractor4": "Speaker "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most powerful person in the Senate is the",
        "correct_answer": "majority leader.",
        "distractor1": "vice president of the United States, who serves as president of the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "chair of the Rules Committee.",
        "distractor3": "Speaker.",
        "distractor4": "president of the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most important congressional activity is done",
        "correct_answer": "in meetings of standing committees and their subcommittees.",
        "distractor1": "on legislators ยน visits to their home districts.",
        "distractor2": "on the House floor.",
        "distractor3": "on the Senate floor.",
        "distractor4": "in the White House. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the business of Congress takes place",
        "correct_answer": "in committees and subcommittees.",
        "distractor1": "in congressional districts.",
        "distractor2": "on the floor of the House and Senate.",
        "distractor3": "during evening social functions.",
        "distractor4": "in the Rules committees. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ committee is one appointed for a limited, specific purpose, such as that set up toinvestigate the Watergate scandal.",
        "correct_answer": "select",
        "distractor1": "standing",
        "distractor2": "conference",
        "distractor3": "joint",
        "distractor4": "special "
    },
    {
        "question": "Appropriations, Judiciary, and Armed Forces are all examples of ________ committees.",
        "correct_answer": "standing",
        "distractor1": "select",
        "distractor2": "conference",
        "distractor3": "joint",
        "distractor4": "rule "
    },
    {
        "question": "When the House and the Senate pass different versions of the same bill",
        "correct_answer": "a conference committee is appointed to resolve differences.",
        "distractor1": "the House bill is changed to conform with the Senate bill.",
        "distractor2": "the Senate bill is changed to conform with the House bill.",
        "distractor3": "a joint committee is appointed to resolve differences.",
        "distractor4": "the president may select which bill to enact into law. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Legislative ________ is the process of monitoring the bureaucracy and its administration ofpolicy.",
        "correct_answer": "oversight",
        "distractor1": "franking",
        "distractor2": "stonewalling",
        "distractor3": "overview",
        "distractor4": "supremacy "
    },
    {
        "question": "When members of Congress hold a hearing to question a cabinet member on how a law isbeing carried out, they are engaging in",
        "correct_answer": "legislative oversight.",
        "distractor1": "agenda-setting.",
        "distractor2": "filibustering.",
        "distractor3": "casework.",
        "distractor4": "congressional administration. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about congressional committees is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Unless a committee gives a bill a favorable report it almost never can be considered by the full House or Senate.",
        "distractor2": "The most important output of the committee is the marked up bill.",
        "distractor3": "Members of the committee usually serve as floor managers of the bill.",
        "distractor4": "Members of the committee act as cue-givers to whom other members turn for advice."
    },
    {
        "question": "The seniority system gave a decisive edge to House members from ________ districts.",
        "correct_answer": "safe",
        "distractor1": "Republican",
        "distractor2": "suburban",
        "distractor3": "older",
        "distractor4": "competitive "
    },
    {
        "question": "Traditionally, Congressional committee chairpersons have been chosen through",
        "correct_answer": "the seniority system.",
        "distractor1": "party rank.",
        "distractor2": "popularity with majority leaders.",
        "distractor3": "a majority vote by committee members.",
        "distractor4": "the merit system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Congressional reforms of the 1970s",
        "correct_answer": "decentralized power and democratized Congress.",
        "distractor1": "professionalized the operation of Congress and made it much more efficient.",
        "distractor2": "were aimed at rooting out scandal and corruption.",
        "distractor3": "ended the two-party monopoly of Congress and brought new parties into Congress.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Republican congressional reforms in the 1990s included all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "committee chairs were given complete control over the timing of bills under consideration.",
        "distractor1": "committee chairs were allowed to choose the chairs of subcommittees on their committees.",
        "distractor2": "both committee and subcommittee chairs were limited to three consecutive two -year terms as chair.",
        "distractor3": "some subcommittees were eliminated.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is responsible for responding to congressional requests for informationand providing non-partisan studies?",
        "correct_answer": "Congressional Research Service",
        "distractor1": "Congressional Budget Office",
        "distractor2": "General Accounting Office",
        "distractor3": "Ways and Means Committee",
        "distractor4": "Office of the Majority Leader "
    },
    {
        "question": "Committee staff is responsible for all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "providing services to constituents.",
        "distractor1": "organizing hearings.",
        "distractor2": "writing legislation.",
        "distractor3": "monitoring the executive branch.",
        "distractor4": "coordinating with congressional offices. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following offices is responsible for making economic projections about theperformance of the economy, the costs of proposed policies, and the economic effects of taxingand spending alternatives?",
        "correct_answer": "Congressional Budget Office",
        "distractor1": "Congressional Research Service",
        "distractor2": "General Accounting Office",
        "distractor3": "Ways and Means Committee",
        "distractor4": "Federal Reserve "
    },
    {
        "question": "Only ________ can formally submit a bill for congressional consideration.",
        "correct_answer": "members of the House or senators",
        "distractor1": "members of the House",
        "distractor2": "senators",
        "distractor3": "the president",
        "distractor4": "the Speaker of the House "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most bills formally submitted for consideration in Congress",
        "correct_answer": "are quietly killed off early in the process.",
        "distractor1": "are passed and signed into law.",
        "distractor2": "are passed, but vetoed by the president.",
        "distractor3": "are defeated in close final votes on the floors of one chamber.",
        "distractor4": "pass one house, but are killed in the other house. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Basically, Congress is a(n) ________ decision -making body.",
        "correct_answer": "reactive and cumbersome",
        "distractor1": "active and smooth",
        "distractor2": "unified and consistent",
        "distractor3": "radical and hasty",
        "distractor4": "retroactive "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's most common method of attempting to influence Congress is to",
        "correct_answer": "hold regular meetings with the party's leaders in Congress.",
        "distractor1": "call up wavering members.",
        "distractor2": "offer to campaign for members.",
        "distractor3": "invite members of Congress to the White House.",
        "distractor4": "use the veto power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Presidential leadership of Congress in promoting the chief executive's programs is",
        "correct_answer": "at the margins, as a facilitator.",
        "distractor1": "dominant, with a heavy hand usually convincing wavering members.",
        "distractor2": "a smooth, generally successful enterprise.",
        "distractor3": "nonexistent.",
        "distractor4": "proactive, substantive, and adversarial. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The parties in Congress are most cohesive",
        "correct_answer": "when electing their official leaders.",
        "distractor1": "on foreign policy issues.",
        "distractor2": "on economic policy.",
        "distractor3": "military matters.",
        "distractor4": "during floor votes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The English politician and philosopher Edmund Burke favored the concept of legislators as________, using their best judgment to make policy in the interests of the people.",
        "correct_answer": "trustees",
        "distractor1": "constituent robots",
        "distractor2": "instructed delegates",
        "distractor3": "politicos",
        "distractor4": "judges "
    },
    {
        "question": "Some prefer the concept of legislators as ________, mirroring the preferences of theirconstituents.",
        "correct_answer": "instructed delegates",
        "distractor1": "trustees",
        "distractor2": "politicos",
        "distractor3": "uninstructed delegates",
        "distractor4": "pollsters "
    },
    {
        "question": "The best way constituents can influence congressional voting on legislation is to",
        "correct_answer": "elect a representative or senator who agrees with their views.",
        "distractor1": "sign petitions.",
        "distractor2": "write letters or send telegrams.",
        "distractor3": "fax or call in their opinions.",
        "distractor4": "demonstrate on the steps of the capitol. "
    },
    {
        "question": "On a typical issue, the primary determinant of a congressional member's vote is",
        "correct_answer": "personal ideology.",
        "distractor1": "constituent preferences as indicated by extensive polling.",
        "distractor2": "the position of the president.",
        "distractor3": "the toss of a coin.",
        "distractor4": "the position of their party leaders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Legislators who use their best judgment to make policy in the interests of the people are called",
        "correct_answer": "trustees.",
        "distractor1": "instructed delegates.",
        "distractor2": "politicos.",
        "distractor3": "attentive leaders.",
        "distractor4": "opinion leaders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most members of Congress would be considered",
        "correct_answer": "politicos.",
        "distractor1": "trustees.",
        "distractor2": "instructed delegates.",
        "distractor3": "ambassadors.",
        "distractor4": "attentive leaders. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Constituencies influence policy mostly by",
        "correct_answer": "the initial choice of the representative.",
        "distractor1": "influencing congressional leaders.",
        "distractor2": "empowering the president in his negotiations with Congress.",
        "distractor3": "buying votes through election contributions.",
        "distractor4": "lobbying Senators. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If Congress has increased the scope of government it is because",
        "correct_answer": "that is what constituencies want.",
        "distractor1": "members typically suffer from Potomac fever.",
        "distractor2": "members are by-spending liberals.",
        "distractor3": "that is what Congressional staffers want.",
        "distractor4": "it is responding to the policy expertise provided by the bureaucracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As Richard Neustadt has argued, presidential power is probably best understood as the powerto",
        "correct_answer": "persuade.",
        "distractor1": "command.",
        "distractor2": "control.",
        "distractor3": "harass.",
        "distractor4": "veto. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard Neustadt has argued that presidential power is the power to",
        "correct_answer": "persuade. ",
        "distractor1": "instruct.",
        "distractor2": "command.",
        "distractor3": "educate.",
        "distractor4": "control."
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans want a strong president,",
        "correct_answer": "but do not like a concentration of power.",
        "distractor1": "and do not care whether the strength is used for good or for ill.",
        "distractor2": "and would like to abolish all checks on presidential power.",
        "distractor3": "but do not expect much from any president.",
        "distractor4": "but want an even stronger Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All presidents but one have been",
        "correct_answer": "Protestant.",
        "distractor1": "Catholic.",
        "distractor2": "Hare Krishna.",
        "distractor3": "atheist.",
        "distractor4": "Evangelical Christian. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the original Constitution, the president must be",
        "correct_answer": "at least 35 years old.",
        "distractor1": "a resident of the United States for at least five years.",
        "distractor2": "a citizen of the United States for at least ten years.",
        "distractor3": "a white man.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above except D "
    },
    {
        "question": "How many presidents were political scientists?",
        "correct_answer": "one",
        "distractor1": "about half of them",
        "distractor2": "all but one of them",
        "distractor3": "two",
        "distractor4": "all of them "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which president was a political scientist?",
        "correct_answer": "Woodrow Wilson ",
        "distractor1": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor2": "James Madison",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor4": "Bill Clinton"
    },
    {
        "question": "________ was widely regarded to be the worst and most ineffective president.",
        "correct_answer": "Warren Harding",
        "distractor1": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor2": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor3": "Bill Clinton",
        "distractor4": "Andrew Johnson "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since World War II, United States presidents have",
        "correct_answer": "come from a diversity of career experiences.",
        "distractor1": "except for Bill Clinton, first served as vice president.",
        "distractor2": "had very similar career backgrounds.",
        "distractor3": "all previously served as governors.",
        "distractor4": "all served as United States senators. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Twenty-second Amendment, passed in 1951,",
        "correct_answer": "limited presidents to two terms of office.",
        "distractor1": "provided for the presidential and vice presidential candidates to run as a team.",
        "distractor2": "gave impeachment powers to Congress.",
        "distractor3": "provided for the direct election of the president by the people.",
        "distractor4": "granted 18-year-olds the right to vote. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The two-term limit was placed on the presidency by",
        "correct_answer": "the Twenty-second Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "an act of Congress passed after Franklin D. Roosevelt's death.",
        "distractor2": "the Presidential Powers Act of 1951.",
        "distractor3": "the Twenty-fifth Amendment.",
        "distractor4": "Article II of the original Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ took over as president upon the death of Franklin Roosevelt in 1945, and eventuallyordered the dropping of the atomic bombs on Japanese cities.",
        "correct_answer": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor1": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "distractor2": "Dwight Eisenhower",
        "distractor3": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor4": "John F. Kennedy "
    },
    {
        "question": "As president, ________ launched the   Great Society   at home while escalating the VietnamWar abroad.",
        "correct_answer": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor1": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor3": "Gerald Ford",
        "distractor4": "Dwight Eisenhower "
    },
    {
        "question": "Appointed to the vice presidency in 1973 due to a vacancy, he was the only one to becomepresident having run for neither the presidency or vice presidency in the preceding election.",
        "correct_answer": "Gerald Ford",
        "distractor1": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor2": "Nelson Rockefeller",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor4": "Jimmy Carter "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following presidents was a Republican?",
        "correct_answer": "Richard Nixon ",
        "distractor1": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor2": "John Kennedy",
        "distractor3": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor4": "Jimmy Carter"
    },
    {
        "question": "The only president to resign his office was",
        "correct_answer": "Richard Nixon. ",
        "distractor1": "Warren Harding.",
        "distractor2": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor3": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor4": "Spiro Agnew."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Most presidents have served two or more full terms.",
        "distractor1": "For over 10 percent of American history, the presidency has been occupied by an individual not elected to the office.",
        "distractor2": "In the twentieth century, almost one-third of our presidents were   accidental Presidents.  ",
        "distractor3": "About one in five presidents got the job because they were vice president when the incumbent president died or resigned.",
        "distractor4": "Most presidential elections are decided by Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to his election as president, ________ had been a well -known actor and served for twoterms as governor of California.",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor1": "George Bush",
        "distractor2": "Jimmy Carter",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor4": "Earl Warren "
    },
    {
        "question": "Impeachment is roughly the political equivalent of a(n)",
        "correct_answer": "indictment in criminal law.",
        "distractor1": "exoneration.",
        "distractor2": "admission of guilt.",
        "distractor3": "guilty verdict.",
        "distractor4": "firing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to impeach a president, it takes",
        "correct_answer": "a majority vote in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor1": "a unanimous vote of the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "a two-thirds vote in the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "a two-thirds vote in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor4": "a majority vote in the Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Impeachment of a president means that the president is",
        "correct_answer": "indicted by the House.",
        "distractor1": "convicted of a crime.",
        "distractor2": "removed from office.",
        "distractor3": "tried by the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to convict and remove an impeached president, it takes",
        "correct_answer": "a two-thirds vote in the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "a majority vote in the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "a majority vote in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor3": "a two-thirds vote in the House of Representatives.",
        "distractor4": "both B and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "Once the House votes for impeachment, the president",
        "correct_answer": "is tried by the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "must leave office.",
        "distractor2": "is fined or sentenced to prison.",
        "distractor3": "is tried by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "must be indicted by a Grand Jury before being removed from office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The scandal surrounding Richard Nixon's administration that led to impeachment hearingswas known as",
        "correct_answer": "Watergate.",
        "distractor1": "Iran-Contra.",
        "distractor2": "the Camp David Affair.",
        "distractor3": "Checkers.",
        "distractor4": "Teapot Dome. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution framers",
        "correct_answer": "generally wanted a president with limited authority and responsibilities.",
        "distractor1": "were unanimous in wanting a single president to lead the country.",
        "distractor2": "were united in wanting a strong chief executive.",
        "distractor3": "were united in wanting a chief executive similar to the prime minister of Great Britain.",
        "distractor4": "hoped to create a monarchy in the United States. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's power can best be understood as",
        "correct_answer": "shared with other branches of government as part of the Madisonian system of checks and balances.",
        "distractor1": "very limited and largely ceremonial.",
        "distractor2": "always the dominant figure in the American political system.",
        "distractor3": "unlimited and absolute.",
        "distractor4": "originally intended to be unlimited and absolute, but gradually weakened over time. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution",
        "correct_answer": "says remarkably little about presidential power.",
        "distractor1": "provides a list of specific powers and implied powers reserved for the president.",
        "distractor2": "places the power of the presidency above the other branches of government.",
        "distractor3": "requires Congress to delegate specific areas of presidential power.",
        "distractor4": "B, C, and D are all correct. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to preserve the balance of power in government without jeopardizing theindependence of the presidency, the framers",
        "correct_answer": "checked those powers that they believed to be most dangerous.",
        "distractor1": "refused to give the president powers in the area of national security.",
        "distractor2": "created a weak executive.",
        "distractor3": "limited the president to administrative powers.",
        "distractor4": "limited presidents to two terms of office so they could not become   elected monarchs.   "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a constitutional power of the president?",
        "correct_answer": "enact legislation by issuing decrees",
        "distractor1": "serve as Commander in Chief of the armed forces",
        "distractor2": "sign or veto legislation passed by Congress",
        "distractor3": "appoint federal judges with the advice and consent of a majority of the Senate",
        "distractor4": "All of these are the president's constitutional powers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president has the constitutional authority to make treaties with other nations, subject tothe agreement of",
        "correct_answer": "two-thirds of the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "a majority of both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "a majority of the Senate.",
        "distractor3": "two-thirds of the House.",
        "distractor4": "a majority of the House. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The founding fathers envisioned a presidency that would",
        "correct_answer": "have fewer responsibilities than today's presidency.",
        "distractor1": "be better organized than today's presidency.",
        "distractor2": "have greater control over the Congress than today's presidency.",
        "distractor3": "have greater powers than today's presidency.",
        "distractor4": "clearly be the dominant branch of government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Theodore Roosevelt and Woodrow Wilson",
        "correct_answer": "set a precedent for presidents to serve as world leaders.",
        "distractor1": "were the first presidents to exercise power beyond the specific powers granted to the president in the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "developed the role of the president as manager of the economy.",
        "distractor3": "were the only two presidents to ever have their actions declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "were among the least effective presidents. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A primary resource available to presidents for controlling the bureaucracy is",
        "correct_answer": "the power to appoint top-level administrators.",
        "distractor1": "control of the federal budget.",
        "distractor2": "their unlimited power to offer patronage positions in the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor3": "their ability to dismiss or fire most members of the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In recent years,",
        "correct_answer": "presidents have paid closer attention to appointing officials who will be responsive to the president's policies.",
        "distractor1": "presidents have been less concerned about their appointment power.",
        "distractor2": "presidents have paid less attention to agency rules and regulations.",
        "distractor3": "there has been a trend toward decentralized decision making in the White House.",
        "distractor4": "there has been a trend toward centralized decision making in the White House. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A constitutional duty of the vice president is to",
        "correct_answer": "preside over the Senate and cast the deciding vote in the event of a tie.",
        "distractor1": "attend the funerals of foreign leaders on behalf of the president.",
        "distractor2": "preside over the House and cast the deciding vote in the event of a tie.",
        "distractor3": "raise funds for party candidates.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Traditionally, a vice president",
        "correct_answer": "has little responsibility.",
        "distractor1": "has no formal constitutional powers.",
        "distractor2": "later becomes president.",
        "distractor3": "is an important advisor to the president.",
        "distractor4": "both C and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's cabinet",
        "correct_answer": "consists of executive branch leaders who advise the president on policy and administer government departments.",
        "distractor1": "was provided for and elaborated upon by the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "has changed very little since 1960.",
        "distractor3": "tends to serve as a collective board of directors.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The presidential cabinet",
        "correct_answer": "consists of the head of each executive department, plus any additional government officials the president designates.",
        "distractor1": "is the electronically locked vault where the president keeps his top secret papers.",
        "distractor2": "is given tremendous power under the Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "includes, by law, a minimum of two sitting members of Congress at all times.",
        "distractor4": "can veto actions by the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a member of the cabinet?",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation",
        "distractor2": "Speaker of the House",
        "distractor3": "secretary of the navy",
        "distractor4": "White House Chief of Staff"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabinet-level executive departments are created by",
        "correct_answer": "Congress.",
        "distractor1": "the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "the president.",
        "distractor3": "rarely held national referendums.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The head of each cabinet-level executive department is appointed by the president and",
        "correct_answer": "must be confirmed by a majority of the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "must be confirmed by a majority of the House.",
        "distractor2": "is not subject to House or Senate approval.",
        "distractor3": "must be confirmed by a majority of both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "must be confirmed by two-thirds of the Senate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabinet department responsible for making foreign policy and handling treatynegotiations is",
        "correct_answer": "state. ",
        "distractor1": "interior.",
        "distractor2": "justice.",
        "distractor3": "foreign affairs.",
        "distractor4": "defense."
    },
    {
        "question": "The two oldest cabinet departments are",
        "correct_answer": "state and treasury.",
        "distractor1": "state and defense.",
        "distractor2": "interior and justice.",
        "distractor3": "treasury and justice.",
        "distractor4": "education and state. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The newest cabinet department is",
        "correct_answer": "homeland security.",
        "distractor1": "commerce.",
        "distractor2": "agriculture.",
        "distractor3": "interior.",
        "distractor4": "transportation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Security Council",
        "correct_answer": "links the president's key foreign and military policy advisors.",
        "distractor1": "is composed of the heads of the three branches of the armed services and makes recommendations to the president on combat strategy.",
        "distractor2": "was established by President Roosevelt to manage foreign and domestic intelligence operations.",
        "distractor3": "was created by legislation to keep the president informed on foreign affairs.",
        "distractor4": "helps the president make policy on such matters as inflation and unemployment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Office of Management and Budget is comprised of",
        "correct_answer": "political appointees and career officials.",
        "distractor1": "political appointees, career officials, and congressional staffers.",
        "distractor2": "all political appointees.",
        "distractor3": "all career officials.",
        "distractor4": "economists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Office of Management and Budget, the National Security Council, and the Council ofEconomic Advisors are",
        "correct_answer": "policymaking bodies of the Executive Office of the President.",
        "distractor1": "members of the White House staff.",
        "distractor2": "advisory bodies of the Department of State.",
        "distractor3": "part of the president's cabinet.",
        "distractor4": "the key liaison agencies between the president and Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The budgetary implications of the president's budget are provided to the president by",
        "correct_answer": "Office of Management and Budget. ",
        "distractor1": "Executive Budget Office.",
        "distractor2": "Department of the Treasury.",
        "distractor3": "Council of Economic Advisors.",
        "distractor4": "Internal Revenue Service."
    },
    {
        "question": "The agency that reviews legislative proposals for the president is the",
        "correct_answer": "Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor1": "Council of Economic Advisors.",
        "distractor2": "National Security Council.",
        "distractor3": "Legislative Executive Agency.",
        "distractor4": "Executive Legislative Agency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the executive branch of government that the president sees daily and relies heavilyon for information, policy options, and analysis is the",
        "correct_answer": "White House staff.",
        "distractor1": "vice president.",
        "distractor2": "president's cabinet.",
        "distractor3": "Executive Office of the President.",
        "distractor4": "Council of Economic Advisors. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The system of White House management employed by President John Kennedy was",
        "correct_answer": "such that many aides equally participated in the decision-making process. ",
        "distractor1": "to disperse his authority to numerous aides, each of who had powerful decision-making power.",
        "distractor2": "unusually closed, with only the president and his two closest aides involved in most major decisions.",
        "distractor3": "to personally take charge of even the minor details of decision making.",
        "distractor4": "a chain of command with a chief of staff who controlled almost all access to the president."
    },
    {
        "question": "John F. Kennedy's   wheel-and-spokes   system of management was characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "many aides with equal status balanced against one another in the decision -making process.",
        "distractor1": "a hierarchical organization with a chief of staff at the top.",
        "distractor2": "the president's involvement in every administrative detail.",
        "distractor3": "a closed, small network of computers that directly linked the president to his closest advisors through e-mail messages.",
        "distractor4": "a streamlined, fast-paced, and efficient decision-making style. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization and importance of the White House staff depend on",
        "correct_answer": "the personal style of the president in office.",
        "distractor1": "the president's Chief of Staff.",
        "distractor2": "agenda schedules and formal rules of debate.",
        "distractor3": "the legal authority granted it by Congress.",
        "distractor4": "a hierarchy of access to the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president who was known as the   consummate delegator   because he dispersed authorityto his advisors was",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor1": "John F. Kennedy.",
        "distractor2": "George Bush.",
        "distractor3": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor4": "Lyndon Johnson. "
    },
    {
        "question": "George W. Bush's management style is",
        "correct_answer": "to delegate. ",
        "distractor1": "wheel and spokes.",
        "distractor2": "chaotic.",
        "distractor3": "hierarchical.",
        "distractor4": "transitional."
    },
    {
        "question": "The pocket veto can only be used",
        "correct_answer": "when Congress is adjourned. ",
        "distractor1": "when a new president is about to take office.",
        "distractor2": "during a presidential election year.",
        "distractor3": "when Congress is in session.",
        "distractor4": "on appropriations bills."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Constitution gives the president the power to influence the legislative process through hisresponsibility to",
        "correct_answer": "report on the state of the union and veto acts of Congress.",
        "distractor1": "make laws by decree without the consent of Congress in some situations.",
        "distractor2": "direct the business of Congress and initiate impeachment.",
        "distractor3": "recommend legislation and make appointments.",
        "distractor4": "manage the economy, lead the party, and deal with national crises. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When a president vetoes congressional legislation,",
        "correct_answer": "Congress can override the veto by a two-thirds vote in both houses.",
        "distractor1": "Congress must form a joint committee to address the president's complaints.",
        "distractor2": "the Supreme Court determines whether the law will take effect.",
        "distractor3": "there is nothing Congress can do about it.",
        "distractor4": "one house of Congress can override the veto if it votes to do so with a two -thirds vote. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A pocket veto is the situation in which the president",
        "correct_answer": "lets a bill die by neither signing nor vetoing it after Congress has adjourned.",
        "distractor1": "vetoes particular items in a spending bill.",
        "distractor2": "rejects a Congressional override.",
        "distractor3": "lets a bill become law by neither vetoing nor signing it.",
        "distractor4": "sends a law back to Congress with the reasons for rejecting it. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the presidential veto is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Almost half of all vetoed bills have been overridden by Congress.",
        "distractor1": "Presidents can not veto only parts of a bill.",
        "distractor2": "Even the threat of a presidential veto can be an effective tool for persuading Congress to give more weight to presidents ยน views.",
        "distractor3": "The presidential veto is an inherently negative resource.",
        "distractor4": "The president, unlike most governors, cannot use a line-item veto. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1998, the Supreme Court ruled in Clinton v. City of New York that",
        "correct_answer": "a 1996 law granting the president the authority to propose rescinding funds in appropriation bills was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor1": "the pocket veto was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor2": "that the Clinton impeachment vote was unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "that the president could not line-item veto grant monies to urban areas.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1996, Congress passed a law giving the president the authority to propose rescinding fundsin appropriations bills. Later,",
        "correct_answer": "the Supreme Court voided the decision.",
        "distractor1": "Congress overturned the law.",
        "distractor2": "President Clinton chose not to use such authority.",
        "distractor3": "President Clinton used it successfully.",
        "distractor4": "President Bush voided the decision. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary obstacle to party unity in Congress is the",
        "correct_answer": "lack of consensus on policy issues among party members. ",
        "distractor1": "multiplicity of parties represented.",
        "distractor2": "lack of presidential leadership.",
        "distractor3": "separation of powers.",
        "distractor4": "bicameral legislature."
    },
    {
        "question": "When constituency opinion and the president's proposals conflict, members of Congress aremore likely to",
        "correct_answer": "vote with their constituents.",
        "distractor1": "vote with the president.",
        "distractor2": "seek an electronic vote rather than a voice vote.",
        "distractor3": "not vote.",
        "distractor4": "vote according to their own ideology. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Presidential coattails refers to",
        "correct_answer": "voters casting their ballots for congressional candidates of the president's party who will support the president.",
        "distractor1": "presidential favors to those who support the president's policies.",
        "distractor2": "the formal constitutional powers of the president.",
        "distractor3": "the ability of members of Congress to hide behind the president on tough issues.",
        "distractor4": "withholding of presidential favors from those who oppose the president's policies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Presidential coattails refers to",
        "correct_answer": "voters who support the president casting their ballots for congressional candidates of the president's party.",
        "distractor1": "the tendency for the president's party to lose congressional seats in midterm elections.",
        "distractor2": "fund-raising parties the president hosts to raise money for congressional candidates.",
        "distractor3": "the president's power to appoint members of his own political party to cabinet posts and as personal advisors.",
        "distractor4": "members of Congress voting according to the wishes of the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Recent election studies show",
        "correct_answer": "a diminishing connection between voters ยน presidential and congressional voting.",
        "distractor1": "the president's party usually gains seats in Congress in mid-term elections.",
        "distractor2": "that the party of the winning presidential candidate has been gaining an increasing number of seats in congress.",
        "distractor3": "that presidential coattails no longer exist.",
        "distractor4": "that many congressional races are determined by presidential coattails. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A mid-term election is",
        "correct_answer": "a congressional election that is not accompanied by a presidential election.",
        "distractor1": "one in which the incumbent is running for reelection.",
        "distractor2": "held every two years.",
        "distractor3": "a special election that may remove an official from office in the middle of the term.",
        "distractor4": "a presidential election that occurs during a session of Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In mid-term elections, the",
        "correct_answer": "president's party typically loses seats. ",
        "distractor1": "president's coattails are the strongest.",
        "distractor2": "president's party typically gains seats.",
        "distractor3": "president almost always wins reelection; a president who does not is the exception.",
        "distractor4": "president usually does not become involved."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most studies show that",
        "correct_answer": "presidential coattails rarely affect elections.",
        "distractor1": "presidential coattails are increasing in certain regions.",
        "distractor2": "presidential coattails are stronger in midterm elections.",
        "distractor3": "presidential coattails are stronger than ever.",
        "distractor4": "presidential coattails affect Republicans more than Democrats. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The impact of public approval or disapproval of the president on the support that thepresident receives in Congress is",
        "correct_answer": "important, but usually at the margins on most policies. ",
        "distractor1": "irrelevant.",
        "distractor2": "not too important, though it occasionally has a minor effect.",
        "distractor3": "represented in the text by the equation s \\ ยน3D px\\ ยน2D1.",
        "distractor4": "extremely important, and sways nearly all members of Congress on every vote."
    },
    {
        "question": "The political resource that has the most potential to turn a situation of stalemate between thepresident and Congress into one supportive of the president's legislative proposals is",
        "correct_answer": "public approval.",
        "distractor1": "presidential leadership.",
        "distractor2": "the president's party leadership.",
        "distractor3": "presidential rewards and sanctions.",
        "distractor4": "the threat of veto. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Electoral mandates",
        "correct_answer": "consist of the perception that the voters strongly support the winner's positions.",
        "distractor1": "are the procedures used by the electoral college to tally the presidential electoral votes.",
        "distractor2": "occur most often in mid-term elections.",
        "distractor3": "are the constitutional requirements that federal elections be held on the second Tuesday of November of even numbered years.",
        "distractor4": "have no real effect on how Congress supports the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about presidential bargaining is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Bargaining in the form of providing specific benefits for members of Congress is critical to creating presidential coalitions.",
        "distractor1": "The presidential bargaining takes a variety of forms.",
        "distractor2": "The president needs to bargain only with enough people to provide a majority.",
        "distractor3": "The president does not have to bargain with every member of Congress to receive support.",
        "distractor4": "Presidents ยน bargaining ability is enhanced by strong public approval. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the text, two strategies used successfully by President Reagan in achieving hisobjectives were",
        "correct_answer": "moving fast and setting priorities.",
        "distractor1": "moving slowly and letting Congress set the priorities.",
        "distractor2": "moving slowly and setting priorities.",
        "distractor3": "lying and forgetting.",
        "distractor4": "moving fast and letting Congress set the priorities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary goal of the president's legislative strategy is usually",
        "correct_answer": "to set the agenda.",
        "distractor1": "to win on all final votes.",
        "distractor2": "to win the support of all fellow partisans.",
        "distractor3": "block legislation he opposes.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's role in the legislative process",
        "correct_answer": "is especially important in influencing Congress's agenda.",
        "distractor1": "usually puts her/him in conflict with Congress.",
        "distractor2": "is usually minor because Congress operates independently from the president.",
        "distractor3": "is most effective in domestic policy.",
        "distractor4": "at least until 1995, has been to react to and modify congressional initiatives. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the president's constitutional powers as a maker of foreign policy is the power to",
        "correct_answer": "extend diplomatic recognition to foreign governments.",
        "distractor1": "ratify peace treaties.",
        "distractor2": "appropriate foreign-aid funds.",
        "distractor3": "declare war.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the president's powers as the nation's chief diplomat?",
        "correct_answer": "declaring war against an adversary",
        "distractor1": "negotiating executive agreements which do not require congressional approval",
        "distractor2": "mediating disputes between nations other than the United States",
        "distractor3": "extending diplomatic recognition to a nation",
        "distractor4": "negotiating treaties with other nations "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the role of the president as chief diplomat is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Senate approval of treaties negotiated by the president is almost automatic.",
        "distractor1": "Presidential diplomacy can involve negotiating conflicts between other nations and not the United States.",
        "distractor2": "The president has the sole power to negotiate treaties with other nations.",
        "distractor3": "In domestic policymaking, as chief diplomat, the president must rely principally on persuasion to lead.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are false. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Some believe the War Powers Resolution could be successfully overturned by the SupremeCourt because it",
        "correct_answer": "uses a legislative veto, which may violate the separation of powers.",
        "distractor1": "was vetoed by President Nixon.",
        "distractor2": "was not ratified within the constitutionally mandated seven -year period.",
        "distractor3": "interferes with the president's power to declare war.",
        "distractor4": "was really aimed at the Vietnam War only. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1991 Gulf War,",
        "correct_answer": "Congress passed a resolution authorizing the president to use force against Iraq.",
        "distractor1": "the War Powers Resolution was ignored.",
        "distractor2": "Congress cut off funding after sixty days.",
        "distractor3": "President Bush did not seek congressional support for the operation.",
        "distractor4": "Congress adopted a formal declaration of war against Iraq. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress's role in national security policy has typically included all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "initiation of policy.",
        "distractor1": "support or criticism of the president.",
        "distractor2": "oversight of the executive branch.",
        "distractor3": "to pass authorizations and appropriations for presidential actions.",
        "distractor4": "monitoring constituent opinions on national security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The typical member of Congress supports the president on national security roll-call votes",
        "correct_answer": "slightly more than half the time. ",
        "distractor1": "very rarely.",
        "distractor2": "about 75 percent of the time.",
        "distractor3": "almost always.",
        "distractor4": "only 38 percent of the time."
    },
    {
        "question": "References by commentators on the presidency to there being   two presidencies   refer to",
        "correct_answer": "national security and domestic policy. ",
        "distractor1": "the president as candidate and the president as elected leader.",
        "distractor2": "the first term and the second term of a president.",
        "distractor3": "what the president originally proposes to accomplish and what the president actually does accomplish.",
        "distractor4": "the differences between public and private presidential actions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about presidents going public is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Dwight Eisenhower was the first president to use presidential speeches to gain policy support.",
        "distractor1": "Presidents are not passive followers of public opinion.",
        "distractor2": "Presidents ยน appearances are often staged purely to obtain the public's attention.",
        "distractor3": "In recent years, presidents have averaged more than one public appearance every weekday of the year.",
        "distractor4": "John F. Kennedy was the first   television president.   "
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the White House Communications Office choreograph George W. Bush's addressfrom the Abraham Lincoln announcing the end of major combat operations in Iraq?",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above ",
        "distractor1": "They placed a   Mission Accomplished   banner over the president's head.",
        "distractor2": "They positioned the Abraham Lincoln so that the shoreline was not visible.",
        "distractor3": "They timed the even so that the sun would cast a favorable light on the president.",
        "distractor4": "The coordinated the shirts of the crewmembers."
    },
    {
        "question": "The higher the president stands in the polls,",
        "correct_answer": "the easier it is to persuade others to support presidential initiatives.",
        "distractor1": "the less support he needs in Congress.",
        "distractor2": "the shorter the president's coattails.",
        "distractor3": "the less need there is for presidential public appearances.",
        "distractor4": "the less likely he will initiate new policy ventures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Among recent presidents, the average approval ratings in the public opinion polls have been",
        "correct_answer": "higher at the beginning of the president's term than at the end.",
        "distractor1": "higher at the end of the president's term than at the beginning.",
        "distractor2": "over 75 percent.",
        "distractor3": "below 40 percent.",
        "distractor4": "slowly rising over the course of a president's term(s). "
    },
    {
        "question": "On average, those who identify with the president's party give approval more than ________percentage points higher than do those who identify with the opposition party.",
        "correct_answer": "40",
        "distractor1": "10",
        "distractor2": "20",
        "distractor3": "30",
        "distractor4": "50 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary factor influencing whether or not a person approves or disapproves of apresident's job performance is",
        "correct_answer": "political party identification.",
        "distractor1": "age.",
        "distractor2": "geographic location.",
        "distractor3": "gender.",
        "distractor4": "presidential personality. "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the base of presidential evaluations is the",
        "correct_answer": "predisposition of many people to support the president. ",
        "distractor1": "public's longstanding suspicion of excessive presidential power.",
        "distractor2": "lack of well-defined opinions among most people.",
        "distractor3": "predisposition of many people to be critical of government and politics in general.",
        "distractor4": "public's indifference to the president."
    },
    {
        "question": "The basic underpinning of approval or disapproval of a president is",
        "correct_answer": "political party identification.",
        "distractor1": "the president's ability to get her/his program passed by Congress.",
        "distractor2": "personality characteristics.",
        "distractor3": "the state of the economy.",
        "distractor4": "the behavior of the media. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to public opinion polls, presidents seem to be most popular",
        "correct_answer": "when they first enter office.",
        "distractor1": "just before they leave office.",
        "distractor2": "after they have introduced their first legislative package to Congress.",
        "distractor3": "after they leave office.",
        "distractor4": "during mid-term elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Changes in presidential approval levels appear to be due primarily to",
        "correct_answer": "the public's evaluation of how the president is handling policy areas.",
        "distractor1": "the president's personality.",
        "distractor2": "how the media treat the president.",
        "distractor3": "the financial elites ยน responses to presidential policies.",
        "distractor4": "how the president's policies affect people individually. "
    },
    {
        "question": "  Rally events  ",
        "correct_answer": "are specific and dramatic events that relate to international relations, directly involving the United States and the president.",
        "distractor1": "have an enduring impact on a president's public approval.",
        "distractor2": "involve economic upsurges that dramatically increase presidential popularity.",
        "distractor3": "have no effect on presidential popularity even though presidents use them for that purpose.",
        "distractor4": "occur frequently during a president's administration. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The surge in President George Bush's approval ratings during and immediately following theGulf War in 1991 was an example of",
        "correct_answer": "a rally event.",
        "distractor1": "the bandwagon effect.",
        "distractor2": "the bully pulpit.",
        "distractor3": "presidential coattails.",
        "distractor4": "a pocket veto. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ultimate weapon in the president's arsenal of resources to influence Congress is probably",
        "correct_answer": "mobilization of the public.",
        "distractor1": "media support.",
        "distractor2": "interest group support.",
        "distractor3": "her/his fundraising ability.",
        "distractor4": "the support of Wall Street and the Federal Reserve Board. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Presidential press conferences",
        "correct_answer": "are not very useful means of eliciting information.",
        "distractor1": "give the president a chance to be spontaneous.",
        "distractor2": "have not been used since the Nixon administration.",
        "distractor3": "are required by the Constitution without saying how often.",
        "distractor4": "are small, intimate meetings with the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's ________ serves as the principal conduit of information from the White Houseto the press on a daily basis.",
        "correct_answer": "press secretary",
        "distractor1": "vice president",
        "distractor2": "Chief of Staff",
        "distractor3": "Secretary of Information",
        "distractor4": "Domestic Policy Advisor "
    },
    {
        "question": "The individual who conducts daily press briefings and serves as a conduit of information fromthe White House is the",
        "correct_answer": "press secretary. ",
        "distractor1": "National Security Advisor.",
        "distractor2": "Minister of Information.",
        "distractor3": "president's secretary.",
        "distractor4": "Chief of Staff."
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the news coverage of the White House",
        "correct_answer": "focuses on the most visible layer of presidents ยน personal and official activities.",
        "distractor1": "is class analysis that seeks to explain which socio-economic groups are benefiting from or being injured by the latest policies.",
        "distractor2": "focuses on the fundamental processes operating in the executive branch.",
        "distractor3": "is concerned with the substance of policies.",
        "distractor4": "is concerned with foreign policy issues. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A large number of studies have concluded that the news media are",
        "correct_answer": "not biased on any systematic basis, and the news is typically characterized by neutrality.",
        "distractor1": "moderately biased toward liberal ideology.",
        "distractor2": "slightly biased toward the Democrats.",
        "distractor3": "strongly biased toward the Democrats.",
        "distractor4": "slightly biased toward the Republicans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "News coverage of presidents and their activities",
        "correct_answer": "is not systematically biased in any direction.",
        "distractor1": "usually focuses on the personality of the president.",
        "distractor2": "tends to focus on the substance of presidential policies.",
        "distractor3": "has a heavy liberal bias.",
        "distractor4": "is typically unfavorable toward the White House. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the presidency and democracy is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Concerns about a tyrannical presidency were prevalent in the Reagan administration due to his ability to impose his will on Congress.",
        "distractor1": "There is little prospect of the presidency being a threat to democracy.",
        "distractor2": "From the time the Constitution was written there has been a fear that the presidency would degenerate into a monarchy.",
        "distractor3": "Concerns over presidential power are generally closely related to policy views.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of today's federal debt was run up by government borrowing during",
        "correct_answer": "the 1980s.",
        "distractor1": "World War II.",
        "distractor2": "the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor3": "the Great Depression.",
        "distractor4": "the Cold War (1947-1989). "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately what percentage of the annual federal budget pays interest on the nationaldebt?",
        "correct_answer": "9",
        "distractor1": "13",
        "distractor2": "15",
        "distractor3": "21",
        "distractor4": "6 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT currently one of the major sources of federal revenue?",
        "correct_answer": "excise taxes",
        "distractor1": "personal income taxes",
        "distractor2": "social insurance taxes",
        "distractor3": "borrowing",
        "distractor4": "corporate income taxes "
    },
    {
        "question": "A(n) ________ is a policy document allocating taxes and expenditures, or a series of goals withprice tags attached.",
        "correct_answer": "budget ",
        "distractor1": "balance sheet",
        "distractor2": "procurement",
        "distractor3": "fiscal register",
        "distractor4": "apportionment"
    },
    {
        "question": "A budget is",
        "correct_answer": "a policy document allocating burdens (taxes) and benefits (expenditures).",
        "distractor1": "a blueprint for what the government should do.",
        "distractor2": "a policy determination of how much to spend.",
        "distractor3": "passed by the president's cabinet.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress was officially given the power to levy an income tax through the",
        "correct_answer": "Sixteenth Amendment.",
        "distractor1": "Supreme Court case of Pollock v. Farmer's Loan and Trust Co. (1895).",
        "distractor2": "revenue clause of the original Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "Internal Revenue Act.",
        "distractor4": "Balanced Budget Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT the responsibility of the Internal Revenue Service?",
        "correct_answer": "establishing the annual tax rates that Americans of different incomes must pay",
        "distractor1": "investigating and prosecuting thousands of errant taxpayers or nonpayers of federal taxes",
        "distractor2": "auditing more than one million taxpayers annually",
        "distractor3": "collecting the federal income tax",
        "distractor4": "All of these are the IRS's responsibilities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Income taxes",
        "correct_answer": "provide the largest source of federal revenue.",
        "distractor1": "were first used in 1915 after the Sixteenth Amendment was passed.",
        "distractor2": "were declared constitutional in Pollock v. Farmer's Loan and Trust Co.",
        "distractor3": "yield about 11 cents of every federal revenue dollar.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order of decreasing amounts, the sources of federal revenue include",
        "correct_answer": "individual income tax, social insurance receipts, borrowing and corporate income tax.",
        "distractor1": "individual income tax, excise tax, corporate income tax, and social insurance receipts.",
        "distractor2": "social insurance receipts, corporate income tax, individual income tax, and borrowing.",
        "distractor3": "corporate income taxes, personal income taxes, borrowing and social insurance taxes.",
        "distractor4": "borrowing, individual income tax, social insurance receipts, and corporate income tax. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Corporations today pay",
        "correct_answer": "income taxes which account for much less federal revenue than individual income taxes.",
        "distractor1": "income taxes which account for most federal revenue.",
        "distractor2": "income taxes which account for more federal revenue than individual income taxes.",
        "distractor3": "no income taxes.",
        "distractor4": "capital gains taxes and property taxes instead of income taxes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The income tax is generally progressive, meaning that",
        "correct_answer": "those with more income pay higher rates of tax on their income.",
        "distractor1": "it increases incrementally on an annual basis.",
        "distractor2": "those with more income pay more in taxes than those with less income.",
        "distractor3": "it is a newer form of taxation than excise and sales taxes.",
        "distractor4": "it is better than a flat tax. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social Security taxes are",
        "correct_answer": "paid for by employees and employers.",
        "distractor1": "paid for by employees only.",
        "distractor2": "paid for by employers only.",
        "distractor3": "taxes paid on Social Security benefits.",
        "distractor4": "levied and collected by state governments. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social insurance taxes",
        "correct_answer": "are earmarked for a specific purpose.",
        "distractor1": "have grown very little in recent years.",
        "distractor2": "go into the government's general money fund.",
        "distractor3": "are paid only by employers.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fastest growing source of federal revenue has been",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security taxes.",
        "distractor1": "fees for services.",
        "distractor2": "personal income taxes.",
        "distractor3": "borrowing.",
        "distractor4": "corporate income taxes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The government borrows money principally by",
        "correct_answer": "selling bonds.",
        "distractor1": "maintaining numerous departmental credit card accounts.",
        "distractor2": "printing more currency.",
        "distractor3": "obtaining loans from foreign governments.",
        "distractor4": "obtaining loans from the Federal Reserve. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who can purchase United States government bonds?",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above ",
        "distractor1": "financial institutions",
        "distractor2": "citizens",
        "distractor3": "corporations",
        "distractor4": "mutual funds"
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal debt",
        "correct_answer": "consists of all the money borrowed over the years by the national government and still outstanding.",
        "distractor1": "is money owed to foreign nations by the United States government when it imports more goods than it exports.",
        "distractor2": "is all money borrowed over the years by the federal government and owed to state governments.",
        "distractor3": "is the difference between the amount of annual tax receipts and government expenditures.",
        "distractor4": "is money owed by taxpayers to the United States government, but never paid. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal debt in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "has increased due to the budget deficit caused by the difference between revenues and expenditures.",
        "distractor1": "is the difference between federal government revenues and expenditures in a given year.",
        "distractor2": "was eliminated due to George W. Bush's efforts to balance the budget.",
        "distractor3": "consists of the interest that government must pay on the budget deficit.",
        "distractor4": "is just under $1,000,000,000. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Unlike state and local governments, the federal government is borrowing primarily for",
        "correct_answer": "its day-to-day expenses.",
        "distractor1": "future development needs.",
        "distractor2": "military defense.",
        "distractor3": "printing money.",
        "distractor4": "its capital needs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ are revenue losses attributable to provisions of the federal tax laws which allow aspecial exemption, exclusion, or deduction.",
        "correct_answer": "Tax expenditures ",
        "distractor1": "Tax dividends",
        "distractor2": "Fiscal seepages",
        "distractor3": "Treasury bills",
        "distractor4": "Tax reductions"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tax expenditures consist of",
        "correct_answer": "tax exemptions, deductions, and exclusions.",
        "distractor1": "the way taxes are spent by the federal government.",
        "distractor2": "taxes paid by employers for social insurance programs.",
        "distractor3": "direct grants-in-aid to individuals by the government.",
        "distractor4": "the amount of deficit caused by revenue shortfalls. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal income tax deduction for mortgage interest on an owner -occupied home is anexample of a",
        "correct_answer": "tax expenditure.",
        "distractor1": "tax rebate.",
        "distractor2": "negative income tax.",
        "distractor3": "federally guaranteed loan.",
        "distractor4": "tax refund. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a tax expenditure is",
        "correct_answer": "a tax deduction for the mortgage interest paid by homeowners.",
        "distractor1": "a lower tax rate for lower income families.",
        "distractor2": "direct government support of a charity.",
        "distractor3": "the social security system.",
        "distractor4": "the purchase of a Stealth Bomber by the Pentagon. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Office of Management and Budget estimates that the total tax expenditures is more than________ of the federal government's total receipts.",
        "correct_answer": "30 percent",
        "distractor1": "10 percent",
        "distractor2": "25 percent",
        "distractor3": "40 percent",
        "distractor4": "50 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Tax expenditures tend to most benefit",
        "correct_answer": "middle- and upper-income people and corporations.",
        "distractor1": "lower-income people and the poor.",
        "distractor2": "lower-middle class people and small businesses.",
        "distractor3": "the government.",
        "distractor4": "state and local governments and school districts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about President Reagan's 1981 tax cut is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Corporate taxes were increased.",
        "distractor1": "Taxes were indexed to the cost of living.",
        "distractor2": "Federal taxes were reduced by 25 percent.",
        "distractor3": "It provided new tax incentives for personal saving and investment.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about President Reagan's 1981 tax cut is TRUE?",
        "correct_answer": "It provided new tax incentives for personal saving and investment.",
        "distractor1": "It reduced the federal government's tax expenditures.",
        "distractor2": "It spread the tax burden more fairly among taxpayers.",
        "distractor3": "It led to a major reduction in the federal deficits.",
        "distractor4": "It helped curb inflation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was NOT a provision of President Reagan's 1985 tax simplificationprogram?",
        "correct_answer": "It increased the number of tax expenditures available to businesses.",
        "distractor1": "It removed several million low-income individuals from the tax rolls.",
        "distractor2": "It eliminated or reduced the value of many tax deductions.",
        "distractor3": "It reduced the number of tax brackets to two.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Beginning in 1985, federal income taxes were ________ to the cost of living, so thatgovernment no longer got a larger percentage when inflation pushed incomes into higherbrackets while the tax rates stayed the same.",
        "correct_answer": "indexed",
        "distractor1": "raised",
        "distractor2": "added",
        "distractor3": "lowered",
        "distractor4": "flat-rated "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Reagan's 1981 tax cuts were most beneficial to",
        "correct_answer": "high-income families.",
        "distractor1": "low-income families.",
        "distractor2": "the middle class.",
        "distractor3": "the government.",
        "distractor4": "the states "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1993, Congress agreed to President Clinton's proposal to",
        "correct_answer": "raise the income tax rate for families in the highest income brackets.",
        "distractor1": "cut Social Security expenditures.",
        "distractor2": "decrease the top corporate income tax rate.",
        "distractor3": "eliminate all energy taxes.",
        "distractor4": "establish national health insurance "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government's annual budget is now approximately",
        "correct_answer": "$2.75 trillion.",
        "distractor1": "$15 trillion.",
        "distractor2": "$775 billion.",
        "distractor3": "$12 trillion.",
        "distractor4": "$11.3 trillion. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to most other countries with developed economies, the national, state, and localgovernments in the United States tax",
        "correct_answer": "less.",
        "distractor1": "about twice as heavily.",
        "distractor2": "about one and a half times as much per capita.",
        "distractor3": "about four times as heavily.",
        "distractor4": "at about the same rate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal budget consumes ________ of America's gross domestic product.",
        "correct_answer": "50 percent",
        "distractor1": "20 percent",
        "distractor2": "30 percent",
        "distractor3": "25 percent",
        "distractor4": "12 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order of decreasing amounts, federal expenditures include",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above ",
        "distractor1": "national defense, interest on the national debt, and direct payments to individuals.",
        "distractor2": "interest on the national debt, national defense, and direct payments to individuals.",
        "distractor3": "national defense, direct payments to individuals, and state and local grants.",
        "distractor4": "direct payments to individuals, national defense, and interest on the national debt."
    },
    {
        "question": "America's national, state and local governments spend an amount equal to ________ of theGDP.",
        "correct_answer": "20 percent.",
        "distractor1": "30 percent.",
        "distractor2": "50 percent.",
        "distractor3": "25 percent.",
        "distractor4": "12 percent. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1950s and early 1960s, over half the federal budget was spent every year on",
        "correct_answer": "the Department of Defense.",
        "distractor1": "agricultural subsidies and programs.",
        "distractor2": "Medicare.",
        "distractor3": "the interstate highway program.",
        "distractor4": "Social Security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "From the mid-1960s to the early 1980s, the biggest change in government spending was the",
        "correct_answer": "increase in social service expenditures and decline in defense spending.",
        "distractor1": "ratification and implementation of the Twenty-eighth Amendment, the Balanced Budget Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "abandonment of the gold standard and the creation of the Federal Reserve System.",
        "distractor3": "growth of new budgeting techniques such as zero-based budgeting.",
        "distractor4": "elimination of tax expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The military industrial complex refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the close relationship between defense officials and the corporations that supply their hardware needs.",
        "distractor1": "the global network of bases that the Department of Defense maintains.",
        "distractor2": "the competition between the military and civilian industries for government dollars.",
        "distractor3": "the government-owned industries that manufacture military weapons and large equipment.",
        "distractor4": "the Pentagon and the buildings that surround it. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The budget of the Department of Defense",
        "correct_answer": "decreased in the 1990s.",
        "distractor1": "constitutes the bulk of the   uncontrollable   expenditures of the United States budget.",
        "distractor2": "constitutes over half of all federal expenditures.",
        "distractor3": "is the driving force in the expansion of the federal budget.",
        "distractor4": "has increased despite the end of the Cold War. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The purchasing of military hardware is known as",
        "correct_answer": "procurement.",
        "distractor1": "regalia.",
        "distractor2": "requisitioning.",
        "distractor3": "appropriations.",
        "distractor4": "mobilization. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The biggest expenditure in the federal budget today is",
        "correct_answer": "income security programs.",
        "distractor1": "foreign aid programs.",
        "distractor2": "welfare programs for the poor.",
        "distractor3": "interest on the debt.",
        "distractor4": "defense. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Social Security Act, which set up the Social Security system, was passed in",
        "correct_answer": "1935.",
        "distractor1": "1913.",
        "distractor2": "1865.",
        "distractor3": "1962.",
        "distractor4": "1929. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Social Security Act was passed under the administration of President",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt.",
        "distractor1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower.",
        "distractor2": "Herbert Hoover.",
        "distractor3": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor4": "Abraham Lincoln. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1965, ________ was added to the Social Security program to provide hospital and physiciancoverage to the elderly.",
        "correct_answer": "Medicare",
        "distractor1": "Medplan",
        "distractor2": "Healthmark",
        "distractor3": "Medicaid",
        "distractor4": "disability "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicare",
        "correct_answer": "provides both hospital and physician coverage to the elderly. ",
        "distractor1": "is given only to those who do not have private insurance.",
        "distractor2": "is administered separately from the social security system.",
        "distractor3": "provides only hospital coverage to the poor.",
        "distractor4": "is the most expensive of all the welfare programs, providing basic medical care for the poor."
    },
    {
        "question": "The biggest slice of the federal budget pie belongs to",
        "correct_answer": "income security expenditures.",
        "distractor1": "law enforcement.",
        "distractor2": "national defense.",
        "distractor3": "education aid.",
        "distractor4": "health expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By 1990, the Social Security system was financed by a payroll tax of",
        "correct_answer": "over 15 percent.",
        "distractor1": "2 percent.",
        "distractor2": "5 percent.",
        "distractor3": "7.5 percent.",
        "distractor4": "10 percent. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A major feature of incremental budgeting is that it",
        "correct_answer": "provides small increases in the current budget over the previous year's budget.",
        "distractor1": "greatly inflates government spending each year.",
        "distractor2": "fragments the budget into many small items, making it hard to plan a unified budget.",
        "distractor3": "reduces current budgets by small amounts over successive years.",
        "distractor4": "reevaluates the budgetary base on which past budgets were built. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of incremental budgeting is",
        "correct_answer": "giving an agency a little more than it had last year.",
        "distractor1": "reviewing an agency's budget to establish a lower base.",
        "distractor2": "Carter's zero-based budgeting.",
        "distractor3": "reducing an agency's budget a little each year.",
        "distractor4": "breaking a budget into its component parts and reviewing each part individually. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most prevalent model of budgetary decision making in practice is",
        "correct_answer": "incrementalism.",
        "distractor1": "program-planning budgeting.",
        "distractor2": "zero-based budgeting.",
        "distractor3": "line-item budgeting.",
        "distractor4": "rational party bargaining. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT associated with incremental budgeting?",
        "correct_answer": "An agency or program must prove it still merits its very existence every year.",
        "distractor1": "Most of the budget debate and attention is over an increase in the agency's funding.",
        "distractor2": "Agencies and programs tend to safely assume they will receive at least what they had last year.",
        "distractor3": "The budget for any given agency tends to grow a bit every year.",
        "distractor4": "Agencies often pad their budgets a little bit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Budget items mandated by law or by a previous obligation are known as",
        "correct_answer": "uncontrollable expenditures.",
        "distractor1": "increments.",
        "distractor2": "fiscal mandates.",
        "distractor3": "bearer bonds.",
        "distractor4": "procurements. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social Security payments are an example of a(n)",
        "correct_answer": "entitlement. ",
        "distractor1": "increment.",
        "distractor2": "indexing.",
        "distractor3": "apportionment.",
        "distractor4": "controllable expenditure."
    },
    {
        "question": "An   uncontrollable   expenditure in the federal budget is defined as",
        "correct_answer": "an expenditure that is required by current law or a previous government obligation to people automatically eligible for some benefit.",
        "distractor1": "expenditures exceeding revenues so as to require borrowing to cover the difference.",
        "distractor2": "an annual incremental increase in the cost of a program.",
        "distractor3": "one in which more money must be appropriated to handle a national crisis.",
        "distractor4": "the government's allowance for meeting budget requests. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social Security programs, interest on the national debt, and military pensions are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "uncontrollable expenditures.",
        "distractor1": "tax expenditures.",
        "distractor2": "revenue sources.",
        "distractor3": "tax loopholes.",
        "distractor4": "incremental expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The biggest uncontrollable expenditure in the federal budget is",
        "correct_answer": "the Social Security system. ",
        "distractor1": "government retirement benefits.",
        "distractor2": "interest on the national debt.",
        "distractor3": "veterans aid.",
        "distractor4": "national defense spending."
    },
    {
        "question": "An estimated ________ of the federal budget is considered uncontrollable, unless Congresschanges a law or existing benefit levels.",
        "correct_answer": "two-thirds",
        "distractor1": "80 percent",
        "distractor2": "one-half",
        "distractor3": "one-third",
        "distractor4": "one-fifth "
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately what percentage of the federal budget is uncontrollable?",
        "correct_answer": "two-thirds",
        "distractor1": "one-fourth",
        "distractor2": "almost all of it",
        "distractor3": "one-half",
        "distractor4": "one-third "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ultimate power to determine how much the government will tax and spend, and what itwill spend taxes for, lies with",
        "correct_answer": "Congress.",
        "distractor1": "the Treasury Department.",
        "distractor2": "the courts.",
        "distractor3": "the president.",
        "distractor4": "the bureaucracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the House of Representatives, it is the ________ Committee that writes tax codes, subject tothe approval of Congress as a whole.",
        "correct_answer": "Ways and Means",
        "distractor1": "Appropriations",
        "distractor2": "Budget",
        "distractor3": "Revenue",
        "distractor4": "Finance "
    },
    {
        "question": "Agencies invariably pad their budget requests because",
        "correct_answer": "they want the almost inevitable budget cuts to be bearable.",
        "distractor1": "Congress would view a lower request as a sign of weakness.",
        "distractor2": "it is an accepted part of zero-based budgeting.",
        "distractor3": "their constituencies expect more benefits.",
        "distractor4": "cost overruns almost always put them over budget. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Senate, the ________ Committee is responsible for writing tax codes, subject to theapproval of Congress as a whole.",
        "correct_answer": "Finance ",
        "distractor1": "Revenue",
        "distractor2": "Budget",
        "distractor3": "Appropriations",
        "distractor4": "Ways and Means"
    },
    {
        "question": "The budget cycle begins in the executive branch ________ months before the fiscal year begins.",
        "correct_answer": "19",
        "distractor1": "11",
        "distractor2": "three",
        "distractor3": "seven",
        "distractor4": "24 or more "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Director of the Office of Management and Budget",
        "correct_answer": "is a presidential appointee requiring approval of the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "is a career official.",
        "distractor2": "is elected by the Council of Economic Advisors.",
        "distractor3": "is a congressional appointee.",
        "distractor4": "is appointed by the Senate Finance Committee. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is responsible for supervising preparation of the federal budget and advising thepresident on budgetary matters.",
        "correct_answer": "Office of Management and Budget",
        "distractor1": "Treasury Department",
        "distractor2": "Senate Finance Committee",
        "distractor3": "General Accounting Office",
        "distractor4": "Bureau of the Budget "
    },
    {
        "question": "The heads of executive agencies send their budget requests to the",
        "correct_answer": "Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor1": "Congressional tax committees.",
        "distractor2": "president.",
        "distractor3": "Treasury Department.",
        "distractor4": "Congressional Budget Office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Agencies ยน behavior and budgets are audited, monitored, and evaluated for Congress by the",
        "correct_answer": "General Accounting Office. ",
        "distractor1": "Congressional Budget Office.",
        "distractor2": "president.",
        "distractor3": "Internal Revenue Service.",
        "distractor4": "Office of Management and Budget."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Office of Management and Budget parcels out money to government agencies and isaccountable to",
        "correct_answer": "the president.",
        "distractor1": "the Internal Revenue Service.",
        "distractor2": "Congress.",
        "distractor3": "the secretary of the treasury.",
        "distractor4": "the Congressional Budget Office. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The OMB is one of the few government agencies created by the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "The OMB advises the president on budgetary matters.",
        "distractor2": "The OMB supervises preparation of the federal budget.",
        "distractor3": "Government agencies send their budget estimates to the OMB.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Once the Office of Management and Budget has prepared the federal budget,",
        "correct_answer": "the president makes revisions and submits it to Congress.",
        "distractor1": "it is sent to the Treasury Department for implementation.",
        "distractor2": "it is either signed into law or vetoed by the president.",
        "distractor3": "Congress must vote it up or down as a package within ten days.",
        "distractor4": "it immediately becomes law. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Constitution, all federal appropriations must be authorized by",
        "correct_answer": "Congress.",
        "distractor1": "the General Accounting Office.",
        "distractor2": "the Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor3": "the president.",
        "distractor4": "the secretary of the treasury. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 set up all of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "the Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor1": "a Budget Committee in each house of Congress.",
        "distractor2": "the Congressional Budget Office.",
        "distractor3": "a fixed budget calendar mandated by law.",
        "distractor4": "both A and B "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the important purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 is to",
        "correct_answer": "force Congress to consider the budget as a whole rather than in terms of individual appropriations.",
        "distractor1": "require the federal government to balance its budget.",
        "distractor2": "restore budgetary control to the appropriations committees and subcommittees.",
        "distractor3": "delegate effective budgetary authority to the president.",
        "distractor4": "give Congress almost exclusive control over the federal budget. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the Congressional Budget Office is to",
        "correct_answer": "advise Congress on the consequences of its budget decisions.",
        "distractor1": "act as a liaison with interest groups.",
        "distractor2": "prepare Congress ยน own operating budget for salaries and supplies.",
        "distractor3": "receive reports and recommendations from committees.",
        "distractor4": "advise the president on congressional priorities in the budget. "
    },
    {
        "question": "To set a limit on total government spending, both houses of Congress are required to pass a(n)________ every April, binding Congress to a total expenditure level, or bottom line, of allfederal spending for all programs.",
        "correct_answer": "budget resolution",
        "distractor1": "budget",
        "distractor2": "omnibus appropriations package",
        "distractor3": "circumscription bill",
        "distractor4": "authorization bill "
    },
    {
        "question": "A budget resolution",
        "correct_answer": "sets limits on expenditures based on revenue projections. ",
        "distractor1": "revises program authorizations to achieve required savings.",
        "distractor2": "resolves the differences between House and Senate versions of the budget.",
        "distractor3": "is an act of Congress that establishes a discretionary government program or an entitlement.",
        "distractor4": "must be passed to actually fund programs established by authorization bills."
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress attempts to bind itself to a total expenditure level that should form the bottom line ofall federal spending for all programs by passing",
        "correct_answer": "a budget resolution.",
        "distractor1": "a zero-based binding resolution.",
        "distractor2": "a budget reconciliation.",
        "distractor3": "an appropriations bill.",
        "distractor4": "an authorization bill. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Budget ________ revises program authorizations to achieve required savings.",
        "correct_answer": "reconciliation ",
        "distractor1": "impoundment",
        "distractor2": "realignment",
        "distractor3": "closure",
        "distractor4": "appropriation"
    },
    {
        "question": "A budget reconciliation",
        "correct_answer": "revises program authorizations to achieve required savings.",
        "distractor1": "reconciles the differences between House and Senate versions of the budget.",
        "distractor2": "is an act of Congress that establishes a discretionary government program or an entitlement.",
        "distractor3": "must be passed to actually fund programs established by authorization bills.",
        "distractor4": "sets limits on expenditures based on revenue projections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An ________ bill is an act of Congress that establishes a discretionary government program oran entitlement, or that continues or changes such programs.",
        "correct_answer": "authorization",
        "distractor1": "omnibus",
        "distractor2": "impoundment",
        "distractor3": "appropriations",
        "distractor4": "enabling "
    },
    {
        "question": "To actually fund a program, Congress must pass an ________ bill.",
        "correct_answer": "appropriations",
        "distractor1": "authorization",
        "distractor2": "expenditure",
        "distractor3": "omnibus",
        "distractor4": "impoundment "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would be a specific example of an appropriations bill?",
        "correct_answer": "a bill funding the Department of the Interior for the fiscal year",
        "distractor1": "Congress voting to discontinue the federal income tax",
        "distractor2": "a budget resolution passed by both Houses of Congress",
        "distractor3": "a bill to continue the space shuttle program for another five years",
        "distractor4": "a bill establishing a national health insurance system "
    },
    {
        "question": "Failing to meet its own budget timetable, Congress has frequently resorted to ________, whichare laws that allow agencies to spend at the previous year's level.",
        "correct_answer": "continuing resolutions",
        "distractor1": "reconciliations",
        "distractor2": "revenue extensions",
        "distractor3": "appropriations",
        "distractor4": "retrenchments "
    },
    {
        "question": "An authorization bill",
        "correct_answer": "establishes, continues, or changes a discretionary program or an entitlement. ",
        "distractor1": "provides the funding for discretionary programs.",
        "distractor2": "authorizes the president to spend specific line-item amounts in the final budget.",
        "distractor3": "covers only one year at a time.",
        "distractor4": "sets the maximum amount that may be spent for entitlement programs."
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to actually fund programs established by authorization bills, Congress must pass",
        "correct_answer": "an appropriations bill.",
        "distractor1": "a budget resolution.",
        "distractor2": "a budget reconciliation.",
        "distractor3": "authorization vouchers.",
        "distractor4": "a continuing resolution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act called for the president to order________, if Congress failed to meet specific deficit-reduction goals.",
        "correct_answer": "sequestrations ",
        "distractor1": "reconciliations",
        "distractor2": "defunding directives",
        "distractor3": "re-authorizations",
        "distractor4": "continuing resolutions"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act",
        "correct_answer": "mandated maximum allowable deficit levels for each year until 1993, when the budget was to be balanced.",
        "distractor1": "required automatic budget cuts, primarily in the area of defense.",
        "distractor2": "froze all United States government expenditures at their 1988 levels for three years in an effort to eliminate the budget deficits.",
        "distractor3": "allowed agencies to spend at the previous year's level.",
        "distractor4": "called for tax increases to pay for federal spending. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1990, Congress split discretionary spending into three categories. Which of the followingwas NOT one of the three categories?",
        "correct_answer": "debt service",
        "distractor1": "domestic",
        "distractor2": "defense",
        "distractor3": "international",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; debt service is a part of domestic expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Near the end of 1990, Congress approved a major change in the making of budget policy thatshifted the focus from cutting spending to",
        "correct_answer": "controlling increases in spending.",
        "distractor1": "eliminating government programs.",
        "distractor2": "increasing taxes.",
        "distractor3": "increasing non-tax revenues.",
        "distractor4": "controlling the size of the deficit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "By 2002, the budget deficit had increased again due to",
        "correct_answer": "the first Iraq war.",
        "distractor1": "decreased tax revenues.",
        "distractor2": "income tax cut of 2001.",
        "distractor3": "both A and B",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Some economists argue that less affluent voters will always use their votes to support publicpolicies that",
        "correct_answer": "redistribute benefits from the rich to the poor.",
        "distractor1": "cut all tax rates.",
        "distractor2": "favor large defense budgets.",
        "distractor3": "keep taxes low.",
        "distractor4": "increase spending on foreign aid and international programs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ are not unwilling victims of big government and its big taxes in a democracy, theyare at least its co-conspirators.",
        "correct_answer": "Citizens",
        "distractor1": "Members of Congress",
        "distractor2": "Presidents",
        "distractor3": "Bureaucrats",
        "distractor4": "Political parties "
    },
    {
        "question": "Research has found that the public sector expands principally",
        "correct_answer": "in response to changes in economic and social conditions that affect the public's preferences for government activity.",
        "distractor1": "as a result of liberal political parties controlling the government.",
        "distractor2": "as a result of Federal Reserve Board monetary policies influencing interest rates and currency reserves.",
        "distractor3": "as a function of increased international economic competition.",
        "distractor4": "in response to the perceived need for increased defense expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Economists Allen Meltzer and Scott Richard argue that the cost of government grows because",
        "correct_answer": "people in a democracy use the government to secure benefits.",
        "distractor1": "democracy works best at the federal level.",
        "distractor2": "big government is necessary for the maintenance of a capitalist system.",
        "distractor3": "democracy is by nature an expensive form of government to operate.",
        "distractor4": "iron triangles pressure the government to expand their favored programs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Studies have found that most Americans",
        "correct_answer": "are satisfied with the help received from bureaucrats.",
        "distractor1": "dislike bureaucrats.",
        "distractor2": "are indifferent about bureaucracies and bureaucrats.",
        "distractor3": "actually like bureaucracies.",
        "distractor4": "want the government bureaucracy dismantled. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the size of bureaucracies is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "As a percentage of America's total work force, federal government employment has been growing.",
        "distractor1": "State and local public employees far outnumber civilian federal government employees.",
        "distractor2": "Almost all the growth in the number of public employees has occurred in state and local governments.",
        "distractor3": "Federal government employment amounts to about three percent of all civilian jobs.",
        "distractor4": "None of the above; all of the above statements are TRUE. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As a percentage of the total work force, federal government employment is",
        "correct_answer": "declining.",
        "distractor1": "rapidly becoming greater than employment in the private sector.",
        "distractor2": "greater than state and local government employment.",
        "distractor3": "rising.",
        "distractor4": "stabilizing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The classic conception of a bureaucracy was advanced by ________, who argued that thebureaucracy was a   rational   way for a modern society to conduct its business.",
        "correct_answer": "Max Weber",
        "distractor1": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "distractor2": "John Locke",
        "distractor3": "Charles L. Schultze",
        "distractor4": "James Madison "
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a hierarchical authority structure, Max Weber argued that a bureaucracyinvolves all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "an incentive system.",
        "distractor1": "extensive rules.",
        "distractor2": "task specialization.",
        "distractor3": "the merit principle.",
        "distractor4": "hierarchical authority structure. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Weberian theory of bureaucracies views them in the most positive light as",
        "correct_answer": "hierarchical.",
        "distractor1": "acquisitive.",
        "distractor2": "inefficient.",
        "distractor3": "monopolistic.",
        "distractor4": "democratic. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would NOT be considered part of the Weberian model of bureaucracy?",
        "correct_answer": "decentralized authority structure",
        "distractor1": "task specialization",
        "distractor2": "extensive rules",
        "distractor3": "impersonality",
        "distractor4": "A and D only "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about bureaucracies is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Government bureaucracies have been shown to be less efficient and effective than private bureaucracies.",
        "distractor1": "Bureaucracies are simply a way of organizing people to perform work.",
        "distractor2": "The vast majority of tasks carried out by governments are noncontroversial.",
        "distractor3": "Bureaucracies receive very little credit when they function well.",
        "distractor4": "Bureaucracies are prevalent in all levels of government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ employs about one -fourth of all federal civilian workers, more than any otherdepartment or agency.",
        "correct_answer": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor1": "Department of Education",
        "distractor2": "Department of Health and Human Services",
        "distractor3": "Department of Justice",
        "distractor4": "Department of Labor "
    },
    {
        "question": "There are roughly ________ civilian and military federal government employees",
        "correct_answer": "4,000,000",
        "distractor1": "800,000",
        "distractor2": "3,000,000",
        "distractor3": "2,100,000",
        "distractor4": "500,000 "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is a hiring and promotion system based on knowing the right people, working in anelection campaign, making large political donations, and/or having the right connections towin jobs with the government.",
        "correct_answer": "The patronage system",
        "distractor1": "The federal Civil Service",
        "distractor2": "The bureaucracy",
        "distractor3": "The golden gate",
        "distractor4": "Administrative discretion "
    },
    {
        "question": "Patronage is a hiring and promotion system based on",
        "correct_answer": "knowing the right people.",
        "distractor1": "civil service exams.",
        "distractor2": "talent and skill.",
        "distractor3": "the Pendelton Act.",
        "distractor4": "the merit principle. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Until the late-nineteenth century, most government employees got their jobs through",
        "correct_answer": "the patronage system.",
        "distractor1": "the merit principle.",
        "distractor2": "hereditary preferences.",
        "distractor3": "civil service testing.",
        "distractor4": "a lottery system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ Act was passed partly as a memorial to the memory of President James Garfield,who was assassinated in 1881.",
        "correct_answer": "Pendleton Civil Service",
        "distractor1": "Treason",
        "distractor2": "Voting Rights",
        "distractor3": "Hatch",
        "distractor4": "Interstate Commerce "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pendleton Act established the",
        "correct_answer": "federal civil service.",
        "distractor1": "patronage system.",
        "distractor2": "Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor3": "plum book.",
        "distractor4": "Interstate Commerce Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The rationale for all civil service systems is based on",
        "correct_answer": "the merit principle.",
        "distractor1": "patronage.",
        "distractor2": "the Hatch Act.",
        "distractor3": "the plum book.",
        "distractor4": "voluntary service. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hatch Act, passed in 1940,",
        "correct_answer": "prohibits federal civil service employees from active participation in partisan politics.",
        "distractor1": "established the patronage system for federal employment.",
        "distractor2": "prohibited the president from firing the heads of independent executive agencies.",
        "distractor3": "required the publication of the plum book.",
        "distractor4": "established the federal civil service. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Once hired into the federal bureaucracy, a person is assigned a ________ rating, whichdetermines one's salary range.",
        "correct_answer": "General Schedule",
        "distractor1": "Federal Register",
        "distractor2": "Weber",
        "distractor3": "step ladder",
        "distractor4": "plum book "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal civil service was created by",
        "correct_answer": "the Pendleton Act. ",
        "distractor1": "Article IV of the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "an executive order of President Arthur.",
        "distractor3": "the Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor4": "the merit principle."
    },
    {
        "question": "The rationale for the civil service rests on the",
        "correct_answer": "desire to create a nonpartisan government service and promotion on the basis of merit.",
        "distractor1": "goal of centralizing government employment at the federal level.",
        "distractor2": "General Schedule rating system for patronage appointees.",
        "distractor3": "the need to separate military institutions from civilian institutions to prevent undue military influence.",
        "distractor4": "need for job replacements when a new party comes to power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal employees are prohibited from active participation in partisan politics through the",
        "correct_answer": "Hatch Act.",
        "distractor1": "Twenty-fifth Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "Pendleton Act.",
        "distractor3": "Supreme Court ruling in Democratic National Committee v. Hayes.",
        "distractor4": "merit system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a legitimate criticism of the federal civil service?",
        "correct_answer": "Firing incompetents is extremely difficult.",
        "distractor1": "Workers are not protected against political firings.",
        "distractor2": "It does not operate on the merit principle.",
        "distractor3": "Too many federal civil servants are actively involved in partisan politics.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would be included in a plum book?",
        "correct_answer": "Cabinet secretaries ",
        "distractor1": "doctors at a Veteran's Administration hospital",
        "distractor2": "postal carriers",
        "distractor3": "the phone numbers of a Congress member's sex partners",
        "distractor4": "Senate committee chairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the hiring and firing of civil servants is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Due to the merit system, it is easy to fire incompetent civil servants.",
        "distractor1": "The Office of Personnel Management has elaborate rules about hiring, promotion, and firing of civil servants.",
        "distractor2": "The top of the civil service is composed of about 9,000 members of the Senior Executive Service.",
        "distractor3": "Once hired, civil servants are assigned a General Schedule ranging from GS-1 to GS-18.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The plum book lists",
        "correct_answer": "top federal jobs available by Presidential appointment.",
        "distractor1": "all federal contracts available for bid.",
        "distractor2": "all civil service jobs above GS-12.",
        "distractor3": "job openings in the prestigious Office of Personnel Management.",
        "distractor4": "appeals filed with the Merit Systems Protection Board. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about plum book appointees is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Plum book appointees are often instrumental in changing and reforming their agencies.",
        "distractor1": "Most presidents seek appointees with sympathy for similar policy positions.",
        "distractor2": "Ambassadorship appointments often go to large campaign contributors.",
        "distractor3": "Presidents often consider sex, region, and race in making plum book appointments.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about presidential appointees to bureaucracies?",
        "correct_answer": "They must be recommended by the Office of Personnel Management's   rule of three.  ",
        "distractor1": "They often do not know their own agency subordinates very well, much less people in other agencies.",
        "distractor2": "As political appointees, they are often unaccustomed to the administrative routines, budget cycles, and legal complexities of their agencies or departments.",
        "distractor3": "They tend to spend fewer years in their positions than those in the civil service.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Hugh Heclo, the plum book system of recruiting federal employees tends toresult in the appointment of",
        "correct_answer": "administrators who do not stay long enough in their appointed position to be effective.",
        "distractor1": "talented experts with proven party loyalty.",
        "distractor2": "people with access to the Internet, but not necessarily the most qualified people.",
        "distractor3": "senior civil servants to sensitive posts.",
        "distractor4": "large numbers of women and minorities, just as it was intended to do. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Cabinet department is charged with overseeing the nation's national resources?",
        "correct_answer": "Interior ",
        "distractor1": "Homeland Security",
        "distractor2": "Environmental Protection Agency",
        "distractor3": "Defense",
        "distractor4": "State"
    },
    {
        "question": "The real work of a Cabinet department is done",
        "correct_answer": "in the bureaus. ",
        "distractor1": "by the entire Cabinet.",
        "distractor2": "by the president's staff.",
        "distractor3": "by the undersecretaries.",
        "distractor4": "by the secretary."
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest federal agency based on dollars spent is the",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security Administration. ",
        "distractor1": "Department of Defense.",
        "distractor2": "Department of Justice.",
        "distractor3": "State Department.",
        "distractor4": "Department of Health and Human Services."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the newest government agency?",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security Administration",
        "distractor1": "Drug Enforcement Agency",
        "distractor2": "Department of Health and Human Services",
        "distractor3": "Drug Interdiction Agency",
        "distractor4": "Cyberspace Commission "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Cabinet department that has the largest budget is the Department of",
        "correct_answer": "Health and Human Services.",
        "distractor1": "Defense.",
        "distractor2": "Commerce.",
        "distractor3": "the Treasury.",
        "distractor4": "Education. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Bureaus in the federal bureaucracy are also known as all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "a department.",
        "distractor1": "an administration.",
        "distractor2": "an office.",
        "distractor3": "a service.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Interstate Commerce Commission and the Federal Reserve Board are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "independent regulatory agencies.",
        "distractor1": "dependent presidential boards.",
        "distractor2": "government corporations.",
        "distractor3": "Cabinet departments.",
        "distractor4": "independent executive agencies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about independent regulatory commissions is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Regulatory commission members may not be drawn from the ranks of present or former employees of the regulated industry.",
        "distractor1": "Regulatory commission members cannot be fired by the president.",
        "distractor2": "Regulatory commissions consist of five to ten members.",
        "distractor3": "Regulatory commission members are appointed by the president and confirmed by the Senate.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The General Services Administration and the National Aeronautical and Space Administrationare examples of",
        "correct_answer": "independent executive agencies. ",
        "distractor1": "government corporations.",
        "distractor2": "independent regulatory agencies.",
        "distractor3": "Cabinet departments.",
        "distractor4": "presidential administrative agencies."
    },
    {
        "question": "Independent regulatory agencies have",
        "correct_answer": "powerful rule-making, dispute-settling, and enforcement authority.",
        "distractor1": "complete independence from the president, but their policymakers are appointed by Congress.",
        "distractor2": "no real enforcement power any more, and remain today as part of the federal government only in a ceremonial role.",
        "distractor3": "no formal ties to either the president or the Congress.",
        "distractor4": "governing commissions composed of long-time federal Civil Service employees. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Amtrak and the United States Postal Service are examples of",
        "correct_answer": "government corporations.",
        "distractor1": "independent executive agencies.",
        "distractor2": "Cabinet departments.",
        "distractor3": "executive commercial agencies.",
        "distractor4": "independent regulatory agencies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government corporations",
        "correct_answer": "provide services and charge for them.",
        "distractor1": "operate an airline, manufacture steel, and provide health insurance.",
        "distractor2": "tend to be captured by interest groups.",
        "distractor3": "are independent regulatory agencies.",
        "distractor4": "sell stock and pay dividends. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An obstacle to the successful implementation of public policy is",
        "correct_answer": "unclear policy goals and poorly designed policies.",
        "distractor1": "the failure of Congress to pass authorizing legislation.",
        "distractor2": "the over-specialization of civil service employees.",
        "distractor3": "competition between the private and public sectors.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Once a policy decision has been made, such as by passing a legislative act or issuing anexecutive order, the bureaucracy is responsible for",
        "correct_answer": "its implementation.",
        "distractor1": "its ratification.",
        "distractor2": "its deregulation.",
        "distractor3": "funding it.",
        "distractor4": "judging its merits. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The main job of federal bureaucrats is to",
        "correct_answer": "implement and regulate government policies. ",
        "distractor1": "advise the president and Cabinet on internal affairs.",
        "distractor2": "countervail the power of private corporations, especially monopolies.",
        "distractor3": "compete with the private sector for monopoly power.",
        "distractor4": "protect the interests of their constituencies."
    },
    {
        "question": "Creating new agencies, developing guidelines, and coordinating resources to achieve a policygoal is called",
        "correct_answer": "implementation.",
        "distractor1": "bureaucratization.",
        "distractor2": "regulation.",
        "distractor3": "actualization.",
        "distractor4": "policymaking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason that policy implementation sometimes breaks down inthe federal bureaucracy?",
        "correct_answer": "lack of standard operating procedures",
        "distractor1": "fragmentation of responsibilities",
        "distractor2": "lack of clarity in the original policy decision",
        "distractor3": "faulty program design",
        "distractor4": "lack of resources "
    },
    {
        "question": "Vigorous disputes over the implementation of Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972in regard to funding for women's athletic programs arose primarily due to",
        "correct_answer": "lack of clarity in the original policy decision.",
        "distractor1": "faulty program design.",
        "distractor2": "adherence to administrative routine.",
        "distractor3": "fragmentation of responsibilities.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Section 844 of Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972",
        "correct_answer": "was vaguely written, eventually resulting in scores of court cases.",
        "distractor1": "was declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "specifically prohibits sex discrimination in college sports.",
        "distractor3": "was supported by most colleges and universities.",
        "distractor4": "was interpreted by Congress to exclude college football. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A major complaint of the Food and Drug Administration is",
        "correct_answer": "the shortage of personnel. ",
        "distractor1": "its lack of clarity.",
        "distractor2": "the fragmentation of responsibilities.",
        "distractor3": "that there is no administrative discretion.",
        "distractor4": "that too much food is contaminated by dirt and rodents."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about standard operating procedures?",
        "correct_answer": "Each federal department and agency has a plum book which lists its standard operating procedures.",
        "distractor1": "They provide routine rules to help bureaucrats make numerous everyday decisions.",
        "distractor2": "They can sometimes be so routinized that they are difficult to change even in the face of changing circumstances.",
        "distractor3": "They are referred to as   red tape   by those who find them burdensome.",
        "distractor4": "They are used by street-level bureaucrats. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard operating procedures",
        "correct_answer": "save time and bring uniformity to complex organizations.",
        "distractor1": "usually prove to be unjust and discriminatory when followed to the letter.",
        "distractor2": "were waived by the Reagan Administration in an effort to make the bureaucracy more flexible and customize the solutions to problems.",
        "distractor3": "give authority to administrative actors to select among various responses to a given problem.",
        "distractor4": "are frustrating and inappropriate in addressing most situations. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard operating procedures accomplish all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "reduce red tape.",
        "distractor1": "bring uniformity to complex organizations.",
        "distractor2": "save time.",
        "distractor3": "make personnel interchangeable.",
        "distractor4": "treat citizens equally, regardless of class or race. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is the authority of administrative actors to select among various responses to a givenproblem.",
        "correct_answer": "Administrative discretion",
        "distractor1": "Standard operating procedure",
        "distractor2": "Administrators ยน disposition",
        "distractor3": "Executive power",
        "distractor4": "Deregulation "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard operating procedures become frustrating to citizens and obstacles to action whenthey",
        "correct_answer": "do not directly apply to a particular situation.",
        "distractor1": "slow bureaucratic responses to citizens ยน needs.",
        "distractor2": "are not specifically codified.",
        "distractor3": "transfer personnel to different posts.",
        "distractor4": "are not closely followed. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The authority of administrative actors to select among various responses to a given problem iscalled",
        "correct_answer": "administrative discretion. ",
        "distractor1": "policy implementation.",
        "distractor2": "selective management.",
        "distractor3": "the merit principle.",
        "distractor4": "the definition of alternatives."
    },
    {
        "question": "Administrative discretion is greatest when",
        "correct_answer": "rules do not fit a case. ",
        "distractor1": "rules and regulations are not written down.",
        "distractor2": "when standard operating procedures are used.",
        "distractor3": "an agency has elaborate rules and regulations.",
        "distractor4": "a particular agency is the subject of media coverage."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Aviation Administration's protocol for for hijackings assumed that",
        "correct_answer": "All of the above ",
        "distractor1": "the pilot would be able to radio air traffic controllers and alert them to the problem.",
        "distractor2": "the FAA would be able to pinpoint the aircraft involved.",
        "distractor3": "there would be enough time for the government to formulate a response.",
        "distractor4": "the hijackers would be motivated in part by a desire to stay alive."
    },
    {
        "question": "Those civil service employees who are in constant contact with the public (often a hostile one)and have considerable discretion are known as",
        "correct_answer": "street-level bureaucrats.",
        "distractor1": "routinizers.",
        "distractor2": "General Schedule foot soldiers.",
        "distractor3": "the Senior Executive Service.",
        "distractor4": "civil servants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Administrative personnel who exercise discretion, pay attention to routine, and deal directlywith clients,",
        "correct_answer": "are called street-level bureaucrats.",
        "distractor1": "are limited to high-level positions in the administration.",
        "distractor2": "implement federal policies.",
        "distractor3": "are part of the Senior Executive Service.",
        "distractor4": "are usually dismissed for not following standard operating procedures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would not be considered a street-level bureaucrat?",
        "correct_answer": "an assistant secretary in the Department of Transportation",
        "distractor1": "a municipal court judge",
        "distractor2": "a welfare worker",
        "distractor3": "a mail carrier who delivers mail exclusively in a high-rise building",
        "distractor4": "a police officer "
    },
    {
        "question": "When bureaucrats are asked to execute orders with which they do not agree,",
        "correct_answer": "slippage is likely to occur between policy decisions and performance. ",
        "distractor1": "they usually ignore the orders.",
        "distractor2": "they are likely to lose their jobs if they do not follow through with the orders.",
        "distractor3": "they can file a Conflict Of Interest Form and will be exempted from that duty by their boss.",
        "distractor4": "implementation follows standard operating procedures."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Bureaucrats are often fired for using too much administrative discretion.",
        "distractor1": "Pay raises in the bureaucracy tend to be small and across -the-board.",
        "distractor2": "Removing appointed officials may be politically embarrassing to the president.",
        "distractor3": "A government agency cannot expand just because it is performing a service effectively and efficiently.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The diffusion of responsibility within the bureaucracy",
        "correct_answer": "makes the coordination of policies both time-consuming and difficult.",
        "distractor1": "increases administrative discretion.",
        "distractor2": "allows for a diversity of opinion thus facilitating effective administration.",
        "distractor3": "helps diminish the use of administrative discretion.",
        "distractor4": "facilitates the use of inter-bureaucracy standard operating procedures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Proposals to reorganize the government in order to solve the problem of bureaucraticfragmentation",
        "correct_answer": "are often opposed by agencies not wanting to be submerged within a broader bureaucratic unit.",
        "distractor1": "tend to be supported by Republican presidents, who advocate governmental centralization.",
        "distractor2": "are opposed by congressional committees, fearing they will be given greater responsibility to oversee larger and more diverse agencies.",
        "distractor3": "are supported by interest groups, who feel they could better control the regulatory programs of a reorganized bureaucracy.",
        "distractor4": "are supported and opposed for all of these reasons. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Voting Rights Act of 1965",
        "correct_answer": "was successfully implemented thanks to its clear goal, its clear methods to achieve the goal, and its lack of bureaucratic fragmentation.",
        "distractor1": "was very difficult to implement because of the fragmentation of responsibility for implementing it.",
        "distractor2": "failed to achieve its policy goals because of the outright hostility of street -level bureaucrats.",
        "distractor3": "was impossible to implement because of a lack of clarity in the legislation.",
        "distractor4": "All but D are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Voting Rights Act of 1965 was successful for all of the following reasons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "it was universally supported.",
        "distractor1": "its goal was clear.",
        "distractor2": "its implementation was straightforward.",
        "distractor3": "the authority of the implementors was plain.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of government authority to control or change some practice in the private sector isknown as",
        "correct_answer": "regulation.",
        "distractor1": "socialism.",
        "distractor2": "oversight.",
        "distractor3": "executive review.",
        "distractor4": "public administration. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of governmental authority to control or change some practice in the private sector iscalled",
        "correct_answer": "regulation.",
        "distractor1": "patronage.",
        "distractor2": "administrative discretion.",
        "distractor3": "policy implementation.",
        "distractor4": "public administration. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about government regulation in America is accurate?",
        "correct_answer": "Until 1887, the federal government made almost no regulatory policies and had no regulatory agencies.",
        "distractor1": "The Constitution set up only six regulatory agencies; the others have been created within the past 100 years or so.",
        "distractor2": "The Federal Communications Commission was the first independent regulatory agency.",
        "distractor3": "Regulatory agencies tended to be more popular in the early years of the nation's history, then grew more controversial during the late-nineteenth century.",
        "distractor4": "both A and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of Munn v. Illinois, decided in 1877, the United States Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "upheld the right of government to regulate the business operations of a firm. ",
        "distractor1": "ruled that states could not impose corporate income taxes.",
        "distractor2": "ruled that the Civil Service System was constitutional.",
        "distractor3": "outlawed the patronage system.",
        "distractor4": "held that government had no right to regulate the business operations of a firm."
    },
    {
        "question": "Until 1887, the federal government",
        "correct_answer": "had almost no regulatory policies.",
        "distractor1": "was involved only in social regulation.",
        "distractor2": "owned and operated most of the major industries in the country.",
        "distractor3": "forbade the states from passing regulatory policies.",
        "distractor4": "was involved only in economic regulation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court case of Munn v. Illinois (1877)",
        "correct_answer": "upheld the right of government to regulate the business operations of a firm.",
        "distractor1": "declared that regulation was not within the realm of state powers.",
        "distractor2": "first established the right to own property as one of the rights of the Bill of Rights.",
        "distractor3": "set the precedent for deregulation.",
        "distractor4": "upheld the constitutionality of the Interstate Commerce Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most regulatory agencies adopt specific ________ to carry out a policy, based on what theybelieve was the intended purpose of the specific policy at hand.",
        "correct_answer": "guidelines",
        "distractor1": "iron triangles",
        "distractor2": "incentive systems",
        "distractor3": "mandates",
        "distractor4": "merit principles "
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatever strategy Congress permits a regulatory agency to use, all regulation contains thefollowing elements EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "an incentive system to maximize performance by those regulated.",
        "distractor1": "some means of enforcing compliance.",
        "distractor2": "a grant of power and set of directions from Congress.",
        "distractor3": "a set of rules and guidelines by the regulatory agency itself.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "All regulations contain each of the following elements EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "presidential oversight and control of enforcement",
        "distractor1": "a grant of power and set of directions from Congress",
        "distractor2": "some means of enforcing compliance with congressional goals and agency regulations",
        "distractor3": "a set of rules and guidelines by the regulatory agency itself",
        "distractor4": "All of these are elements of the regulatory process. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When Congress passes regulatory legislation for which it has established goals, it then",
        "correct_answer": "grants power to regulatory agencies to develop guidelines and enforce compliance.",
        "distractor1": "assigns responsibility for administration to regulatory agencies and responsibility for enforcement to the courts.",
        "distractor2": "establishes the guidelines that regulatory agencies must implement.",
        "distractor3": "grants interest groups the power to develop the rules governing the new policy.",
        "distractor4": "authorizes the president to use his administrative discretion to implement the legislation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One proposed solution to the   problem   of the proliferation of regulatory agencies and policieshas been",
        "correct_answer": "deregulation.",
        "distractor1": "deproliferation.",
        "distractor2": "budget cuts.",
        "distractor3": "standard operating procedures.",
        "distractor4": "the incentive system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Deregulation has resulted, at least in part, in each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "the proliferation of government agencies.",
        "distractor1": "environmental damage.",
        "distractor2": "competitive airline fares.",
        "distractor3": "an expensive bailout of the savings and loan industry.",
        "distractor4": "less government oversight in some key areas. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an accusation made against the regulatory system?",
        "correct_answer": "Excessive regulation contributed to the savings and loan industry disaster of the 1980s.",
        "distractor1": "If the producer is faced with expensive regulations, costs will inevitably be passed along to the consumer in the form of higher prices.",
        "distractor2": "Regulations do not always work well, and they simply create massive regulatory bureaucracies.",
        "distractor3": "Other nations have laxer regulations on pollution, worker safety, and other business practices, thus American exports often cost more.",
        "distractor4": "All of these have been criticisms of regulation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Each of the following is a criticism of regulation EXCEPT that it",
        "correct_answer": "lowers prices.",
        "distractor1": "does not work.",
        "distractor2": "distorts market forces.",
        "distractor3": "is too complex.",
        "distractor4": "gives bureaucrats too much power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most of the government is composed of",
        "correct_answer": "bureaucrats.",
        "distractor1": "regulators.",
        "distractor2": "lawyers.",
        "distractor3": "elected legislators.",
        "distractor4": "politicians. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Executive orders are issued by",
        "correct_answer": "the president. ",
        "distractor1": "independent regulatory agencies.",
        "distractor2": "any federal agency or department.",
        "distractor3": "Congress.",
        "distractor4": "members of the Senior Executive Service."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a method a president can use to control the bureaucracy?",
        "correct_answer": "rewrite statutes to make instructions clearer as to how policies are intended",
        "distractor1": "issue executive orders or more informal requests",
        "distractor2": "appoint people to head an agency who share the president's goals and strategies",
        "distractor3": "tinker with an agency's recommended budget",
        "distractor4": "request a congressional oversight hearing "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about Congress and the bureaucracy is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Congress has found it easy to control the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor1": "Bureaucracies can help Congress find answers to policy problems.",
        "distractor2": "Bureaucracies help provide services to constituents.",
        "distractor3": "Members of Congress often find a big bureaucracy congenial.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress tries to control the bureaucracy through each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "issuing congressional orders.",
        "distractor1": "rewriting legislation.",
        "distractor2": "influencing the appointment of agency heads.",
        "distractor3": "holding hearings.",
        "distractor4": "both A and B "
    },
    {
        "question": "Congress tries to control the bureaucracy through",
        "correct_answer": "rewriting laws and budgets and holding hearings.",
        "distractor1": "deregulation.",
        "distractor2": "the use of executive orders and appointments.",
        "distractor3": "the creation of   iron triangles.  ",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "To limit bureaucratic discretion and make its instructions clearer, Congress can",
        "correct_answer": "write new and more detailed legislation.",
        "distractor1": "deregulate.",
        "distractor2": "hold congressional hearings.",
        "distractor3": "reregulate.",
        "distractor4": "threaten to cut an agency's budget. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As the oversight powers of Congress in regard to the bureaucracy have become morevigorous,",
        "correct_answer": "they have also become more fragmented.",
        "distractor1": "Congress is increasingly the policy-implementation branch of government.",
        "distractor2": "it has become easier to rein in the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor3": "  iron triangles   have weakened considerably.",
        "distractor4": "the amount of government corruption has decreased dramatically. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A major problem for presidents and Congress in controlling bureaucracies is the existence of",
        "correct_answer": "  iron triangles.  ",
        "distractor1": "the plum book.",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court rulings curbing the scope of their oversight.",
        "distractor3": "standard operating procedures.",
        "distractor4": "the incentive system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An   iron triangle   is also referred to as",
        "correct_answer": "a subgovernment.",
        "distractor1": "a government corporation.",
        "distractor2": "a reverse diagonal.",
        "distractor3": "the alphabet soup of American government.",
        "distractor4": "an issue network. "
    },
    {
        "question": "  Iron triangles   face challenges from a growing number of",
        "correct_answer": "issue networks. ",
        "distractor1": "street-level bureaucrats.",
        "distractor2": "subgovernments.",
        "distractor3": "plastics and softer metals.",
        "distractor4": "administrative discretions."
    },
    {
        "question": "A group of participants in bureaucratic policymaking with technical policy expertise andintellectual and emotional commitment to the issue is called",
        "correct_answer": "an issue network.",
        "distractor1": "a government corporation.",
        "distractor2": "an   iron triangle  .",
        "distractor3": "a subgovernment.",
        "distractor4": "a vested cohort. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an area in which an   iron triangle   has controlled federal policyover the past several decades?",
        "correct_answer": "environmental policy",
        "distractor1": "nuclear power policy",
        "distractor2": "pesticide policy",
        "distractor3": "smoking & tobacco policy",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about   iron triangles  ?",
        "correct_answer": "They are indestructible.",
        "distractor1": "They present tremendous difficulties for Congress and the president when they attempt to control the bureaucracy.",
        "distractor2": "They add a strong decentralizing and fragmenting element to the government's policymaking process.",
        "distractor3": "They are also known as subgovernments.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "  Iron triangles   are composed of",
        "correct_answer": "bureaucratic agencies, interest groups, and congressional committees.",
        "distractor1": "primarily iron, but also metallic, alloys.",
        "distractor2": "urban bureaucracies, state bureaucracies, and federal bureaucracies.",
        "distractor3": "congressional committees, state governments, and bureaucratic agencies.",
        "distractor4": "senators, governors, and department heads. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1887, Congress established the first regulatory agency, the ________, and charged it withregulating the railroads, their prices, and their services to farmers.",
        "correct_answer": "Interstate Commerce Commission ",
        "distractor1": "Department of Transportation",
        "distractor2": "Railroad Commission",
        "distractor3": "American Railway Union",
        "distractor4": "Federal Trade Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about bureaucracies and the scope of government isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "When the president and Congress chose to deregulate certain areas of the economy or cut taxes, the bureaucracy prevented them from doing so.",
        "distractor1": "The federal bureaucracy has actually shrunk in size relative to the population it serves.",
        "distractor2": "The bureaucracy is now expected to play an active role in dealing with social and economic problems.",
        "distractor3": "The federal bureaucracy has not grown over the past two generations.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the courts is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Most of American judicial policy is made in the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor1": "Supreme Court decisions may directly shape people's lives.",
        "distractor2": "The great bulk of American legal business is transacted in the less-noticed courts.",
        "distractor3": "The Supreme Court decides a handful of key issues each year.",
        "distractor4": "The judicial system in the U.S. is, at least in principle, an adversarial one. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the differences between criminal law and civil law is that in civil law",
        "correct_answer": "there is no charge that a law has been violated.",
        "distractor1": "there is no jury.",
        "distractor2": "the case cannot be appealed.",
        "distractor3": "the government cannot be one of the litigants.",
        "distractor4": "common law takes precedent over statutory law. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Litigants are",
        "correct_answer": "the plaintiff and the defendant.",
        "distractor1": "the attorneys.",
        "distractor2": "the plaintiff and the plaintiff's attorney.",
        "distractor3": "the defendant and the defendant's attorney.",
        "distractor4": "plaintiffs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Not everyone can challenge a law. Litigants must have what is called ________, meaning thatthey must have a serious personal stake in the case, typically determined by whether or notthey have sustained or are in danger of an injury.",
        "correct_answer": "standing to sue",
        "distractor1": "a writ of mandamus",
        "distractor2": "stare decisis",
        "distractor3": "original jurisdiction",
        "distractor4": "legal prerogative "
    },
    {
        "question": "Class action suits",
        "correct_answer": "permit a small number of people to sue on behalf of all other people similarly situated.",
        "distractor1": "are those which have to do with constitutional issues, thus broadening the standing to sue.",
        "distractor2": "are filed by students seeking to force a school district to offer additional sections of perpetually over-enrolled courses.",
        "distractor3": "may only be filed if all of those with a standing to sue agree to participate.",
        "distractor4": "are routinely filed by teachers ยน groups to prepare the way for legal strikes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Courts may only decide ________ disputes.",
        "correct_answer": "justiciable",
        "distractor1": "civil",
        "distractor2": "constitutional",
        "distractor3": "criminal",
        "distractor4": "class action "
    },
    {
        "question": "Standing to sue is determined by",
        "correct_answer": "whether or not the litigants have a serious interest in a case.",
        "distractor1": "the judiciary committee of Congress.",
        "distractor2": "whether or not the case involves a class action suit.",
        "distractor3": "the Solicitor General's office.",
        "distractor4": "a court-appointed jury. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Merely being a taxpayer and being opposed to a law does not provide the standing necessaryto challenge that law in court except in cases pertaining to",
        "correct_answer": "governmental support for religion.",
        "distractor1": "taxation.",
        "distractor2": "environmental protection.",
        "distractor3": "civil liberties.",
        "distractor4": "racial or sexual discrimination. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Class action suits",
        "correct_answer": "permit a small number of people to sue on behalf of all other people similarly situated.",
        "distractor1": "are cases in which the government sues on behalf of groups of people unable to go to court for a variety of reasons.",
        "distractor2": "are civil suits brought to the courts by interest groups.",
        "distractor3": "are civil or criminal cases involving discrimination on the basis of income.",
        "distractor4": "involve groups of people suing each other rather than individuals. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One constraint on federal courts is that they may decide only",
        "correct_answer": "justiciable disputes.",
        "distractor1": "statutory law.",
        "distractor2": "appellate cases.",
        "distractor3": "constitutional issues.",
        "distractor4": "interstate conflicts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are examples of standing to sue EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "raising a political question.",
        "distractor1": "having sustained a direct injury from another party.",
        "distractor2": "serious interest in the case.",
        "distractor3": "having sustained a direct injury from the government.",
        "distractor4": "being a member of a class "
    },
    {
        "question": "Courts with ________ hear cases brought to them on appeal from a lower court.",
        "correct_answer": "appellate jurisdiction ",
        "distractor1": "stare decisis",
        "distractor2": "original jurisdiction",
        "distractor3": "judicial review",
        "distractor4": "justiciable disputes"
    },
    {
        "question": "A legislative court is",
        "correct_answer": "staffed by judges who lack the protections against removal or salary reductions while in office.",
        "distractor1": "a state-level court.",
        "distractor2": "the initial level of federal courts for most disputes.",
        "distractor3": "staffed by judges who serve for life.",
        "distractor4": "one that specializes in the review of legislation for its constitutionality. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The entry point for most litigation in the federal courts is in one of the ________ courts.",
        "correct_answer": "district",
        "distractor1": "appellate",
        "distractor2": "Superior",
        "distractor3": "legislative",
        "distractor4": "municipal "
    },
    {
        "question": "There are ________ federal district courts.",
        "correct_answer": "91",
        "distractor1": "53",
        "distractor2": "12",
        "distractor3": "9",
        "distractor4": "50 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Courts of original jurisdiction are",
        "correct_answer": "trial courts.",
        "distractor1": "usually federal courts.",
        "distractor2": "highly specialized in the types of cases they hear.",
        "distractor3": "usually appellate courts.",
        "distractor4": "the courts that were established by the original Constitution rather than by Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Courts with appellate jurisdiction",
        "correct_answer": "review the legal issues involved in a case.",
        "distractor1": "determine the facts about a case.",
        "distractor2": "hear only criminal cases.",
        "distractor3": "have no original jurisdiction.",
        "distractor4": "hear only civil cases "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Court of Claims is a",
        "correct_answer": "legislative court.",
        "distractor1": "district court.",
        "distractor2": "state court.",
        "distractor3": "Constitutional court.",
        "distractor4": "presidential court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The only federal courts in which trials are held, and in which juries may be impaneled, are the",
        "correct_answer": "district courts.",
        "distractor1": "superior courts.",
        "distractor2": "legislative courts.",
        "distractor3": "courts of claims.",
        "distractor4": "courts of appeal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "About 98 percent of all criminal cases in the United States are heard in",
        "correct_answer": "state and local court systems.",
        "distractor1": "federal district courts.",
        "distractor2": "appellate courts.",
        "distractor3": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "legislative courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An important player at the district court level in each district is the ________, nominated bythe president and confirmed by the Senate. He or she serves at the discretion of the president.",
        "correct_answer": "United States attorney",
        "distractor1": "Solicitor General",
        "distractor2": "county clerk",
        "distractor3": "federal marshal",
        "distractor4": "federal magistrate "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most criminal and civil cases",
        "correct_answer": "never reach trial, but are settled out of court.",
        "distractor1": "are decided by jury trial in state courts.",
        "distractor2": "are appealed to a higher court.",
        "distractor3": "are decided by a judge in federal district court.",
        "distractor4": "eventually end up in the Supreme Court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The vast majority of all civil and criminal cases",
        "correct_answer": "begin and end in state courts.",
        "distractor1": "involve federal law, but are tried in state courts.",
        "distractor2": "begin and end in federal courts.",
        "distractor3": "begin in state courts and are appealed to federal courts.",
        "distractor4": "involve state laws that are tried in federal courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal magistrates perform each of the following functions EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "prosecute violations of federal law.",
        "distractor1": "preside over some trials.",
        "distractor2": "issue warrants for arrest.",
        "distractor3": "hear motions subject to review.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government is represented in civil cases in district courts by a",
        "correct_answer": "United States attorney.",
        "distractor1": "district judge.",
        "distractor2": "United States marshal.",
        "distractor3": "federal magistrate.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "About 75 percent of the more than 63,000 cases heard in the United States courts of appealcome from",
        "correct_answer": "the district courts.",
        "distractor1": "challenges to orders of many federal regulatory agencies, such as the Securities and Exchange Commission.",
        "distractor2": "the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor3": "the Superior Courts.",
        "distractor4": "the legislative courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The jurisdiction of the district courts extends to each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "appeals from state courts.",
        "distractor1": "federal crimes.",
        "distractor2": "supervision of bankruptcy proceedings.",
        "distractor3": "admiralty and maritime law cases.",
        "distractor4": "federal civil suits. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about the United States courts of appeal?",
        "correct_answer": "Their decisions are final and cannot be appealed to the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor1": "They hold no actual trials, hear no testimony, and do not impanel juries.",
        "distractor2": "Their focus is on correcting errors of procedure and law that occurred in the original proceedings of the case.",
        "distractor3": "Their decisions set precedent for all the courts and agencies within their jurisdiction.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "For handling cases at the courts of appeal level, the United States is divided into ________judicial circuits, including one for the District of Columbia.",
        "correct_answer": "12",
        "distractor1": "55",
        "distractor2": "26",
        "distractor3": "51",
        "distractor4": "91 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Each court of appeals normally hears cases in panels consisting of ________ judges.",
        "correct_answer": "3 ",
        "distractor1": "9",
        "distractor2": "6",
        "distractor3": "12",
        "distractor4": "7"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court consists of the chief justice and ________ associate justices.",
        "correct_answer": "eight",
        "distractor1": "ten",
        "distractor2": "six",
        "distractor3": "twelve",
        "distractor4": "nine "
    },
    {
        "question": "The functions of the Supreme Court include each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "reviewing the evidence in cases involving crimes committed by public officials.",
        "distractor1": "maintaining national supremacy in the law.",
        "distractor2": "resolving conflicts among the states.",
        "distractor3": "ensuring uniformity in the interpretation of national laws.",
        "distractor4": "rule on cases accepted from lower courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The size of the Supreme Court has remained the same since",
        "correct_answer": "President Ulysses S. Grant took office in 1869. ",
        "distractor1": "the Judiciary Act of 1789.",
        "distractor2": "the Twelfth Amendment was ratified in 1804.",
        "distractor3": "President Roosevelt expanded it in 1937.",
        "distractor4": "the original Constitution specified the number of justices."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Supreme Court's jurisdiction includes",
        "correct_answer": "appellate jurisdiction from both state and federal courts.",
        "distractor1": "original jurisdiction only in cases involving foreign diplomats.",
        "distractor2": "only appellate jurisdiction.",
        "distractor3": "original jurisdiction in cases involving citizens from one state only if it involves a federal question.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most decisions handed down by the Supreme Court are cases involving",
        "correct_answer": "appeals from lower federal courts.",
        "distractor1": "original jurisdiction.",
        "distractor2": "appeals from state courts.",
        "distractor3": "federal felonies involving   exceptional circumstances.  ",
        "distractor4": "appeals from state supreme courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most cases heard by the Supreme Court come from",
        "correct_answer": "civil actions from lower federal courts.",
        "distractor1": "matters over which the Supreme Court has original jurisdiction.",
        "distractor2": "state criminal courts.",
        "distractor3": "the United States Court of Appeal for the Federal Circuit.",
        "distractor4": "civil actions from state courts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about federal judges is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Only seven Supreme Court justices have ever been removed from office.",
        "distractor1": "All federal judges are nominated by the president and confirmed by a majority of the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "Federal judges may be removed from office only by conviction of impeachment.",
        "distractor3": "Members of the federal judiciary can not have their salaries reduced.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The customary manner in which the Senate disposes of federal judicial nominations in onestate is through",
        "correct_answer": "senatorial courtesy.",
        "distractor1": "the seniority system.",
        "distractor2": "majority vote, usually along party lines.",
        "distractor3": "judicial review.",
        "distractor4": "state's review. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Senators have dominated the selection of judges for the federal district courts through",
        "correct_answer": "the custom of senatorial courtesy.",
        "distractor1": "their control of the budget.",
        "distractor2": "their power over court jurisdictions.",
        "distractor3": "the influence of the Senate Judiciary Committee.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about senatorial courtesy is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "To invoke senatorial courtesy, the relevant senator must provide documented evidence why the nominee is not fit for office.",
        "distractor1": "When there is a vacancy for a federal judgeship, the relevant senator will suggest one or more names to the Attorney General and the president.",
        "distractor2": "Presidents usually check carefully with the relevant senator ahead of time so that they will avoid making a nomination that will fail to be confirmed.",
        "distractor3": "Federal judicial nominations are not confirmed when opposed by a senator of the president's party from the state in which the nominee is to serve.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about judicial selection in the lower courts is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Candidates for judicial nomination rarely campaign for the positions themselves.",
        "distractor1": "The president usually has more influence in the selection of judges to the federal courts of appeal than to federal district courts.",
        "distractor2": "Sitting judges may be asked to evaluate prospective judicial nominees.",
        "distractor3": "The Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation conduct competency and background checks on prospective judicial nominees.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the selection of Supreme Court justices is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Senators play a greater role in the recruitment of Supreme Court justices than in the selection of lower court judges.",
        "distractor1": "The president usually relies on the Attorney General and the Department of Justice to identify and screen candidates for the Court.",
        "distractor2": "The president usually operates under fewer constraints in nominating members to the Supreme Court than to the lower courts.",
        "distractor3": "Candidates for nomination to the Supreme Court usually keep a low profile.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "About ________ of nominees to the Supreme Court fail to be confirmed.",
        "correct_answer": "20 percent",
        "distractor1": "38 percent",
        "distractor2": "5 percent",
        "distractor3": "50 percent",
        "distractor4": "10 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "In its investigation of Supreme Court nominees, the Senate Judiciary Committee",
        "correct_answer": "may probe a nominee's judicial philosophy in great detail.",
        "distractor1": "follows the custom of senatorial courtesy and confirms nominees approved by their home state senators.",
        "distractor2": "limits its investigation to the nominee's judicial integrity and experience.",
        "distractor3": "is basically a rubber stamp for the president's nomination.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to convince moderate senators to join them, opponents of a nomination for theSupreme Court try to focus on a nominee's",
        "correct_answer": "competence or ethics.",
        "distractor1": "mistrial rate.",
        "distractor2": "ideology.",
        "distractor3": "political activities.",
        "distractor4": "age. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to defeat a judicial nomination, opponents in the Senate usually must",
        "correct_answer": "be able to question a nominee's competence or ethics.",
        "distractor1": "get public support in opposition to the nomination.",
        "distractor2": "be in the majority and be in the opposite party as the president.",
        "distractor3": "get the American Bar Association on their side.",
        "distractor4": "prove the nominee's ideological extremism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Reagan's nomination of Robert Bork as an associate justice on the Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "was rejected by the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "was rejected by both the House and the Senate.",
        "distractor2": "was withdrawn after it came to light that Bork had smoked marijuana while a law professor at Harvard.",
        "distractor3": "was confirmed by the closest margin in the twentieth century.",
        "distractor4": "based on Bork's extensive legal experience. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Supreme Court justice Clarence Thomas",
        "correct_answer": "is ideologically conservative. ",
        "distractor1": "has no identifiable ideology.",
        "distractor2": "is an ideological moderate.",
        "distractor3": "is an ideological moderate who advocates a jurisprudence of original intent.",
        "distractor4": "is ideologically liberal."
    },
    {
        "question": "President ________ appointed more women, African Americans, and Hispanics to the federaldistrict and circuit courts than all previous presidents combined.",
        "correct_answer": "Jimmy Carter",
        "distractor1": "Lyndon Johnson",
        "distractor2": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor3": "Gerald Ford",
        "distractor4": "George Bush "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first woman appointed to the United States Supreme Court was",
        "correct_answer": "Sandra Day O ยนConnor.",
        "distractor1": "Frances Perkins.",
        "distractor2": "Hillary Clinton.",
        "distractor3": "Charlotte Perkins Gilman.",
        "distractor4": "Ruth Bader Ginsberg. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who currently serves on the Supreme Court as the chief justice?",
        "correct_answer": "John Roberts",
        "distractor1": "William Rehnquist",
        "distractor2": "Samuel Alito",
        "distractor3": "Harriet Miers",
        "distractor4": "Dennis Kucinich "
    },
    {
        "question": "Usually more than 90 percent of presidents ยน judicial nominations are members of",
        "correct_answer": "their own party.",
        "distractor1": "the Department of Justice.",
        "distractor2": "law school faculties.",
        "distractor3": "state legislatures.",
        "distractor4": "Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of presidents ยน judicial nominations are members of their own parties?",
        "correct_answer": "usually more than 90 percent",
        "distractor1": "almost 80 percent",
        "distractor2": "slightly more than half",
        "distractor3": "except for rare occasions, 100 percent",
        "distractor4": "about 75 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important factors influencing the president's selection of judges and justices appearsto be",
        "correct_answer": "ideology and partisanship.",
        "distractor1": "race and gender.",
        "distractor2": "judicial and elective experience.",
        "distractor3": "geography and religion.",
        "distractor4": "their law school rank. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under Ronald Reagan's administration, there was a strong tendency to appoint federal judgeson the basis of",
        "correct_answer": "ideology.",
        "distractor1": "ascriptive characteristics.",
        "distractor2": "experience in the law profession.",
        "distractor3": "partisan involvement.",
        "distractor4": "their contributions to Reagan's presidential campaign. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Supreme Court justices often try to time their retirement",
        "correct_answer": "so that a president with compatible views will choose their successor.",
        "distractor1": "to maximize their government retirement pension.",
        "distractor2": "in such a way as to maximize their historical impact.",
        "distractor3": "so they can resign in protest of a major majority decision that they disagree with.",
        "distractor4": "near election time so that the Supreme Court nomination becomes an election issue. "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Eisenhower's selection of Earl Warren and William Brennan to the Supreme Court isan example of",
        "correct_answer": "how presidents can become disappointed with their selections.",
        "distractor1": "the Senate majority's tendency to reject nominees of the opposing political party.",
        "distractor2": "how religion and region were once important selection criteria.",
        "distractor3": "how a president can mold the Court to his ideology.",
        "distractor4": "the importance of partisanship in the selection of justices. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Presidents are disappointed with their judicial nominations to the Court about ________percent of the time.",
        "correct_answer": "25",
        "distractor1": "33",
        "distractor2": "15",
        "distractor3": "10",
        "distractor4": "50 "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Franklin Roosevelt's appointees to the Supreme Court",
        "correct_answer": "liberalized the Court.",
        "distractor1": "routinely ruled his New Deal legislation unconstitutional.",
        "distractor2": "made the Court more conservative.",
        "distractor3": "proved to have no effect upon the decisions of the Court.",
        "distractor4": "proved to be great disappointments to him on issue after issue. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most important factors that brings potential federal judges to the attention ofsenators and the Department of Justice is their",
        "correct_answer": "involvement in partisan politics. ",
        "distractor1": "stand on issues.",
        "distractor2": "conviction rates.",
        "distractor3": "total honesty and integrity.",
        "distractor4": "ideological neutrality."
    },
    {
        "question": "If ________ Supreme Court justices agree to grant review of a case, it can be scheduled for oralargument or decided on the basis of the written record already on file with the Court.",
        "correct_answer": "four",
        "distractor1": "six",
        "distractor2": "two",
        "distractor3": "nine",
        "distractor4": "a majority of "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common way for the Supreme Court to put a case on its docket is by issuing a(n)________, a formal document that calls up a case which deals with a Constitutional question orin which state laws are claimed to violate federal law.",
        "correct_answer": "writ of certiorari ",
        "distractor1": "writ of mandamus",
        "distractor2": "stare decisis",
        "distractor3": "amicus curiae brief",
        "distractor4": "per curiam decision"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order for the Supreme Court to hear oral arguments or decide a case on the written record,",
        "correct_answer": "four justices must agree to take the case.",
        "distractor1": "a majority of the justices must agree to take the case.",
        "distractor2": "the case must first be sent to it by the president.",
        "distractor3": "only the chief justice must agree to take the case.",
        "distractor4": "all justices must agree to take the case. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A writ of certiorari",
        "correct_answer": "is used by the Supreme Court to call up a case.",
        "distractor1": "means that judges have decided a case on the basis of precedent.",
        "distractor2": "frees a detained person whom a court has found is being held in violation of due process.",
        "distractor3": "is the official record of a court's decision, stating the facts of the case and the rationale for the decision.",
        "distractor4": "is used to move a case from a court of original jurisdiction to a federal district court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is a presidential appointee who is in charge of the appellate court litigation ofthe federal government, works out of the Department of Justice, and can have an importantinfluence on the Supreme Court.",
        "correct_answer": "Solicitor General",
        "distractor1": "Adjutant General",
        "distractor2": "United States attorney",
        "distractor3": "Attorney General",
        "distractor4": "chief justice "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a function of the United States Solicitor General's office?",
        "correct_answer": "require the Supreme Court to review a government case on appeal",
        "distractor1": "decide whether or not to appeal cases the government has lost in the lower courts",
        "distractor2": "review and modify the briefs presented in government appeals",
        "distractor3": "represent the government before the Supreme Court",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "In a typical year, the Supreme Court issues ________ formal written opinions that could serveas precedent, and thus as the basis of guidance for lower courts.",
        "correct_answer": "fewer than 100",
        "distractor1": "more than 1,000",
        "distractor2": "between 150 and 500",
        "distractor3": "more than 500, but less than 1,000",
        "distractor4": "fewer than ten "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ is a Supreme Court ruling without explanation which resolves an immediate casebut has no value as precedent because the Court does not offer reasoning that would guidelower courts in future decisions.",
        "correct_answer": "per curiam decision",
        "distractor1": "stare decisis",
        "distractor2": "writ of certiorari",
        "distractor3": "concurring opinion",
        "distractor4": "writ of mandamus "
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who are interested in the outcome of a case, but are not formal litigants, sometimessubmit ________ briefs, raising points of view and presenting information that they hope willinfluence the Supreme Court's decision.",
        "correct_answer": "amicus curiae",
        "distractor1": "certiorari",
        "distractor2": "stare decisis",
        "distractor3": "per curiam decision",
        "distractor4": "concurring "
    },
    {
        "question": "Principal reasons for the Court's choosing to hear a case would include each of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "politically hot and divisive cases.",
        "distractor1": "conflict between different lower courts on the interpretation of federal law.",
        "distractor2": "cases that involve major issues, like civil liberties.",
        "distractor3": "disagreement between a majority of the Supreme Court and lower court decisions.",
        "distractor4": "the justices ยน law clerks recommend doing so. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The decision to appeal cases the federal government has lost in the lower courts is made by the",
        "correct_answer": "Solicitor General.",
        "distractor1": "majority of the Supreme Court.",
        "distractor2": "president.",
        "distractor3": "chief justice.",
        "distractor4": "district judge. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ opinions are those offered by one or more Supreme Court justices not only tosupport a majority decision, but also to stress a different Constitutional or legal basis for thejudgment.",
        "correct_answer": "Concurring",
        "distractor1": "Amicus curiae",
        "distractor2": "Dissenting",
        "distractor3": "Adjunct",
        "distractor4": "Differential "
    },
    {
        "question": "A written opinion in a Supreme Court case is a",
        "correct_answer": "statement of the legal reasoning behind a decision.",
        "distractor1": "legal argument submitted by an attorney in a case seeking to sway a justice's decision.",
        "distractor2": "way of establishing the Court's agenda.",
        "distractor3": "formality handled by the chief justice's law clerks.",
        "distractor4": "form of press release written by the chief justice. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All courts rely heavily upon ________ รฎโฌโthe way similar cases were handled in the pastรฎโฌโas aguide to current decisions.",
        "correct_answer": "precedent",
        "distractor1": "writs of certiorari",
        "distractor2": "writs of mandamus",
        "distractor3": "original intent",
        "distractor4": "amicus curiae "
    },
    {
        "question": "Stare decisis means that cases are",
        "correct_answer": "decided on the basis of precedent.",
        "distractor1": "decided using an adversarial system of opposing sides through which the truth hopefully will emerge.",
        "distractor2": "decided on the grounds of constitutionality.",
        "distractor3": "often used by judges to in effect enact new law and public policy.",
        "distractor4": "appealable only on procedural grounds not on evidence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Supreme Court ________ overrule is own precedents.",
        "correct_answer": "can",
        "distractor1": "can, but has not tried to",
        "distractor2": "will routinely",
        "distractor3": "has tried but has failed to",
        "distractor4": "cannot "
    },
    {
        "question": "Judicial ________ refers to how and whether court decisions are translated into real policy,affecting the behavior of others.",
        "correct_answer": "implementation ",
        "distractor1": "restraint",
        "distractor2": "intent",
        "distractor3": "action",
        "distractor4": "review"
    },
    {
        "question": "Until the Civil War, the dominant questions before the Supreme Court regarded",
        "correct_answer": "the powers and legitimacy of the federal government.",
        "distractor1": "questions of the relationship between the federal government and the economy.",
        "distractor2": "presidential powers.",
        "distractor3": "issues of social and political equality and the expansion of the right to vote.",
        "distractor4": "the interpretation of First Amendment rights. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Marbury v. Madison established the principle of",
        "correct_answer": "judicial review.",
        "distractor1": "Constitutional penumbra.",
        "distractor2": "national supremacy.",
        "distractor3": "original intent.",
        "distractor4": "stare decisis. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Supreme Court case of  Marbury v. Madison isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The Court ruled that Madison was in the right to withhold Marbury's commission.",
        "distractor1": "The Court established its power to hold acts of Congress in violation of the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "The Court ruled part of the Judiciary Act of 1789 unconstitutional.",
        "distractor3": "The Court ruled that it had no power to require that Marbury's commission be delivered.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early New Deal era, the Supreme Court was dominated by conservatives who",
        "correct_answer": "viewed federal intervention in the economy as unconstitutional, and declared several laws invalid.",
        "distractor1": "came to be known as the Bad Deal Five for thwarting New Deal legislation and were impeached and removed as a group by Congress.",
        "distractor2": "strongly supported federal intervention in the economy, and voted to uphold all New Deal acts.",
        "distractor3": "overturned the precedent of Marbury v. Madison and ruled that the Supreme Court has no power of judicial review.",
        "distractor4": "were impeached one by one by Congress. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The proposal to add justices to the Supreme Court, known as the   court packing plan   tocritics, was made by President ________ who wanted to be able to appoint justices moresympathetic to his philosophy than the   nine old men.  ",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt",
        "distractor1": "Dwight Eisenhower",
        "distractor2": "Harry Truman",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor4": "John F. Kennedy "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president who tried to pack the Supreme Court by increasing its size in order to effect asympathetic majority was",
        "correct_answer": "Franklin Roosevelt.",
        "distractor1": "Harry Truman.",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor3": "Dwight Eisenhower.",
        "distractor4": "Thomas Jefferson. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most liberal court of the modern era has been the",
        "correct_answer": "Warren Court.",
        "distractor1": "Rehnquist Court.",
        "distractor2": "Marshall Court.",
        "distractor3": "Taft Court.",
        "distractor4": "Burger Court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most active Supreme Courts in shaping public policy in areas of desegregation andthe rights of the accused was the",
        "correct_answer": "Warren Court.",
        "distractor1": "Rehnquist Court.",
        "distractor2": "Marshall Court.",
        "distractor3": "Burger Court.",
        "distractor4": "Nixon Court. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Richard Nixon chose ________ as the new chief justice in 1969, hoping with this appointmentto move the Supreme Court toward a more   strict construction   interpretation of theConstitution in its subsequent decisions.",
        "correct_answer": "Warren Burger",
        "distractor1": "John Marshall",
        "distractor2": "Nelson Rockefeller",
        "distractor3": "Harry Blackmun",
        "distractor4": "Earl Warren "
    },
    {
        "question": "Democratic theorists criticize the courts on the grounds that they are",
        "correct_answer": "not representative of the people or majority public opinion.",
        "distractor1": "used indiscriminately, leading to legal stagnation.",
        "distractor2": "not representative of the victimized upper and upper-middle classes.",
        "distractor3": "and always have been used to persecute vulnerable minorities.",
        "distractor4": "easily swayed by interest-group pressure. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Studies of Supreme Court decisions found that",
        "correct_answer": "the Court is normally in line with popular majorities.",
        "distractor1": "the Court prefers to base its decisions on the Constitution rather than narrower and more contentious technical grounds.",
        "distractor2": "the Court is usually out of line with public opinion.",
        "distractor3": "there is no correlation between public opinion and Court decisions.",
        "distractor4": "the Court renders fewer decisions in election years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Advocates of ________ emphasize that the courts may alleviate pressing needs, especially ofthose who are weak politically or economically, left unmet by the majoritarian politicalprocess.",
        "correct_answer": "judicial activism",
        "distractor1": "the jurisprudence of original intent",
        "distractor2": "judicial restraint",
        "distractor3": "judicial implementation",
        "distractor4": "judicial review "
    },
    {
        "question": "The justification used by federal courts primarily to avoid deciding cases regarding conflictsbetween the president and Congress is known as the doctrine of",
        "correct_answer": "political questions.",
        "distractor1": "judicial activism.",
        "distractor2": "independent grounds.",
        "distractor3": "stare decisis.",
        "distractor4": "judicial restraint. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As a means to avoid deciding some cases, the federal courts have developed a doctrine of",
        "correct_answer": "political questions. ",
        "distractor1": "judicial precedent.",
        "distractor2": "strict constructionism.",
        "distractor3": "statutory construction.",
        "distractor4": "judicial activism."
    },
    {
        "question": "When given a choice, the courts are least likely to decide a case on the basis of",
        "correct_answer": "the Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "standing.",
        "distractor2": "precedent.",
        "distractor3": "mootness.",
        "distractor4": "jurisdiction. "
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times has the Supreme Court ruled a federal law unconstitutional?",
        "correct_answer": "fewer than 200",
        "distractor1": "more than 500",
        "distractor2": "once",
        "distractor3": "never",
        "distractor4": "about 1,000 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Cases that involve statutory construction",
        "correct_answer": "can be overturned by Congress by clarifying an existing law.",
        "distractor1": "must be decided according to a strict construction of the Constitution.",
        "distractor2": "are usually precedent setting.",
        "distractor3": "involve policy issues.",
        "distractor4": "can only be changed through a Constitutional amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Conservatives complain about",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above",
        "distractor1": "the size of the public sector.",
        "distractor2": "excessive regulation of the private sector.",
        "distractor3": "the oppressive scope of government.",
        "distractor4": "new legislation limiting corporate power. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The consumer price index measures",
        "correct_answer": "the change in the cost of buying a fixed basket of good and services.",
        "distractor1": "the change what various incomes can buy.",
        "distractor2": "the change in the amount of taxes paid by individuals.",
        "distractor3": "the change in income, controlling for periods of unemployment.",
        "distractor4": "the change in the prime lending rate. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Hundreds, if not thousands, of studies by political scientists have concluded that voters",
        "correct_answer": "vote for the candidate who will benefit the voter's financial condition the most.",
        "distractor1": "ignore the economic consequences of government policies.",
        "distractor2": "vote for candidates who promise the most.",
        "distractor3": "vote solely on the basis of partisanship alone.",
        "distractor4": "vote against their personal financial interests. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Business owners, managers, and professional people are more likely to vote ________ thanlower income people are.",
        "correct_answer": "Republican (due to greater concern about inflation)",
        "distractor1": "Democratic (due to greater concern about unemployment)",
        "distractor2": "Democratic (due to greater concern about inflation)",
        "distractor3": "Republican (due to greater concern about both inflation and unemployment)",
        "distractor4": "Republican (due to greater concern about unemployment) "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republican party is more concerned than the Democrats about",
        "correct_answer": "inflation than unemployment.",
        "distractor1": "crime and health problems that are linked to unemployment.",
        "distractor2": "high interest rates.",
        "distractor3": "staving off a recession.",
        "distractor4": "raising the consumer price index. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The nation's unemployment rate is determined by",
        "correct_answer": "a monthly random survey of the population.",
        "distractor1": "monthly changes in income tax withholdings monitored by the Internal Revenue Service.",
        "distractor2": "randomly selected payroll audits by Federal Reserve Board analysts.",
        "distractor3": "monthly reports by the unemployment department of each state.",
        "distractor4": "monthly reports filed by all employers regarding the number of their employees. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ conducts a huge statistical survey of the population monthly to measure thenation's unemployment rate.",
        "correct_answer": "Bureau of Labor Statistics",
        "distractor1": "Federal Reserve Board",
        "distractor2": "Council of Economic Advisors",
        "distractor3": "Census Bureau",
        "distractor4": "Office of Management and the Budget "
    },
    {
        "question": "The official unemployment rate underestimates unemployment because it leaves out",
        "correct_answer": "discouraged workers.",
        "distractor1": "students.",
        "distractor2": "housewives.",
        "distractor3": "the high-tech sector.",
        "distractor4": "the homeless. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 2004 presidential election, people who thought their families were doing better off voted",
        "correct_answer": "4 to 1 for George W. Bush.",
        "distractor1": "2 to 1 for George W. Bush.",
        "distractor2": "10 to 1 for George W. Bush.",
        "distractor3": "4 to 1 for John Kerry.",
        "distractor4": "2 to 1 for John Kerry. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Inflation was generally highest during the",
        "correct_answer": "1970s.",
        "distractor1": "1930s.",
        "distractor2": "1960s.",
        "distractor3": "1980s.",
        "distractor4": "1990s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle that the government should not meddle with the economy is known as",
        "correct_answer": "laissez faire.",
        "distractor1": "Keynesian economic theory.",
        "distractor2": "caveat emptor.",
        "distractor3": "monetarism.",
        "distractor4": "conservatism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When the stock market crash of 1929 sent unemployment soaring, President Herbert Hoover",
        "correct_answer": "clung to the laissez-faire economic theory.",
        "distractor1": "embraced Keynesian economic theory.",
        "distractor2": "experimented with dozens of new federal policies and work projects to put the economy back on track.",
        "distractor3": "pushed a massive tax cut through Congress to stimulate the economy.",
        "distractor4": "put strict wage, price, and production controls into effect nationwide. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is the manipulation of the supply of money and credit in private hands to promotethe nation's economic health.",
        "correct_answer": "Monetary policy",
        "distractor1": "Keynesianism",
        "distractor2": "Laissez faire",
        "distractor3": "Fiscal policy",
        "distractor4": "Supply-side policy "
    },
    {
        "question": "Monetary policy is directly regulated by",
        "correct_answer": "the Federal Reserve System.",
        "distractor1": "the United States Mint.",
        "distractor2": "Congress and the President.",
        "distractor3": "the Department of Commerce.",
        "distractor4": "the Treasury Department. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve System is governed by",
        "correct_answer": "a seven-member Board of Governors appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate.",
        "distractor1": "the director of the Internal Revenue Service.",
        "distractor2": "a twelve-member Board of Governors chosen by local bankers in each of the twelve Federal Reserve districts.",
        "distractor3": "the President's Council of Economic Advisors.",
        "distractor4": "the Secretary of the Treasury, whose name appears on all currency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A supporter of laissez-faire policy would oppose",
        "correct_answer": "governmental intervention in the economy.",
        "distractor1": "supply-side economics.",
        "distractor2": "a strict separation between government and business.",
        "distractor3": "reducing governmental economic regulation.",
        "distractor4": "reducing government subsidies of failing businesses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the New Deal,",
        "correct_answer": "policymakers have made it part of their regular business to seek to control the economy.",
        "distractor1": "the federal government has become less involved in economic policy.",
        "distractor2": "the principle of laissez faire has dominated economic policy.",
        "distractor3": "economic issues have become less politicized.",
        "distractor4": "Keynesian economics has replaced supply-side theory in American fiscal policy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The economic theory that considers the supply of money as the key to the nation's economichealth is",
        "correct_answer": "monetarism.",
        "distractor1": "supply-side economics.",
        "distractor2": "currency-reserve theory.",
        "distractor3": "Keynesian economic theory.",
        "distractor4": "laissez-faire capitalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Monetarists emphasize that economic conditions are related to",
        "correct_answer": "the supply of money. ",
        "distractor1": "the level of government deficit spending.",
        "distractor2": "the value of the dollar in global currency markets.",
        "distractor3": "declining productivity.",
        "distractor4": "how much money government spends."
    },
    {
        "question": "The main agency for making monetary policy is the",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Reserve Board.",
        "distractor1": "Office of Management and Budget.",
        "distractor2": "United States Treasury.",
        "distractor3": "Congressional Budget Office.",
        "distractor4": "Council of Economic Advisors. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve Board is intended to be",
        "correct_answer": "independent of partisan politics. ",
        "distractor1": "formally under the control of Congress.",
        "distractor2": "half Democrat and half Republican.",
        "distractor3": "replaced by each new president.",
        "distractor4": "formally under the control of the president."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve Board regulates",
        "correct_answer": "the supply of money and credit in the economy. ",
        "distractor1": "antitrust policy.",
        "distractor2": "tax and spending policies.",
        "distractor3": "the nation's gold reserves and the United States Mint.",
        "distractor4": "all United States government bank accounts and investments."
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of the use of monetary policy is",
        "correct_answer": "requiring banks to keep more money on reserve.",
        "distractor1": "instituting a freeze on prices.",
        "distractor2": "subsidizing farmers.",
        "distractor3": "making low-interest, long-term loans to college students.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to monetarists, making too much money available to borrow may lead to",
        "correct_answer": "inflation.",
        "distractor1": "widespread bankruptcies.",
        "distractor2": "economic belt-tightening.",
        "distractor3": "recession.",
        "distractor4": "too little credit. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Members of the Federal Reserve System's Board of Governors",
        "correct_answer": "are given 14-year terms designed to insulate them from political pressures.",
        "distractor1": "are subject to replacement by each new president.",
        "distractor2": "can be fired by the president at any time.",
        "distractor3": "are career civil-servants, neither appointed nor fired by presidents.",
        "distractor4": "merely carry out policy decided by the Treasury Department. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve System's Board of Governors sets discount rates at a higher level",
        "correct_answer": "to decrease the amount of money in circulation. ",
        "distractor1": "to assist incumbent presidents near election time.",
        "distractor2": "thus lowering the cost of money and stimulating borrowing.",
        "distractor3": "to combat high unemployment.",
        "distractor4": "to increase the amount of money in circulation."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the measures used by the Fed to control the moneysupply?",
        "correct_answer": "It dictates the minimum prime lending rate by commercial banks.",
        "distractor1": "It sets discount rates for the money that banks can borrow from the Federal Reserve.",
        "distractor2": "It can buy and sell government securities in the market, thereby either expanding or contracting the money supply.",
        "distractor3": "It sets reserve requirements that determine the amount of money that banks must keep in reserve at all times.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT influenced in a major way by the actions of the Fed?",
        "correct_answer": "the minimum wage",
        "distractor1": "money supply",
        "distractor2": "inflation",
        "distractor3": "commercial interest rates",
        "distractor4": "the unemployment rate "
    },
    {
        "question": "Fiscal policy is",
        "correct_answer": "taxing, spending, and borrowing decisions shaped mostly by Congress and the president.",
        "distractor1": "the manipulation of interest rates by the government to affect economic growth rates.",
        "distractor2": "based on the principle that government should not meddle with the economy.",
        "distractor3": "the manipulation of the supply of money and credit in private hands.",
        "distractor4": "the reduction of taxes in order to stimulate the economy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxing, spending, and borrowing decisions by Congress and the president are knowncollectively as",
        "correct_answer": "fiscal policy.",
        "distractor1": "econometrics.",
        "distractor2": "supply-side economics.",
        "distractor3": "monetary policy.",
        "distractor4": "laissez faire. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important political action in setting monetary policy is",
        "correct_answer": "the Federal Reserve.",
        "distractor1": "Congress.",
        "distractor2": "secretary of the treasury.",
        "distractor3": "the president.",
        "distractor4": "International Monetary Fund. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An important tool in fiscal policy is the",
        "correct_answer": "level of government spending as indicated in the budget.",
        "distractor1": "control of interest rates.",
        "distractor2": "use of price supports.",
        "distractor3": "amount of money banks must keep on deposit.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxing, spending, and borrowing policies of the federal government are called",
        "correct_answer": "fiscal policy.",
        "distractor1": "tax expenditure policy.",
        "distractor2": "apportionment policy.",
        "distractor3": "supply-side economics.",
        "distractor4": "monetarism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Keynesian economic theory argues for",
        "correct_answer": "stimulating the economy through government spending programs.",
        "distractor1": "the government keeping its hands off the economy.",
        "distractor2": "stimulating the economy through manipulating the nation's money supply.",
        "distractor3": "stimulating the economy through massive tax cuts and reducing the size of the national government.",
        "distractor4": "government wage and price controls to control inflation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ encourages government to create jobs for people during times of severeunemployment in order to get money into the hands of consumers and stimulate the entireeconomy.",
        "correct_answer": "Keynesian economic theory ",
        "distractor1": "Supply-side economics",
        "distractor2": "Industrial policy",
        "distractor3": "Laissez faire",
        "distractor4": "Monetary policy theory"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Keynesian economic theory argues that government's role in an economic depressionshould be to",
        "correct_answer": "increase demand.",
        "distractor1": "reduce demand.",
        "distractor2": "lower taxes.",
        "distractor3": "increase supply.",
        "distractor4": "increase the total money supply with lower interest rates. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Jumping into the business of consumer protection in the 1960s and 1970s, the ________ madenew rules about product labeling, exaggerated product claims, and the use of celebrities inadvertising.",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Trade Commission",
        "distractor1": "Consumer Products Safety Commission",
        "distractor2": "Food and Drug Administration",
        "distractor3": "Clayton Antitrust Act",
        "distractor4": "Consumer Protection Agency "
    },
    {
        "question": "________, supported by President Reagan, was encouraged by the economist Arthur Laffer.",
        "correct_answer": "Supply-side economics",
        "distractor1": "Deficit spending",
        "distractor2": "Keynesian economic theory",
        "distractor3": "A strict laissez-faire system",
        "distractor4": "Monetarism "
    },
    {
        "question": "George W. Bush's tax cuts in 2001 were based on",
        "correct_answer": "supply-side economics.",
        "distractor1": "stagflation.",
        "distractor2": "the Federal funds rate.",
        "distractor3": "Keynesian economics.",
        "distractor4": "hyperinflation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Major corporate corruption scandals in the 1990s",
        "correct_answer": "followed an era of corporate concentration.",
        "distractor1": "were largely ignored by Congress.",
        "distractor2": "were ignored by conservatives.",
        "distractor3": "have had few economic effects.",
        "distractor4": "resulted in prosecution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the 1980s big business was particularly characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "an increase in corporate mergers.",
        "distractor1": "the breakup of many multinational corporations.",
        "distractor2": "a decline in foreign competition.",
        "distractor3": "an increase in government regulation.",
        "distractor4": "an increase in ethical concerns. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Sherman Act of 1890 was passed as ________ measure.",
        "correct_answer": "an antitrust",
        "distractor1": "a tariff reform",
        "distractor2": "a monetary reform",
        "distractor3": "a Civil War reparations",
        "distractor4": "a pro-labor "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about the Food and Drug Administration?",
        "correct_answer": "It has the regulatory power to cap the retail prices of food and drugs and prevent profiteering by food and drug companies.",
        "distractor1": "It has the responsibility to ascertain the safety and effectiveness of new drugs before approving them for marketing in America.",
        "distractor2": "It has broad regulatory powers over the manufacturing, contents, marketing, and labeling of food and drugs.",
        "distractor3": "Recent budget cuts have left it overburdened and seriously understaffed.",
        "distractor4": "All of these are true. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first major consumer protection policy was the",
        "correct_answer": "Food and Drug Act.",
        "distractor1": "Product Safety Act.",
        "distractor2": "Environmental Protection Act.",
        "distractor3": "Wagner Act.",
        "distractor4": "Consumer Credit Protection Act. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to the New Deal era of the 1930s, the national government",
        "correct_answer": "usually allied itself with business elites to squelch labor unions.",
        "distractor1": "forbade workers from joining unions.",
        "distractor2": "actively encouraged workers to join unions.",
        "distractor3": "guaranteed collective bargaining rights for those workers who formed a viable union.",
        "distractor4": "set long prison terms for anyone convicted of unionization activity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The right of American workers to collective bargaining was first guaranteed by the NationalLabor Relations Act, also known as the ________ Act.",
        "correct_answer": "Wagner",
        "distractor1": "Taft-Hartley",
        "distractor2": "Clayton Antitrust",
        "distractor3": "Roosevelt",
        "distractor4": "Hawley-Smoot "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of the Wagner Act?",
        "correct_answer": "It gave states the power to adopt right-to-work laws.",
        "distractor1": "It stated that the right of workers to collective bargaining was guaranteed by the national government.",
        "distractor2": "It represented a sharp break with the government's traditional anti-labor stance.",
        "distractor3": "It barred employers from firing or discriminating against a worker who advocates the possibility of unionizing.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Truth in lending is enforced by the",
        "correct_answer": "Federal Trade Commission.",
        "distractor1": "National Labor Relations Board.",
        "distractor2": "Federal Reserve Board.",
        "distractor3": "Justice Department.",
        "distractor4": "Product Safety Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The right of workers to collective bargaining is guaranteed by the",
        "correct_answer": "National Labor Relations Act.",
        "distractor1": "First Amendment.",
        "distractor2": "United States Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "Taft-Hartley Act.",
        "distractor4": "Clayton Antitrust Act. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An employer is forbidden to fire or discriminate against a worker who advocates thepossibility of unionizing under a provision of the",
        "correct_answer": "Wagner Act.",
        "distractor1": "Landrum-Griffin Act.",
        "distractor2": "Taft-Hartley Act.",
        "distractor3": "Clayton Act.",
        "distractor4": "First Amendment. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Taft-Hartley Act was aimed at",
        "correct_answer": "limiting certain practices by organized labor. ",
        "distractor1": "expanding the rights of organized labor.",
        "distractor2": "requiring employers to provide basic health insurance for their employees.",
        "distractor3": "guaranteeing the right to collective bargaining for the first time in United States history.",
        "distractor4": "establishing a minimum wage."
    },
    {
        "question": "Right-to-work laws were permitted by the",
        "correct_answer": "Taft-Hartley Act.",
        "distractor1": "Clayton Antitrust Act.",
        "distractor2": "Wagner Act.",
        "distractor3": "National Labor Relations Act.",
        "distractor4": "Federal Trade Commission. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Right-to-work laws are supported by",
        "correct_answer": "business management.",
        "distractor1": "union members, but not necessarily organized unions.",
        "distractor2": "illegal immigrants.",
        "distractor3": "organized labor unions.",
        "distractor4": "both organized labor unions and management. "
    },
    {
        "question": "States were given the right to pass right-to-work laws by the",
        "correct_answer": "Taft-Hartley Act.",
        "distractor1": "National Labor Relations Act.",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court ruling in Standard Oil v. California.",
        "distractor3": "Clayton Antitrust Act.",
        "distractor4": "Sherman Antitrust Act. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Right-to-work laws prohibit",
        "correct_answer": "requirements that workers join a union to hold their jobs.",
        "distractor1": "employers from discriminating against legal aliens in their hiring practices.",
        "distractor2": "discrimination in the work place on the basis of race or gender.",
        "distractor3": "employers from hiring illegal aliens.",
        "distractor4": "the formation of labor unions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government regulation affects businesses like Wal-Mart by",
        "correct_answer": "none of the above",
        "distractor1": "monitoring stock transactions.",
        "distractor2": "affection labor practices such as the minimum wage.",
        "distractor3": "regulating working conditions and labor practices.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above (excluding D) "
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans believe strongly that",
        "correct_answer": "people should take personal responsibility for themselves. ",
        "distractor1": "Social Security is a bad policy.",
        "distractor2": "government is responsible for social welfare.",
        "distractor3": "families are responsible for social welfare.",
        "distractor4": "social welfare is a collective good."
    },
    {
        "question": "Examples of Social Welfare policies include",
        "correct_answer": "A and B",
        "distractor1": "entitlements.",
        "distractor2": "means-tested programs.",
        "distractor3": "project grants.",
        "distractor4": "A and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "Policies that attempt to provide assistance and support to specific groups in society are called",
        "correct_answer": "social welfare policies.",
        "distractor1": "equal opportunity policies.",
        "distractor2": "redistributive policies.",
        "distractor3": "tax subsidies.",
        "distractor4": "anti-poverty policies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Federal spending on social programs ________ spending on the military and homelandsecurity.",
        "correct_answer": "is substantially higher than",
        "distractor1": "is slightly less than",
        "distractor2": "is about the same as",
        "distractor3": "is slightly higher than",
        "distractor4": "is much lower than "
    },
    {
        "question": "Programs to assist the poor have always been",
        "correct_answer": "controversial.",
        "distractor1": "politically popular.",
        "distractor2": "supported at increasingly high levels.",
        "distractor3": "provided as entitlements.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The government spends more on the ________ than on the ________.",
        "correct_answer": "non poor; poor",
        "distractor1": "military; civilians",
        "distractor2": "youth; elderly",
        "distractor3": "men; women",
        "distractor4": "non citizens; citizens "
    },
    {
        "question": "The median American household income is approximately",
        "correct_answer": "$46,000.",
        "distractor1": "$27,000.",
        "distractor2": "$32,000.",
        "distractor3": "$59,000.",
        "distractor4": "$60,000. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government benefits provided regardless of financial need are called",
        "correct_answer": "entitlements.",
        "distractor1": "means-tested.",
        "distractor2": "transfer payments.",
        "distractor3": "non-merit benefits.",
        "distractor4": "generic expenditures. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An entitlement program is one",
        "correct_answer": "which provides benefits regardless of financial need.",
        "distractor1": "to which only a small group of people are entitled.",
        "distractor2": "which requires a means test to qualify.",
        "distractor3": "guaranteed in the Constitution.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The distribution of income across segments of the American population is",
        "correct_answer": "highly uneven.",
        "distractor1": "just about even.",
        "distractor2": "slightly uneven.",
        "distractor3": "impossible to gauge.",
        "distractor4": "constantly changing. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1960s and 1970s, the income distribution in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "remained much the same, which is fairly unequal.",
        "distractor1": "grew more equitable.",
        "distractor2": "remained much the same, which is fairly equal.",
        "distractor3": "grew more unequal.",
        "distractor4": "narrowed considerably. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1980s and 1990s, income distribution in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "grew more unequal.",
        "distractor1": "grew more equitable.",
        "distractor2": "remained much the same, which is fairly equal.",
        "distractor3": "remained much the same, which is fairly unequal.",
        "distractor4": "narrowed considerably. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is the amount of money owned, including stocks, bonds, bank accounts, cars, houses,and so forth.",
        "correct_answer": "Wealth",
        "distractor1": "Income",
        "distractor2": "Taxable income",
        "distractor3": "Net earnings",
        "distractor4": "Net profit "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about wealth and income in American society?",
        "correct_answer": "Wealth is distributed less equally than income.",
        "distractor1": "Wealth and income are distributed about the same in society.",
        "distractor2": "Income is distributed less equally than wealth.",
        "distractor3": "Wealth and income are the same thing.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The top one percent of wealth-holders currently possess about ________ of all Americanwealth.",
        "correct_answer": "one third",
        "distractor1": "one percent",
        "distractor2": "one tenth",
        "distractor3": "one quarter",
        "distractor4": "one half "
    },
    {
        "question": "Statistics show that the distribution of income among American households was most unequalin",
        "correct_answer": "1990.",
        "distractor1": "1960.",
        "distractor2": "1970.",
        "distractor3": "1980.",
        "distractor4": "1950. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of money collected between two points of time is called",
        "correct_answer": "income.",
        "distractor1": "wealth.",
        "distractor2": "taxes.",
        "distractor3": "savings.",
        "distractor4": "asset accumulation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about wealth in the United States is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Between 1979 and 1995, the poorest one-fifth of the population saw their real incomes increase, while the richest one-fifth of the population saw their real incomes decrease.",
        "distractor1": "The top one percent of the wealth-holders currently possess about three percent of all American wealth.",
        "distractor2": "The wealth of the richest one percent exceeds the wealth of the bottom 90 percent.",
        "distractor3": "There are now over two million millionaires in the world, most in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The poverty line is measured by",
        "correct_answer": "taking into account what a family would need to spend to maintain an   austere   standard of living.",
        "distractor1": "the minimum wage extended on a yearly basis.",
        "distractor2": "the number of people filing for unemployment benefits.",
        "distractor3": "the boundaries of an urban ghetto.",
        "distractor4": "proportion of the median income as determined by IRS records. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States Bureau of Census ยน definition of the poverty line takes into account",
        "correct_answer": "what a family would need to spend for an austere standard of living and the size of the family.",
        "distractor1": "the earning power of the head of the household and family size.",
        "distractor2": "a daily intake of 2,000 calories and half the average hourly wage in the country.",
        "distractor3": "the earning power of the head of the household and racial composition of the family.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "To count the poor, the United States Bureau of the Census has established the ________ whichtakes into account what a family would need to spend to maintain an   austere   standard ofliving.",
        "correct_answer": "poverty line",
        "distractor1": "culture of poverty",
        "distractor2": "urban underclass",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation index",
        "distractor4": "Poverty Index "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to the general population, poverty is more common among all of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "the elderly.",
        "distractor1": "African Americans and Hispanics.",
        "distractor2": "children.",
        "distractor3": "inner city residents.",
        "distractor4": "Asian Americans. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Official poverty counts tend to underestimate poverty because",
        "correct_answer": "some families go in and out of poverty without being counted.",
        "distractor1": "some families refuse to report their income level.",
        "distractor2": "they do not include individuals ยน wealth.",
        "distractor3": "the Republicans want it that way.",
        "distractor4": "the Democrats want it that way. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The poverty rate is highest among",
        "correct_answer": "African Americans.",
        "distractor1": "people over 65.",
        "distractor2": "Caucasians who live in Appalachia.",
        "distractor3": "Hispanics.",
        "distractor4": "residents of central cities. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ tax takes a higher percentage from the incomes of the rich than the poor.",
        "correct_answer": "progressive",
        "distractor1": "proportional",
        "distractor2": "regressive",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation",
        "distractor4": "flat "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ of poverty refers to the increased concentration of poverty among women.",
        "correct_answer": "feminization",
        "distractor1": "gender-enhancement",
        "distractor2": "female-orientation",
        "distractor3": "  pink  ening",
        "distractor4": "sexualization "
    },
    {
        "question": "Poverty among the elderly declined over the past several decades primarily due to",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security payments.",
        "distractor1": "the booming economy in the 1980s.",
        "distractor2": "changing attitudes in society regarding the elderly.",
        "distractor3": "the larger proportion of savings held by the elderly.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ tax requires the same share from everyone, rich and poor alike.",
        "correct_answer": "proportional",
        "distractor1": "progressive",
        "distractor2": "regressive",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation",
        "distractor4": "flat "
    },
    {
        "question": "A ________ tax takes a higher percentage from those with lower incomes, and less from thewealthy.",
        "correct_answer": "regressive",
        "distractor1": "progressive",
        "distractor2": "proportional",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation",
        "distractor4": "flat "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal income tax is an example of a ________ tax.",
        "correct_answer": "progressive",
        "distractor1": "proportional",
        "distractor2": "regressive",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation",
        "distractor4": "flat "
    },
    {
        "question": "The best evidence indicates that the overall incidence of taxesรฎโฌโlocal, state, and federalรฎโฌโinAmerica is",
        "correct_answer": "proportional.",
        "distractor1": "progressive.",
        "distractor2": "regressive.",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation.",
        "distractor4": "flat. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The overall incidence of taxes in America is proportional, because",
        "correct_answer": "generally regressive state and local taxes are counterbalanced by progressive federal taxes.",
        "distractor1": "federal, state, and local taxes all tend to be proportional.",
        "distractor2": "generally regressive federal taxes are counterbalanced by more progressive state and local taxes.",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation serves as a counterbalance at each level.",
        "distractor4": "federal taxes are proportional. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Government's main tools for influencing the distribution of income and wealth are",
        "correct_answer": "income taxation and expenditure policies.",
        "distractor1": "equal opportunity and affirmative action programs.",
        "distractor2": "extending eligibility for welfare and Medicare benefits.",
        "distractor3": "legislating and enforcing economic policies.",
        "distractor4": "monetary policy and wage and price controls. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If the government takes a bigger bite from the income of a rich family than from the income ofa poor family, then the tax system is",
        "correct_answer": "progressive.",
        "distractor1": "proportional.",
        "distractor2": "regressive.",
        "distractor3": "redistributive.",
        "distractor4": "retrogressive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If one person earns twice as much as another, but each pays 15 percent of their income intaxes, then the tax system is",
        "correct_answer": "proportional.",
        "distractor1": "progressive.",
        "distractor2": "regressive.",
        "distractor3": "redistributive.",
        "distractor4": "egalitarian. "
    },
    {
        "question": "If a poor family pays 50 percent of its income in taxes and a rich one 5 percent, then the taxsystem is",
        "correct_answer": "regressive.",
        "distractor1": "progressive.",
        "distractor2": "proportional.",
        "distractor3": "redistributive.",
        "distractor4": "retrogressive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A tax that can make the rich richer and the poor poorer is a",
        "correct_answer": "regressive tax.",
        "distractor1": "flat tax.",
        "distractor2": "progressive tax.",
        "distractor3": "proportional tax.",
        "distractor4": "graduated tax. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The best evidence indicates that the overall incidence of taxes in America is",
        "correct_answer": "proportional.",
        "distractor1": "progressive.",
        "distractor2": "regressive.",
        "distractor3": "redistributive.",
        "distractor4": "relative deprivation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The biggest chunk of transfer payments goes to",
        "correct_answer": "the elderly and other recipients of social security.",
        "distractor1": "means-tested programs in general.",
        "distractor2": "Temporary Aid to Needy Families (TANF) in particular.",
        "distractor3": "unmarried black females with children.",
        "distractor4": "foreign aid. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Food Stamps, low-interest student loans, and Temporary Aid to Needy Families are allexamples of",
        "correct_answer": "transfer payments.",
        "distractor1": "regressive taxes.",
        "distractor2": "entitlements.",
        "distractor3": "relative deprivation.",
        "distractor4": "proportional taxes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A transfer payment is one which",
        "correct_answer": "provides money from the government's general treasury to those in specific need.",
        "distractor1": "requires some form of work in exchange for government assistance.",
        "distractor2": "is paid in lieu of cash.",
        "distractor3": "is not based on need.",
        "distractor4": "provides tax credits from the government general treasury to those in need. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a means-tested program?",
        "correct_answer": "Medicare",
        "distractor1": "Medicaid",
        "distractor2": "Food Stamps",
        "distractor3": "Aid to Families with Dependent Children",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an example of an entitlement?",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security",
        "distractor1": "Food Stamps",
        "distractor2": "Aid to Families with Dependent Children",
        "distractor3": "low-interest college loans",
        "distractor4": "Pell Grants "
    },
    {
        "question": "Transfer payments",
        "correct_answer": "consist of cash and in-kind benefits from the government.",
        "distractor1": "are part of the proposed changes to make taxation more proportional.",
        "distractor2": "have significantly redistributed income in America.",
        "distractor3": "have the net effect of being regressive.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Transfer payments have",
        "correct_answer": "raised many of the poor above the poverty line.",
        "distractor1": "significantly redistributed income in America.",
        "distractor2": "created greater income equality.",
        "distractor3": "have had virtually no affect on poverty in America.",
        "distractor4": "conspicuously bypassed the elderly, while helping many other groups. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social Security and Medicare",
        "correct_answer": "are the largest and most expensive social welfare programs in America.",
        "distractor1": "require an income and means test for eligibility.",
        "distractor2": "have had little effect on the health and income of older Americans.",
        "distractor3": "are voluntary programs aimed specifically at the poor.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following programs receives the most funding?",
        "correct_answer": "Medicare",
        "distractor1": "Medicaid",
        "distractor2": "Food Stamps",
        "distractor3": "Aid to Families with Dependent Children",
        "distractor4": "Supplemental Security Income "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicaid provides",
        "correct_answer": "medical and hospital aid to the poor on the basis of need through federally assisted state health programs.",
        "distractor1": "hospital care for the retired and disabled people covered by Social Security.",
        "distractor2": "medical insurance to those over 65 and disabled.",
        "distractor3": "cash payments to aged, blind, or disabled people whose income is below a certain amount.",
        "distractor4": "hospital care for people covered by Social Security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Martin Gilens, whites ยน attitudes toward welfare are strongly influenced by",
        "correct_answer": "whether they viewed African Americans as lazy or not.",
        "distractor1": "whether they had ever personally experienced poverty.",
        "distractor2": "their religious beliefs about caring for the poor.",
        "distractor3": "their current wealth.",
        "distractor4": "their educational background. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The feminization of poverty refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the high incidence of poverty among unmarried mothers and their children.",
        "distractor1": "high poverty levels among the elderly, who tend to be female.",
        "distractor2": "higher incarceration rates of women today compared to twenty years ago.",
        "distractor3": "higher rates of homelessness among women.",
        "distractor4": "the high incidence of poverty among married mothers and their children. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Means-tested public assistance programs",
        "correct_answer": "were strengthened as a result of Lyndon Johnson's   War on Poverty.  ",
        "distractor1": "are funded at much higher levels than entitlement programs.",
        "distractor2": "were eliminated by President Reagan.",
        "distractor3": "include Medicare, Unemployment Insurance and Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance.",
        "distractor4": "were eliminated by President Bush. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________, passed by Congress in 1935, dramatically brought the government into theequation of one generation's obligations to another.",
        "correct_answer": "Social Security Act",
        "distractor1": "Aid to Families with Dependent Children Act",
        "distractor2": "Medicaid bill",
        "distractor3": "National Direct Student Loan Act",
        "distractor4": "Medicare Bill "
    },
    {
        "question": "Social Security was begun in the United States during",
        "correct_answer": "the New Deal.",
        "distractor1": "the Civil War.",
        "distractor2": "World War I.",
        "distractor3": "the Great Society era.",
        "distractor4": "Spanish American War. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Social Security Act of 1935",
        "correct_answer": "brought government into the equation of the obligations of one generation to another.",
        "distractor1": "substantially freed adults from the obligation of caring for both their children and parents.",
        "distractor2": "provided for free medical care for all citizens over the age of 65 until it was repealed by the Republican congress of 1953.",
        "distractor3": "freed American citizens from the obligation of supporting the poor.",
        "distractor4": "substantially freed children and adults from paying their parents ยน medical expenses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   War on Poverty   was the set of social welfare policy initiatives begun by President",
        "correct_answer": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor1": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt.",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor4": "Harry S. Truman. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   War on Poverty   programs were later attacked and had their funding reducedsubstantially by President",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor1": "Dwight Eisenhower.",
        "distractor2": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor4": "George Bush. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following presidents did not accept or expand many of the programs initiatedunder Johnson's   War on Poverty  ?",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor1": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor2": "Gerald Ford",
        "distractor3": "Jimmy Carter",
        "distractor4": "both Nixon and Reagan "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Ronald Reagan ________ the   War on Poverty   programs.",
        "correct_answer": "severely reduced many of",
        "distractor1": "was the mastermind behind the passage of",
        "distractor2": "continued to support",
        "distractor3": "completely abolished",
        "distractor4": "enhanced the scope of "
    },
    {
        "question": "Charles Murray's evaluation of the Great Society programs concluded they",
        "correct_answer": "did not curb the spread of poverty, and actually increased the number of the nation's poor.",
        "distractor1": "helped to curb the spread of poverty and made the situation much better for millions of the nation's poor.",
        "distractor2": "helped to curb the spread of poverty, but did not make the situation any better for the nation's poor.",
        "distractor3": "helped to curb the spread of poverty, but actually made the situation worse for the nation's poor.",
        "distractor4": "did not curb the spread of poverty, but strengthened the family as a social institution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Charles Murray's study of the programs of the Great Society concluded all of the followingEXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "a key problem all along was inadequate funding to see the anti -poverty programs through.",
        "distractor1": "public policies discouraged the poor from solving their own problems.",
        "distractor2": "the programs actually made it profitable to be poor and victimized.",
        "distractor3": "many of the programs not only failed to halt the spread of poverty, they actually made matters worse.",
        "distractor4": "many of the programs actually increase poverty in the U.S. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Criticisms of the current welfare system include each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "they do not include a means test to weed out welfare fraud.",
        "distractor1": "they discourage the poor from solving their problems.",
        "distractor2": "they make it profitable to be poor and victimized.",
        "distractor3": "they discourage poor people from saving money.",
        "distractor4": "they discourage recipients from getting married or even living together. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Martin Gilens research suggested that Americans ยน opposition to welfare was based on",
        "correct_answer": "negative attitudes toward blacks.",
        "distractor1": "economic self-interest.",
        "distractor2": "conservative political ideology.",
        "distractor3": "negative attitudes toward the poor.",
        "distractor4": "negative attitudes toward government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Each of the following were provisions of the 1996 welfare reform bill EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "basic health care benefits would be provided to those who found jobs.",
        "distractor1": "each state would receive a fixed amount of money to run its own welfare programs.",
        "distractor2": "people on welfare would have to find work within two years or lose all their benefits.",
        "distractor3": "a lifetime maximum of five years on welfare was set.",
        "distractor4": "All of the above were provisional the 1996 welfare reform bill. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nationally, over the past six decades, there has been a particularly strong redistribution ofgovernment benefits in favor of the",
        "correct_answer": "elderly.",
        "distractor1": "very wealthy.",
        "distractor2": "corporations.",
        "distractor3": "nation's children.",
        "distractor4": "middle class. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to other industrialized countries, the United States ________ in providing a safetynet for all its citizens and in lifting a greater percentage of the poor above the poverty line withvarious programs.",
        "correct_answer": "does worse",
        "distractor1": "does much better",
        "distractor2": "does somewhat better",
        "distractor3": "does about the same",
        "distractor4": "does something similar "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States differs from other industrial countries in regard to social welfare in all of thefollowing ways EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "only the Scandinavian countries spend a smaller proportion of their gross national products on social welfare policies than does the United States.",
        "distractor1": "the United States does not have a comprehensive family leave policy.",
        "distractor2": "Americans tend to see poverty and social welfare needs as individual rather than government concerns.",
        "distractor3": "Europeans tend to see government in a more positive light, while Americans tend to distrust government action.",
        "distractor4": "the universal provision of daycare to toddlers, paid for by the government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to most Western democracies, the United States provides",
        "correct_answer": "relatively few social welfare benefits.",
        "distractor1": "selective rather than universal social welfare payments.",
        "distractor2": "an average amount of social welfare benefits.",
        "distractor3": "more cash transfers, but fewer in-kind transfers.",
        "distractor4": "overly generous social welfare benefits. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to Western European nations, the United States has a ________ infant mortalityrate.",
        "correct_answer": "higher",
        "distractor1": "nearly identical",
        "distractor2": "slightly lower",
        "distractor3": "significantly lower",
        "distractor4": "faster growing "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countries has the highest infant mortality rate?",
        "correct_answer": "United States",
        "distractor1": "France",
        "distractor2": "Japan",
        "distractor3": "Italy",
        "distractor4": "Canada "
    },
    {
        "question": "Health care in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "constitutes nearly 15 percent of America's gross domestic product.",
        "distractor1": "has decreased in cost due to the technological revolution.",
        "distractor2": "has made the United States the healthiest country in the world.",
        "distractor3": "has failed to keep up with the technological revolution.",
        "distractor4": "All of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countries has the lowest life expectancy?",
        "correct_answer": "United States",
        "distractor1": "Italy",
        "distractor2": "Japan",
        "distractor3": "Canada",
        "distractor4": "France "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a reason that American health care expenses are so high?",
        "correct_answer": "High-tech care is available for previously untreatable conditions.",
        "distractor1": "Americans visit the doctor more often.",
        "distractor2": "Americans have longer hospital stays.",
        "distractor3": "Doctors practice   offensive medicine   to avoid medical liability.",
        "distractor4": "All of the above. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans have ________ health care.",
        "correct_answer": "high-tech, expensive, and unequal",
        "distractor1": "low-tech, inexpensive, and unequal",
        "distractor2": "high-tech, expensive, and equal",
        "distractor3": "low-tech, expensive, and unequal",
        "distractor4": "high tech, inexpensive and equal "
    },
    {
        "question": "The infant mortality rate in the United States",
        "correct_answer": "ranks 18th among the world's nations.",
        "distractor1": "is the lowest in the world.",
        "distractor2": "is second lowest in the world after Japan.",
        "distractor3": "is only worse than Finland, Japan, and Iceland.",
        "distractor4": "is half of what it is in Japan. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following contributes to higher costs of medical care in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "Insured patients have little incentive to ask for cheaper care.",
        "distractor1": "The best doctors tend to practice abroad where insurance premiums are lower.",
        "distractor2": "Americans are the healthiest people in the world.",
        "distractor3": "Malpractice insurance costs for doctors are covered by the federal government.",
        "distractor4": "None of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Doctors have no reason to compete with each other to offer cheaper health care expensesbecause",
        "correct_answer": "insurance companies and government pay for most health care expenses.",
        "distractor1": "government mandates that everyone receives equal access to health care.",
        "distractor2": "technology has made medical care more efficient and less costly.",
        "distractor3": "specialization has made competition unnecessary.",
        "distractor4": "All of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Access to health insurance in the United States is strongly related to",
        "correct_answer": "race and income.",
        "distractor1": "race and geographic location.",
        "distractor2": "gender and income.",
        "distractor3": "gender and geographic location.",
        "distractor4": "race and gender. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ is part of the Social Security system and covers 40 million American seniors withhospitalization insurance and other optional health insurance.",
        "correct_answer": "Medicare",
        "distractor1": "Medicaid",
        "distractor2": "The National Institutes of Health",
        "distractor3": "The Superfund",
        "distractor4": "The United States Health Service "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the United States, the largest single source of health care dollars comes from",
        "correct_answer": "government.",
        "distractor1": "private insurance companies.",
        "distractor2": "private charities.",
        "distractor3": "citizens themselves in out-of-pocket medical payments.",
        "distractor4": "the private sector. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States government finances much of the medical research done in the countrythrough",
        "correct_answer": "the National Institutes of Health.",
        "distractor1": "Medicaid.",
        "distractor2": "the National Endowment for Medical Research.",
        "distractor3": "the National Science Foundation.",
        "distractor4": "the Department of Health and Human Services. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Institutes of Health",
        "correct_answer": "provides funds for medical research in the United States.",
        "distractor1": "administers the national health insurance system in the United States.",
        "distractor2": "is the largest hospital and physicians ยน interest group in the United States.",
        "distractor3": "administers the Medicare and Medicaid programs.",
        "distractor4": "is the federal agency that regulates private health insurance companies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans pay about ________ of their health care costs out of their own pockets.",
        "correct_answer": "20 percent",
        "distractor1": "4 percent",
        "distractor2": "40 percent",
        "distractor3": "33 percent",
        "distractor4": "54 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicare was adopted in 1965 to provide government health insurance to",
        "correct_answer": "the elderly.",
        "distractor1": "veterans.",
        "distractor2": "government employees.",
        "distractor3": "the poor.",
        "distractor4": "children living in poverty. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first president to call for national health insurance was",
        "correct_answer": "Harry Truman.",
        "distractor1": "Franklin Roosevelt.",
        "distractor2": "Lyndon Johnson.",
        "distractor3": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor4": "Bill Clinton. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The federal program that permits older Americans to purchase inexpensive coverage fordoctor fees and other non-hospital expenses is",
        "correct_answer": "Medicare Part B.",
        "distractor1": "Medicare Part A.",
        "distractor2": "Medicaid.",
        "distractor3": "social insurance program.",
        "distractor4": "the American Association of Retired Persons. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Medicaid is a program designed to provide health care for",
        "correct_answer": "the very poor.",
        "distractor1": "the elderly.",
        "distractor2": "everyone who lives below the poverty line.",
        "distractor3": "veterans.",
        "distractor4": "Social Security recipients. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about Medicaid?",
        "correct_answer": "It provides health care for all poor Americans.",
        "distractor1": "It is funded by both the states and national government.",
        "distractor2": "It is a means-tested program.",
        "distractor3": "The costs of Medicaid are increasing rapidly.",
        "distractor4": "States have cut Medicaid coverage in recent years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest voluntary association in the world?",
        "correct_answer": "American Association of Retired Persons",
        "distractor1": "Sierra Club",
        "distractor2": "International Association of Workers and Peasants",
        "distractor3": "National Patients ยน Union",
        "distractor4": "Chinese Revolutionary Workers ยน Party "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the American Association of Retired Persons isFALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Its widespread respect and authority are due to the fact that it has avoided involvement in political activity.",
        "distractor1": "It is the largest voluntary association in the world.",
        "distractor2": "It can claim to represent one American in eight.",
        "distractor3": "It speaks with authority on all questions associated with the elderly.",
        "distractor4": "Its membership has been growing dramatically. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Business groups are becoming increasingly active in health care policymaking because",
        "correct_answer": "private employers often pay the insurance premiums for their employees.",
        "distractor1": "businesses contribute the most taxes that pay for Medicare and Medicaid.",
        "distractor2": "businesses are run primarily by elderly Americans who have a vested interest in health care.",
        "distractor3": "healthy employees are more profitable to businesses.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary focus of President Clinton's Health Security Act was",
        "correct_answer": "providing health care for all Americans.",
        "distractor1": "fraud on the part of insurance companies.",
        "distractor2": "rationing and access.",
        "distractor3": "the establishment of national health insurance.",
        "distractor4": "the elderly. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under Bill Clinton's proposed Health Security Act, the brunt of the increased health care costswould have fallen most directly on",
        "correct_answer": "employers.",
        "distractor1": "employees.",
        "distractor2": "those who purchased tobacco, alcohol, and pornography.",
        "distractor3": "patients.",
        "distractor4": "doctors. "
    },
    {
        "question": "George W. Bush's proposal for lowering medical costs by encouraging health savings accountscan best be described as",
        "correct_answer": "market based.",
        "distractor1": "socialist.",
        "distractor2": "popular.",
        "distractor3": "cheap.",
        "distractor4": "egalitarian. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which aspect of health care costs has increased the fastest?",
        "correct_answer": "prescription drugs",
        "distractor1": "emergency room care",
        "distractor2": "prenatal care",
        "distractor3": "out-patient surgery",
        "distractor4": "treatment for drug and alcohol abuse "
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following, who can not be considered a strong advocate for stem cell research?",
        "correct_answer": "George W. Bush",
        "distractor1": "Michael J. Fox",
        "distractor2": "Nancy Reagan",
        "distractor3": "Christopher Reeve",
        "distractor4": "the State of California "
    },
    {
        "question": "Oregon started rationing health care provided under Medicaid by",
        "correct_answer": "deciding not to pay for some costly treatments in order to provide medical care to more people.",
        "distractor1": "moving toward greater high-tech breakthroughs in medicine.",
        "distractor2": "giving everyone a certain number of health care   credits,   which they can spend annually as they see fit.",
        "distractor3": "requiring Medicaid recipients to stop bearing children in order to receive free health coverage for their present families.",
        "distractor4": "distributing Medicare patients to a greater number of physicians. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The enforcement of the Clean Air Act and other anti-pollution legislation is administered bywhat regulatory body?",
        "correct_answer": "Environmental Protection Agency",
        "distractor1": "Department of Interior",
        "distractor2": "Department of Justice",
        "distractor3": "Occupational Safety and Health Administration",
        "distractor4": "Federal Pollution Board "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about the Environmental Protection Agency?",
        "correct_answer": "It was established in the 1910s.",
        "distractor1": "It is the nation's largest regulatory agency.",
        "distractor2": "It is in charge of administering policies dealing with toxic wastes such as dangerous chemicals.",
        "distractor3": "It enforces the Clean Air Act, the Water Pollution Control Act, and many other environmental bills.",
        "distractor4": "The head of the EPA is a cabinet member. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Environmental Policy Act, the Clean Air Act, and the Water Pollution ControlAct are implemented by the",
        "correct_answer": "Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).",
        "distractor1": "Department of the Interior (DOI).",
        "distractor2": "Department of Transportation (DOT).",
        "distractor3": "Department of Energy (DOE).",
        "distractor4": "President's National Environmental Council. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Clean Air Act of 1970",
        "correct_answer": "empowered the Department of Transportation to authorize mandatory reductions in automobile emissions.",
        "distractor1": "banned cigarette advertisements on television.",
        "distractor2": "empowered the Department of Interior with enforcing tough anti -pollution laws on industries near national forests or national parks.",
        "distractor3": "never passed Congress due to economic concerns about its effect.",
        "distractor4": "banned cigarette smoking in public buildings. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The smaller size of American cars, the use of unleaded gasoline, and the lower gasconsumption of new cars are all due in large part to",
        "correct_answer": "Department of Transportation regulations.",
        "distractor1": "self-regulation of the automobile industry.",
        "distractor2": "Supreme Court rulings.",
        "distractor3": "consumer demands.",
        "distractor4": "the dramatic increases of Middle Eastern oil prices in the 1970s. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Auto companies have been partially successful in their efforts to delay implementation of",
        "correct_answer": "clean air standards.",
        "distractor1": "mandatory air bag requirements.",
        "distractor2": "oil price deregulation.",
        "distractor3": "the National Environmental Policy Act.",
        "distractor4": "auto safety legislation. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Water Pollution Control Act of 1972 has successfully",
        "correct_answer": "improved the water quality of the Great Lakes and northeastern rivers.",
        "distractor1": "chlorinated the water systems of nearly every major city.",
        "distractor2": "abolished ocean dumping.",
        "distractor3": "banned all oil drilling in off-shore rigs.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "About ________ of the United States is now designated as protected wilderness.",
        "correct_answer": "4 percent",
        "distractor1": "12 percent",
        "distractor2": "24 percent",
        "distractor3": "35 percent",
        "distractor4": "17 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Half of the designated wilderness area in the United States is located in",
        "correct_answer": "Alaska.",
        "distractor1": "New England.",
        "distractor2": "Texas.",
        "distractor3": "California.",
        "distractor4": "the Rocky Mountains. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Perhaps the most consistently successful environmental campaigns in the post -war era havebeen those aimed at",
        "correct_answer": "wilderness preservation.",
        "distractor1": "air pollution.",
        "distractor2": "water pollution.",
        "distractor3": "energy conservation.",
        "distractor4": "toxic waste cleanup. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Endangered Species Act of 1973, as originally passed, required that the government",
        "correct_answer": "actively protect each of the hundreds of species listed as endangered, regardless of the economic effect on the surrounding region.",
        "distractor1": "choose which species were significant enough to protect from extinction, while others would be allowed to die off.",
        "distractor2": "merely acknowledge that some species were likely to go extinct.",
        "distractor3": "actively protect each of the hundreds of species listed as endangered unless that protection would cause severe economic harm to the local region.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Superfund is paid for by",
        "correct_answer": "taxes on chemical products.",
        "distractor1": "a voluntary check-off system on federal income tax forms.",
        "distractor2": "a special tax on automobiles, trucks, snowmobiles, and motorized farm vehicles.",
        "distractor3": "the federal gasoline tax.",
        "distractor4": "aviation fuel taxes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about Superfund?",
        "correct_answer": "It has successfully located and isolated the country's toxic waste dump sites and has completely cleaned more than half of those sites.",
        "distractor1": "Taxes on chemical products are used to pay for it.",
        "distractor2": "It was created by Congress in part to respond to the Love Canal disaster in New York state.",
        "distractor3": "Its costs represent the fastest growing segment of the nation's environmental budget.",
        "distractor4": "It is administered by the EPA. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Superfund was created to",
        "correct_answer": "clean up toxic waste.",
        "distractor1": "preserve endangered species.",
        "distractor2": "buy land for wilderness protection.",
        "distractor3": "finance the national park system.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "A large number of legal suits currently involve conflicts over who will pay to",
        "correct_answer": "clean up radioactive wastes.",
        "distractor1": "protect endangered species.",
        "distractor2": "fund environmental research.",
        "distractor3": "administer wilderness preserves.",
        "distractor4": "purchase new wilderness lands. "
    },
    {
        "question": "After more than a decade of political delays, President Bush in 2002 signed off onCongressional legislation choosing Yucca Flats, Nevada, as the",
        "correct_answer": "site for the long-term storage of nuclear waste.",
        "distractor1": " official location of the Superfund.",
        "distractor2": " new office location of the EPA.",
        "distractor3": " only remaining pristine wilderness in the United States.",
        "distractor4": "site for the destruction of nuclear weapons. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An estimated 90 percent of the energy resources of the United States is in",
        "correct_answer": "coal deposits.",
        "distractor1": "oil reserves.",
        "distractor2": "natural gas reserves.",
        "distractor3": "uranium deposits.",
        "distractor4": "water. "
    },
    {
        "question": "America's coal deposits are expected to last",
        "correct_answer": "for hundreds of years.",
        "distractor1": "15 more years.",
        "distractor2": "50 more years.",
        "distractor3": "for thousands of years.",
        "distractor4": "forever, as coal is a renewable resource. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of coal?",
        "correct_answer": "It accounts for half the energy Americans use.",
        "distractor1": "It is the nation's most abundant fuel.",
        "distractor2": "It is responsible for the   black lungs   health hazard to coal miners.",
        "distractor3": "Its use to produce electricity is linked to acid rain.",
        "distractor4": "About 90 percent of all of America's energy resources are in coal. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The   dirtiest   type of fuel is",
        "correct_answer": "coal.",
        "distractor1": "oil.",
        "distractor2": "natural gas.",
        "distractor3": "nuclear fuel.",
        "distractor4": "wood. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most controversial energy source is",
        "correct_answer": "nuclear fuel.",
        "distractor1": "coal.",
        "distractor2": "oil.",
        "distractor3": "natural gas.",
        "distractor4": "solar. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Global warming refers to",
        "correct_answer": "the expectation that the Earth's atmosphere is becoming warmer due to high levels of carbon monoxide production.",
        "distractor1": "the expectation that the Earth's atmosphere is becoming warmer due to the decreasing size of ice masses in Antarctica.",
        "distractor2": "the expectation that the world will share a common weather pattern by the year 2010.",
        "distractor3": "the spread of nuclear power throughout the world.",
        "distractor4": "the melting of the polar ice caps. "
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of 1997, 150 nations met in Kyoto, Japan, and agreed in principle to",
        "correct_answer": "reduce their emissions of greenhouse gases below 1990 levels by about 2010.",
        "distractor1": "stop producing carbon monoxide.",
        "distractor2": "increase their reliance on renewable resources by 200 percent of their 1990 levels.",
        "distractor3": "offer tax incentives for reducing carbon monoxide production.",
        "distractor4": "stop using nuclear energy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a renewable resource?",
        "correct_answer": "solar energy",
        "distractor1": "coal",
        "distractor2": "natural gas",
        "distractor3": "oil",
        "distractor4": "nuclear "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are instruments of foreign policy EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "taxation.",
        "distractor1": "military.",
        "distractor2": "economic.",
        "distractor3": "diplomacy.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Diplomacy refers to",
        "correct_answer": "formal and informal communications with representatives of other governments.",
        "distractor1": "regulation of international travel.",
        "distractor2": "the exchange of military officials between countries.",
        "distractor3": "a recent philosophy regarding world relations.",
        "distractor4": "multi-sided arms negotiations. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United Nations was created in",
        "correct_answer": "1945.",
        "distractor1": "1789.",
        "distractor2": "1865.",
        "distractor3": "1967.",
        "distractor4": "1919. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Member countries of the United Nations agree to",
        "correct_answer": "renounce war and respect certain human and economic freedoms.",
        "distractor1": "elect their leaders through the democratic process.",
        "distractor2": "adopt the United States Constitution as their model for self-government.",
        "distractor3": "limit the organization's activities to a peacekeeping function, and not involve themselves in economic development or health, education, and welfare concerns.",
        "distractor4": "adopt capitalist economic systems. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United Nations General Assembly is made up of about ________ members.",
        "correct_answer": "185",
        "distractor1": "15",
        "distractor2": "60",
        "distractor3": "320",
        "distractor4": "144 "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the real focus of power in the United Nations.",
        "correct_answer": "Security Council",
        "distractor1": "General Assembly",
        "distractor2": "Foreign Relations Committee",
        "distractor3": "Secretariat",
        "distractor4": "Secretary General "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United Nations Security Council has ________ members.",
        "correct_answer": "15",
        "distractor1": "5",
        "distractor2": "35",
        "distractor3": "175",
        "distractor4": "100 "
    },
    {
        "question": "On the United Nations Security Council, ________ countries have permanent seats.",
        "correct_answer": "5",
        "distractor1": "no",
        "distractor2": "2",
        "distractor3": "15",
        "distractor4": "9 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a permanent member country on the United Nations SecurityCouncil?",
        "correct_answer": "Japan",
        "distractor1": "Great Britain",
        "distractor2": "China",
        "distractor3": "France",
        "distractor4": "Russia "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United Nations is composed of nearly 200",
        "correct_answer": "nations.",
        "distractor1": "civil servants.",
        "distractor2": "diplomats.",
        "distractor3": "nations and international organizations.",
        "distractor4": "regional caucuses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "New actors on the world stage include all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "diplomats.",
        "distractor1": "international organizations.",
        "distractor2": "non-governmental organizations.",
        "distractor3": "multinational corporations.",
        "distractor4": "tourists. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The European Union is an example of a ________ organization.",
        "correct_answer": "regional ",
        "distractor1": "nongovernmental",
        "distractor2": "domestic",
        "distractor3": "military",
        "distractor4": "diplomatic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regional organizations have ________ in the post -World War II era.",
        "correct_answer": "proliferated",
        "distractor1": "declined in number",
        "distractor2": "decreased in influence",
        "distractor3": "disappeared",
        "distractor4": "remained active "
    },
    {
        "question": "Permanent members of the United Nations Security Council have",
        "correct_answer": "veto power over any Security Council decisions, including any effort to deploy UN peacekeeping troops.",
        "distractor1": "two votes each on the Security Council, making them more important than non-permanent members.",
        "distractor2": "no more or no less clout on the Security Council than the non-permanent members, just guaranteed membership.",
        "distractor3": "no voting power on the Security Council, but are guaranteed the right to listen in or speak at any meeting.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait, the United Nations",
        "correct_answer": "authorized an embargo on the shipment of goods into and out of Iraq, then authorized the use of force against Iraq.",
        "distractor1": "sided with Iraq, but many countries refused to go along.",
        "distractor2": "authorized an embargo on the shipment of goods into and out of Iraq, but would not authorize the use of military force.",
        "distractor3": "remained a neutral ground for diplomacy, siding neither with nor against Iraq's actions, but calling for a peaceful resolution.",
        "distractor4": "sided with Iraq. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The seat of real power in the United Nations is the",
        "correct_answer": "Security Council.",
        "distractor1": "General Assembly.",
        "distractor2": "World Bank.",
        "distractor3": "Superpower Caucus.",
        "distractor4": "Secretariat. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The North Atlantic Treaty Organization is an example of a",
        "correct_answer": "regional organization for military purposes.",
        "distractor1": "United Nations agency.",
        "distractor2": "regional organization for economic purposes.",
        "distractor3": "multinational corporation.",
        "distractor4": "global organization for military purposes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Cold War era, the Soviet Union and its Eastern European allies formed a regionalorganization known as the",
        "correct_answer": "Warsaw Pact.",
        "distractor1": "Iron Curtain.",
        "distractor2": "European Economic Community.",
        "distractor3": "Trilateral Commission.",
        "distractor4": "Geneva Convention. "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Cold War era, more than a million ________ troops were spread from WestGermany to Portugal.",
        "correct_answer": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization",
        "distractor1": "Trilateral Commission",
        "distractor2": "German",
        "distractor3": "United Nations peacekeeping",
        "distractor4": "United Nations combat "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is a regional economic organization of major nations.",
        "correct_answer": "European Union",
        "distractor1": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization",
        "distractor2": "Warsaw Pact",
        "distractor3": "Trilateral Commission",
        "distractor4": "Geneva Convention "
    },
    {
        "question": "Multinational corporations",
        "correct_answer": "have been known to link forces with the CIA to overturn governments they disliked.",
        "distractor1": "are usually strictly regulated by their host country.",
        "distractor2": "are among the oldest actors on the international stage.",
        "distractor3": "contribute two-thirds of the world's industrial output.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of an interest group involved in international affairs would be",
        "correct_answer": "Greenpeace.",
        "distractor1": "the World Bank.",
        "distractor2": "the European Economic Community.",
        "distractor3": "tourists.",
        "distractor4": "immigrants. "
    },
    {
        "question": "As chief diplomat, the president does all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "entertains foreign heads of state.",
        "distractor1": "negotiates treaties.",
        "distractor2": "deploys troops abroad.",
        "distractor3": "appoints United States ambassadors.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is the primary foreign policy arm of the United States government.",
        "correct_answer": "State Department",
        "distractor1": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor2": "Joint Chiefs of Staff",
        "distractor3": "National Security Council",
        "distractor4": "Central Intelligence Agency "
    },
    {
        "question": "After the president, the ________ is considered the nation's foremost diplomat in the UnitedStates.",
        "correct_answer": "Secretary of State",
        "distractor1": "National Security Adviser",
        "distractor2": "Secretary of Defense",
        "distractor3": "United States Ambassador to the United Nations",
        "distractor4": "chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ staffs United States embassies and consulates in about 300 overseas posts fromAlbania to Zimbabwe, representing the interests of Americans.",
        "correct_answer": "State Department",
        "distractor1": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor2": "Justice Department",
        "distractor3": "National Security Council",
        "distractor4": "Executive Office of the President "
    },
    {
        "question": "The head of the foreign policy arm of the federal government who traditionally advises thepresident is the",
        "correct_answer": "Secretary of State.",
        "distractor1": "National Security Assistant.",
        "distractor2": "Secretary of Defense.",
        "distractor3": "United States Ambassador to the United Nations.",
        "distractor4": "chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Many recent presidents have bypassed the Secretary of State for foreign policy advice andcome to rely more on the",
        "correct_answer": "special assistant for National Security Affairs.",
        "distractor1": "Secretary of Defense.",
        "distractor2": "United States Ambassador to the United Nations.",
        "distractor3": "Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor4": "National Security Council. "
    },
    {
        "question": "  The Pentagon   refers to the",
        "correct_answer": "Department of Defense.",
        "distractor1": "State Department.",
        "distractor2": "Foreign Service.",
        "distractor3": "Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor4": "Department of Homeland Security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The commanding officers of each of the services, plus a chair, constitute the",
        "correct_answer": "Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor1": "Armed Services Committee.",
        "distractor2": "National Security Council.",
        "distractor3": "Department of Defense.",
        "distractor4": "Central Intelligence Agency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The president's principal civilian adviser on the military is the",
        "correct_answer": "Secretary of Defense.",
        "distractor1": "National Security Adviser.",
        "distractor2": "Secretary of State.",
        "distractor3": "chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor4": "director of the Central Intelligence Agency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The chief role of the Secretary of Defense is to",
        "correct_answer": "manage the military budget.",
        "distractor1": "be the president's chief foreign policy advisor.",
        "distractor2": "coordinate American foreign and military policy.",
        "distractor3": "act as Commander in Chief of the armed forces.",
        "distractor4": "declare war. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Security Council is officially composed of the president and all of the followingEXCEPT the",
        "correct_answer": "director of the Central Intelligence Agency.",
        "distractor1": "Secretary of Defense.",
        "distractor2": "Secretary of State.",
        "distractor3": "vice president.",
        "distractor4": "Secretary of Homeland Security. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is officially composed of the president, the vice president, the Secretary ofDefense and the Secretary of State.",
        "correct_answer": "National Security Council",
        "distractor1": "National Security Agency",
        "distractor2": "Pentagon",
        "distractor3": "Joint Chiefs of Staff",
        "distractor4": "Trilateral Commission "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ was formed in 1947 to coordinate American foreign and military policies andadvise the president.",
        "correct_answer": "National Security Council",
        "distractor1": "State Department",
        "distractor2": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor3": "Joint Chiefs of Staff",
        "distractor4": "Central Intelligence Agency "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Iran-Contra affair erupted in 1986 when it came to light that members of the ________were involved in a secret operation selling arms to Iran in return for Iranian help in returningAmerican hostages held in Lebanon, and using money from the arms sale to fund rebels inNicaragua.",
        "correct_answer": "National Security Council staff",
        "distractor1": "Joint Chiefs of Staff",
        "distractor2": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor3": "State Department",
        "distractor4": "Central Intelligence Agency "
    },
    {
        "question": "The government body responsible for coordinating foreign and military policy is the",
        "correct_answer": "National Security Council.",
        "distractor1": "Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor2": "Central Intelligence Agency.",
        "distractor3": "State Department.",
        "distractor4": "Department of Defense. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Iran-Contra affair involved covert activities staged by the",
        "correct_answer": "National Security Council.",
        "distractor1": "State Department.",
        "distractor2": "Pentagon.",
        "distractor3": "Central Intelligence Agency.",
        "distractor4": "Joint Chiefs of Staff. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Lieutenant Colonel Oliver North became a national celebrity when he explained hisinvolvement in the ________ to a televised Congressional hearing.",
        "correct_answer": "Iran-Contra scandal",
        "distractor1": "Watergate scandal",
        "distractor2": "defense procurement scandal",
        "distractor3": "liberation of Kuwait",
        "distractor4": "Whitewater scandal "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ was established after World War II in order to coordinate American informationand data-gathering operations abroad and to collect, analyze, and evaluate its own data.",
        "correct_answer": "CIA",
        "distractor1": "OSS",
        "distractor2": "JCS",
        "distractor3": "National Security Council",
        "distractor4": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "The CIA has never been involved in domestic affairs.",
        "distractor1": "The CIA was created after World War II to coordinate American information and intelligence activities abroad.",
        "distractor2": "The bulk of the material gathered and analyzed by the CIA comes from readily available sources.",
        "distractor3": "Congress requires the CIA to inform relevant Congressional committees of current and anticipated covert operations.",
        "distractor4": "It was involved in the overthrow of the Iranian government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ helped to overthrow the governments of Iran in 1953 and Guatemala in 1954,and has a long history of involvement in the internal affairs of other nations.",
        "correct_answer": "Central Intelligence Agency",
        "distractor1": "Department of Defense",
        "distractor2": "National Security Council",
        "distractor3": "Joint Chiefs of Staff",
        "distractor4": "Federal Bureau of Investigation "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Central Intelligence Agency is required by law to report its activities to",
        "correct_answer": "relevant Congressional committees.",
        "distractor1": "the Joint Chiefs of Staff.",
        "distractor2": "the United Nations Security Council.",
        "distractor3": "the Secretary of State.",
        "distractor4": "no one, not even the president. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A study by Richard Betts showed that the advice given to the president by the Joint Chiefs ofStaff tends to",
        "correct_answer": "be no more aggressive than advice given by civilian advisors.",
        "distractor1": "be split, with the Army and Marine Corps favoring aggressive policies and the Navy favoring peaceful policies.",
        "distractor2": "favor aggressive solutions to crises.",
        "distractor3": "be ignored by the president who listens mainly to the national security advisor.",
        "distractor4": "favor the use of nuclear weapons. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a power of Congress in foreign and defense policy?",
        "correct_answer": "to appoint ambassadors",
        "distractor1": "to declare war",
        "distractor2": "to ratify treaties",
        "distractor3": "to confirm presidential nominees to head the State Department and Department of Defense",
        "distractor4": "to provide oversight of the CIA "
    },
    {
        "question": "The foreign-policy powers of Congress",
        "correct_answer": "include raising and organizing the armed forces.",
        "distractor1": "have no constitutional basis.",
        "distractor2": "include making treaties.",
        "distractor3": "are negligible when compared with the president's.",
        "distractor4": "appoint the top military officials including the Joint Chiefs of Staff. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Throughout most of American history, American foreign policy has centered on the concept of",
        "correct_answer": "isolationism.",
        "distractor1": "brinkmanship.",
        "distractor2": "containment.",
        "distractor3": "McCarthyism.",
        "distractor4": "internationalism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Monroe Doctrine",
        "correct_answer": "showed again that America was not concerned with Europe's problems.",
        "distractor1": "ended the American policy of isolationism.",
        "distractor2": "affirmed America's intention to stay out of Latin American affairs.",
        "distractor3": "symbolized the start of the Cold War.",
        "distractor4": "first enunciated the policy of isolationism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Throughout most of its history up to the early twentieth century, the United States followed aforeign policy course of ________, particularly with regard to Europe.",
        "correct_answer": "isolationism",
        "distractor1": "internationalism",
        "distractor2": "intervention",
        "distractor3": "collective security",
        "distractor4": "laissez faire "
    },
    {
        "question": "It was, above all else, ________ that dealt a death blow to American isolationism.",
        "correct_answer": "World War II",
        "distractor1": "World War I",
        "distractor2": "the Cuban Missile Crisis",
        "distractor3": "the Vietnam War",
        "distractor4": "World War III "
    },
    {
        "question": "The death-blow to American isolationism occurred as a result of",
        "correct_answer": "World War II.",
        "distractor1": "the Monroe Doctrine.",
        "distractor2": "World War I.",
        "distractor3": "the League of Nations.",
        "distractor4": "the Soviet takeover of Eastern Europe. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The containment doctrine did not prevent the communists from winning a stunning victory in________ in 1949.",
        "correct_answer": "China",
        "distractor1": "Turkey",
        "distractor2": "West Berlin",
        "distractor3": "Taiwan",
        "distractor4": "Vietnam "
    },
    {
        "question": "America's principal foreign policy strategy toward the Soviet Union throughout the Cold War,proposed by the foreign policy strategist George Kennan in 1947, was",
        "correct_answer": "containment.",
        "distractor1": "isolationism.",
        "distractor2": "peaceful coexistence.",
        "distractor3": "covert operations.",
        "distractor4": "laissez faire. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Marshall Plan",
        "correct_answer": "poured billions of dollars into war-ravaged European nations after World War II.",
        "distractor1": "warned European nations to stay out of Latin America.",
        "distractor2": "established the containment doctrine.",
        "distractor3": "imposed democratic constitutions on Germany and Japan in the wake of World War II.",
        "distractor4": "created NATO. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The containment doctrine was",
        "correct_answer": "intended to prevent Soviet expansion after World War II.",
        "distractor1": "the policy of nuclear arms agreements to limit the spread of nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor2": "the Soviet policy of building the Iron Curtain and Berlin Wall to hold American influence to Western Europe after World War II.",
        "distractor3": "first proposed as a military maneuver during the Korean War as a means to prevent Chinese advances.",
        "distractor4": "the policy of cooperation and relaxation of tensions with the Soviet Union. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Almost immediately following World War II, the United States entered into ________ with theSoviet Union.",
        "correct_answer": "a Cold War",
        "distractor1": "the Korean War",
        "distractor2": "the Cuban Missile Crisis",
        "distractor3": "peaceful coexistence",
        "distractor4": "a lend lease plan "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 1950s, John Foster Dulles, the Secretary of State under Eisenhower, proclaimed apolicy of ________ in America's dealings with the Soviet Union.",
        "correct_answer": "brinkmanship",
        "distractor1": "containment รยด",
        "distractor2": "detente",
        "distractor3": "peaceful coexistence",
        "distractor4": "laissez faire "
    },
    {
        "question": "Fear of a serious communist conspiracy in the United States during the early years of the ColdWar led to the rise of a near panic that communism was infiltrating American government andcultural institutions, and became known as",
        "correct_answer": "McCarthyism. รยด",
        "distractor1": "brinkmanship.",
        "distractor2": "detente.",
        "distractor3": "isolationism.",
        "distractor4": "the Deep Freeze. "
    },
    {
        "question": "McCarthyism was strongest during",
        "correct_answer": "the Korean War. รยด",
        "distractor1": "World War II.",
        "distractor2": "the Vietnam War.",
        "distractor3": "detente.",
        "distractor4": "World War I. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The growth of the military budget during the 1950s under President Eisenhower led him toremark at the end of his second term that",
        "correct_answer": "the military-industrial complex that had developed between private defense contractors and the Pentagon was worrisome.",
        "distractor1": "although the Soviets were not aware of it yet, the United States had won the Cold War.",
        "distractor2": "atomic bombs should be dropped on the Soviet Union.",
        "distractor3": "due to the Soviet launching of the Sputnik satellite, peaceful coexistence between the superpowers was over.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "By the mid-1950s, defense expenditures",
        "correct_answer": "grew to be the largest component of the federal budget.",
        "distractor1": "declined below World War II levels.",
        "distractor2": "gave way to expenditures on social-welfare policies.",
        "distractor3": "reduced the profits of defense contractors.",
        "distractor4": "shifted to the Middle East to protect American oil supplies. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The rise of detente and the first Strategic Arms Limitation Treaty (SALT) were brought aboutunder President",
        "correct_answer": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor1": "Harry Truman.",
        "distractor2": "Dwight Eisenhower.",
        "distractor3": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor4": "John F. Kennedy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The relaxation of tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union throughout the1970s was known asรยด",
        "correct_answer": "detente.",
        "distractor1": "containment.",
        "distractor2": "the Strategic Defense Initiative.",
        "distractor3": "glasnost.",
        "distractor4": "New Thinking. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A product of detente was the",
        "correct_answer": "start of the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks.",
        "distractor1": "end of the Korean War.",
        "distractor2": "1979 Israeli-Egyptian peace treaty.",
        "distractor3": "creation of the United Nations.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States and Soviet Union agreement on SALT I reflected",
        "correct_answer": "a policy of detente.",
        "distractor1": "a policy of containment.",
        "distractor2": "brinkmanship. รยด",
        "distractor3": "McCarthyism.",
        "distractor4": "the two nations ยน first effort to coordinate the development of a natural resource. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The largest increase in peacetime defense spending occurred under President ________, whoargued that the Soviets had used arms control agreements to gallop ahead of the United Statesin military spending.",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan",
        "distractor1": "Gerald Ford",
        "distractor2": "Jimmy Carter",
        "distractor3": "Richard Nixon",
        "distractor4": "Harry Truman "
    },
    {
        "question": "President Ronald Reagan proposed a massive new spending program called the ________ tocreate a global umbrella in space, wherein computers would scan the skies and use varioushigh-tech devices to destroy invading missiles.",
        "correct_answer": "Strategic Defense Initiative",
        "distractor1": "brinkmanship",
        "distractor2": "Superpatriot Missile Shield",
        "distractor3": "Anti-Ballistic Missile System",
        "distractor4": "Early Warning System "
    },
    {
        "question": "During the early years of his administration, Reagan's foreign and defense policiesemphasizedรยด",
        "correct_answer": "anticommunism.",
        "distractor1": "detente.",
        "distractor2": "arms reduction talks.",
        "distractor3": "nuclear disarmament.",
        "distractor4": "international free trade agreements. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of violence to demoralize and frighten a country's population or government isreferred to as",
        "correct_answer": "terrorism.",
        "distractor1": "isolationism. รยด",
        "distractor2": "detente.",
        "distractor3": "mutual assured destruction.",
        "distractor4": "psychological warfare. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In response to the terrorist acts of September 11, 2001, the George W. Bush administration hasdeveloped a new foreign policy emphasizing",
        "correct_answer": "preemptive strikes.",
        "distractor1": "negotiation.",
        "distractor2": "deterrence. รยด",
        "distractor3": "detente.",
        "distractor4": "diplomacy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "What errors did the United States make in planning post-war Iraq?",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above",
        "distractor1": "The U.S. believed that the American soldiers would be welcomed as liberators.",
        "distractor2": "The U.S. believed that Iraqi oil revenues would pay for most reconstruction costs.",
        "distractor3": "The U.S. believed Iraqis had the skill and infrastructure to do most of the rebuilding.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Unites States originally pursued a   decapitation   strategy for confronting al -Qaida. Whatdid this strategy propose to do?",
        "correct_answer": "eliminate a small number of al-Qaida leaders",
        "distractor1": "attack the root causes of terrorism, namely poverty",
        "distractor2": "reduce America's cultural influence on the Muslim world",
        "distractor3": "execute publicly all al-Qaida members by way of the guillotine",
        "distractor4": "spread democracy to the Middle East "
    },
    {
        "question": "The threat posed by terrorist groups and the hostile states supporting them has causedAmerica to",
        "correct_answer": "reconsider basic principles of its foreign policy.",
        "distractor1": "recall many of its senior diplomats from the Middle East.",
        "distractor2": "emphasize the principles of deterrence and containment in foreign policy.",
        "distractor3": "make dramatic cuts in domestic expenditures to pay for the new war on terrorism.",
        "distractor4": "shift back to isolationism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Defense spending now makes up about ________ of the federal budget.",
        "correct_answer": "one-fifth",
        "distractor1": "one-third",
        "distractor2": "one-half",
        "distractor3": "three-fifths",
        "distractor4": "one-fourth "
    },
    {
        "question": "The phrase   guns and butter   refers to",
        "correct_answer": "what many scholars claim is the trade-off a nation faces between defense spending and social spending.",
        "distractor1": "politicians who promise money for both military and domestic spending programs.",
        "distractor2": "the general economic improvement accompanying the nation's involvement in a major war, though at a high human cost.",
        "distractor3": "the economic impact on cities and towns with military bases or large defense industries.",
        "distractor4": "the economic impact of foreign countries with large defense industries. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, American conservatives argue that the breakup of the communist regimes inEastern Europe and the demise of the Soviet Union were principally due to",
        "correct_answer": "America's defense build-up during the 1980s which the Soviet Union could not match and eventually toppled it.",
        "distractor1": "the serious defects of the Soviet economyรฎโฌโthe inertia, the wastefulness, and the corruption inherent in the system.",
        "distractor2": "Mikhail Gorbachev's unexpected and unyielding commitment to glasnost and perestroika.",
        "distractor3": "brilliant efforts over several years by various agencies and representatives of the United Nations.",
        "distractor4": "political revolution in the Soviet Union. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about defense spending is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Evidence indicates that as defense spending increases, domestic spending decreases.",
        "distractor1": "Pressures to cut defense spending and allocate funds to decrease the budget deficit are strong.",
        "distractor2": "Conservatives fight deep cuts in defense spending in order to maintain readiness at a high level.",
        "distractor3": "Liberals maintain that the Pentagon wastes money and that the United States buys too many guns and too little butter.",
        "distractor4": "Defense spending now comprises half of the federal budget. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Liberals argue that the most crucial aspect of national defense is",
        "correct_answer": "a strong economy.",
        "distractor1": "diplomacy.",
        "distractor2": "a strong military capability.",
        "distractor3": "international alliances.",
        "distractor4": "nuclear deterrence. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatever their ideology, members of Congress tend to support military spending mostconsistently",
        "correct_answer": "when it means jobs for their constituents.",
        "distractor1": "when the Pentagon argues that such programs are necessary.",
        "distractor2": "if they are asked to do so by the president.",
        "distractor3": "once a project has already begun and needs additional funding.",
        "distractor4": "during election years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The structure of America's defenses has been based on",
        "correct_answer": "a large standing military force and a triad of strategic nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor1": "complete control of the sea and large overseas bases.",
        "distractor2": "military control of outer space.",
        "distractor3": "strategic nuclear air command and a small but specialized standing army.",
        "distractor4": "the defense of our borders and the ability to fight one minor regional conflict. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT part of America's triad of nuclear weapons delivery systems?",
        "correct_answer": "Strategic Defense Initiative",
        "distractor1": "intercontinental ballistic missiles",
        "distractor2": "strategic bombers",
        "distractor3": "submarine-launched ballistic missiles",
        "distractor4": "both A and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first American president to sign a treaty to actually reduce current levels of nuclearweapons in the United States arsenal was",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor1": "Dwight Eisenhower.",
        "distractor2": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor3": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor4": "John Kennedy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Arms reduction talks were pushed onto the agenda of discussions between the twosuperpowers in the late 1980s due to all of the following reasons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "President Reagan's consistent policy of detente.",
        "distractor1": "the rapid drive toward democracy in Eastern Europe.",
        "distractor2": "Moscow's economic torpor.",
        "distractor3": "the Pentagon's budgetary squeeze. รยด",
        "distractor4": "the thaw of the Cold War. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first American president to sign a treaty to reduce existing levels of nuclear weapons was",
        "correct_answer": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor1": "Richard Nixon.",
        "distractor2": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor3": "George Bush.",
        "distractor4": "Bill Clinton. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The first American president to unilaterally dismantle some United States nuclear weaponswas",
        "correct_answer": "George Bush.",
        "distractor1": "Jimmy Carter.",
        "distractor2": "Ronald Reagan.",
        "distractor3": "Bill Clinton.",
        "distractor4": "Richard Nixon. "
    },
    {
        "question": "An agreement between President Bush and President Yeltsin in January 1993 called for",
        "correct_answer": "elimination of over two-thirds of their long-range nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor1": "the total elimination of nuclear weapons in Europe.",
        "distractor2": "a moratorium on the manufacture of nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor3": "a ban on all intermediate-range nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor4": "an indefinite freeze on overall levels of nuclear weapons. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument of foreign policy used to guarantee world dominance but no longer doesso?",
        "correct_answer": "military strength",
        "distractor1": "economic sanctions",
        "distractor2": "diplomacy",
        "distractor3": "none of the above",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Economic sanctions are",
        "correct_answer": "non-military sanctions imposed on a foreign government in an attempt to modify its behavior.",
        "distractor1": "sanctions imposed by the United States government on multinational corporations.",
        "distractor2": "accomplished through the use of tariffs and quotas.",
        "distractor3": "typically used as a second resort in an escalating military conflict.",
        "distractor4": "an example of a last resort sanction. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary means the United States has used to keep rogue nations from acquiring nuclearweapons has been by",
        "correct_answer": "encouraging nations to agree that they would not acquire, or at least test, nuclear weapons.",
        "distractor1": "successful monitoring of the international arms market.",
        "distractor2": "dramatically increasing foreign aid to rogue nations.",
        "distractor3": "infiltrating the intelligence communities of the rogue nations.",
        "distractor4": "both A and D "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following countries have agreed to give up their nuclear weapons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "North Korea.",
        "distractor1": "Argentina.",
        "distractor2": "Sweden.",
        "distractor3": "Brazil.",
        "distractor4": "Norway. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following countries are seeking to acquire nuclear weapons EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "Algeria.",
        "distractor1": "Iran.",
        "distractor2": "Iraq.",
        "distractor3": "North Korea.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The international economy today is one characterized by",
        "correct_answer": "interdependence.",
        "distractor1": "independence.",
        "distractor2": "isolationism.",
        "distractor3": "intransigence.",
        "distractor4": "protectionism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A tariff is a",
        "correct_answer": "tax added to the price of imported goods.",
        "distractor1": "good imported from another country.",
        "distractor2": "good exported to another country.",
        "distractor3": "tax added to the price of exported goods.",
        "distractor4": "tax added to the price of technological goods. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ are intended to raise the price of imported goods and thereby protect a nation'sbusinesses and workers from foreign competition.",
        "correct_answer": "Tariffs",
        "distractor1": "Quotas",
        "distractor2": "Balances of trade",
        "distractor3": "Subsidies",
        "distractor4": "Excise taxes "
    },
    {
        "question": "The one key word that could be used to describe today's international economy is",
        "correct_answer": "interdependency.",
        "distractor1": "protectionism.",
        "distractor2": "isolationism.",
        "distractor3": "self-sufficiency.",
        "distractor4": "bankruptcy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) is a cooperative international organization intended tostabilize",
        "correct_answer": "the exchange of currencies.",
        "distractor1": "diplomatic costs.",
        "distractor2": "economic policies between the developed and less developed countries.",
        "distractor3": "stock markets in new democracies.",
        "distractor4": "protective tariffs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The U.S. was involved in humanitarian intervention in which of the following countries?",
        "correct_answer": "all of the above ",
        "distractor1": "Somalia",
        "distractor2": "Haiti",
        "distractor3": "Bosnia",
        "distractor4": "Kosovo"
    },
    {
        "question": "The North American Free Trade Agreement is designed to eventually eliminate most ________among Canada, Mexico, and the United States.",
        "correct_answer": "tariffs",
        "distractor1": "subsidies",
        "distractor2": "imports",
        "distractor3": "border patrols",
        "distractor4": "exports "
    },
    {
        "question": "International economic policies today tend to emphasize",
        "correct_answer": "lower tariffs and freer trade.",
        "distractor1": "high tariffs and protectionism.",
        "distractor2": "central planning and policymaking.",
        "distractor3": "heavy reliance on international economic organizations.",
        "distractor4": "free trade and protectionism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of what a country pays for imports to what it earns in exports is known as its",
        "correct_answer": "balance of trade.",
        "distractor1": "federal deficit.",
        "distractor2": "international productivity quotient.",
        "distractor3": "tariff.",
        "distractor4": "trade gap. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the balance of trade is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "When a country exports more than it imports, it has a balance of trade deficit.",
        "distractor1": "The excess of imports over exports decreases the dollar's buying power against foreign currencies.",
        "distractor2": "Since the late 1980s, the United States has experienced an export boom that has given us a balance of trade surplus with Western Europe.",
        "distractor3": "A poor balance of trade exacerbates unemployment.",
        "distractor4": "A decline in the dollar makes American products cheaper abroad and increases exports. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about America's foreign aid programs?",
        "correct_answer": "A substantial percentage of foreign aid is military assistance. ",
        "distractor1": "Nearly all of the money spent goes to help modernize agriculture and industry in poorer nations, or directly provides food to the hungry.",
        "distractor2": "The United States spends a greater percentage of its gross national product on foreign aid than any other developed nation.",
        "distractor3": "Among the developed countries of the world, the United States donates the smallest actual amount of foreign aid.",
        "distractor4": "Foreign aid has always been a highly popular expenditure with Americans."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about foreign aid is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Congress usually increases the president's foreign aid requests. ",
        "distractor1": "Presidents of each party have pressed for aid to nations in the developing world.",
        "distractor2": "A major goal of foreign aid is to stabilize nations friendly to the United States.",
        "distractor3": "A substantial percentage of foreign aid is in the form of military assistance.",
        "distractor4": "Foreign food aid often ends up in the pockets of American farmers."
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States",
        "correct_answer": "donates more total aid than any other country.",
        "distractor1": "devotes a larger share of its GNP to foreign economic development than any other country.",
        "distractor2": "no longer gives military aid to less developed countries.",
        "distractor3": "funnels all of its foreign aid through the United Nations.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countries spends the smallest percentage of its gross domestic producton foreign economic development?",
        "correct_answer": "United States",
        "distractor1": "New Zealand",
        "distractor2": "Japan",
        "distractor3": "Italy",
        "distractor4": "Norway "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following nations is least dependent on foreign oil?",
        "correct_answer": "United States",
        "distractor1": "Japan",
        "distractor2": "Germany",
        "distractor3": "Great Britain",
        "distractor4": "the European nations together "
    },
    {
        "question": "Americans are usually least interested in",
        "correct_answer": "foreign policy.",
        "distractor1": "domestic policy.",
        "distractor2": "economic policy.",
        "distractor3": "social policy.",
        "distractor4": "tax policy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "When the American people hold strong opinions regarding international relations,",
        "correct_answer": "they find policymakers responsive to them.",
        "distractor1": "they are usually ignored.",
        "distractor2": "policymakers manipulate the agenda to emphasize domestic issues.",
        "distractor3": "they follow the lead of the president.",
        "distractor4": "national security policy decisions are delayed. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most pervasive characteristic of American international economic policy is",
        "correct_answer": "pluralism.",
        "distractor1": "elitism.",
        "distractor2": "secrecy.",
        "distractor3": "the dominance of the president.",
        "distractor4": "the lead role played by top State Department officials. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Every state is governed by ________, in which the basic rules of the political game for thatparticular state are established.",
        "correct_answer": "a state constitution",
        "distractor1": "the state government clause in the United States Constitution",
        "distractor2": "a collection of state statutes",
        "distractor3": "an official state guidebook",
        "distractor4": "the laws of the United States Congress "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most states",
        "correct_answer": "have constitutions more detailed and longer than the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "do not have their own constitutions.",
        "distractor2": "have constitutions less detailed and shorter than the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "have unwritten constitutions rather than written constitutions.",
        "distractor4": "have constitutions with about the same level of detail as the United States Constitution. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about state constitutions is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "State constitutions are typically much shorter than the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor1": "A state constitution spells out basic rules of the political game for that particular state.",
        "distractor2": "State constitutions are subordinate to the United States Constitution.",
        "distractor3": "State constitutions take precedence over state laws.",
        "distractor4": "All fifty states have constitutions. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All state constitutions",
        "correct_answer": "have a bill of rights.",
        "distractor1": "have provisions for a bicameral legislature.",
        "distractor2": "require one legislative session per year.",
        "distractor3": "require a balanced budget.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Historically, state elections have been decided by",
        "correct_answer": "national political and economic forces.",
        "distractor1": "vigorous campaigning on the part of candidates.",
        "distractor2": "strong political parties.",
        "distractor3": "contributions of Political Action Committees.",
        "distractor4": "state political bosses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the methods used by states to amend their constitutions?",
        "correct_answer": "simple statute",
        "distractor1": "legislative proposal",
        "distractor2": "constitutional convention",
        "distractor3": "popular initiative",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common method used to amend state constitutions is through",
        "correct_answer": "legislative proposal.",
        "distractor1": "constitutional convention.",
        "distractor2": "popular initiative.",
        "distractor3": "judicial review.",
        "distractor4": "executive order of the governor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the consequences of the greater visibility of state elections is that",
        "correct_answer": "state officials have become more representative.",
        "distractor1": "state administration has become more efficient.",
        "distractor2": "state policies have become more progressive.",
        "distractor3": "media coverage of state politics has increased.",
        "distractor4": "citizens know more about state politics. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Gubernatorial elections have become more   presidentialized   in that they",
        "correct_answer": "have become more personality-focused.",
        "distractor1": "have become more policy-oriented.",
        "distractor2": "have come to rely on political party organizations more.",
        "distractor3": "receive greater media coverage",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since the 1960s, most states have",
        "correct_answer": "both A and C",
        "distractor1": "shifted gubernatorial elections to off-Presidential years.",
        "distractor2": "reduced the number of elected state executives.",
        "distractor3": "changed the governor's term of office to four years.",
        "distractor4": "both B and C "
    },
    {
        "question": "Gubernatorial elections tend to be decided based on",
        "correct_answer": "what voters think about the candidates.",
        "distractor1": "presidential coattails.",
        "distractor2": "campaign spending.",
        "distractor3": "  hot-button   issues such as abortion.",
        "distractor4": "the national economy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "One result of the personalization of gubernatorial elections has been",
        "correct_answer": "divided government.",
        "distractor1": "more of an emphasis on policy positions.",
        "distractor2": "the adoption of sunset legislation.",
        "distractor3": "weakening of state political parties.",
        "distractor4": "less media coverage. "
    },
    {
        "question": "State legislative races are",
        "correct_answer": "less personalized than gubernatorial races.",
        "distractor1": "more personalized than gubernatorial races.",
        "distractor2": "more personalized than congressional races.",
        "distractor3": "not personalized at all.",
        "distractor4": "more personalized than presidential elections. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 1960s, a succession of United States Supreme Court decisions required that statelegislative districts be redrawn to",
        "correct_answer": "adhere to the principle of   one man, one vote.  ",
        "distractor1": "follow county lines.",
        "distractor2": "ensure the election of more women to the legislature.",
        "distractor3": "give rural areas more clout.",
        "distractor4": "give minority parties more opportunity. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to the Supreme Court's rulings in the 1960s to end the malapportionment, ________ areaswere overrepresented in many state legislatures.",
        "correct_answer": "rural",
        "distractor1": "urban",
        "distractor2": "suburban",
        "distractor3": "Republican",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Until the mid-1960s, the one group that was over-represented in state legislatures was",
        "correct_answer": "the rural population.",
        "distractor1": "women.",
        "distractor2": "urban dwellers.",
        "distractor3": "minorities.",
        "distractor4": "Southerners. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasingly close partisan divisions in state legislatures",
        "correct_answer": "have occurred in both the North and South.",
        "distractor1": "are relatively new as of the 1990s.",
        "distractor2": "are evident only in the South.",
        "distractor3": "are relatively new as of the 1980s.",
        "distractor4": "are evident only in the North. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Divided government exists when",
        "correct_answer": "the major parties do not control both chambers of the state legislature and a majority of state elected officials.",
        "distractor1": "a single party does not control both chambers of the state legislature.",
        "distractor2": "a single party does not control both chambers of the state legislature and a majority of state elected offices.",
        "distractor3": "a single party does not control both chambers of the state legislature and the governor's office.",
        "distractor4": "when the Republicans and the Democrats hold an equal number of congressional seats. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Over a ten-year period, about ________ of state legislative seats turned over.",
        "correct_answer": "75 percent",
        "distractor1": "10 percent",
        "distractor2": "30 percent",
        "distractor3": "50 percent",
        "distractor4": "90 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "Voters in many states have recently approved ________ to guarantee legislative turnover.",
        "correct_answer": "term limits",
        "distractor1": "reapportionment",
        "distractor2": "malapportionment",
        "distractor3": "shorter terms of office for state legislative seats",
        "distractor4": "recall elections "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ten-year turnover of state legislative seats",
        "correct_answer": "results in a significant change in the people holding office.",
        "distractor1": "occurs at a very slow rate.",
        "distractor2": "averages over 90 percent.",
        "distractor3": "is costly to taxpayers, but results in nicely furnished capitols.",
        "distractor4": "results in a completely new legislature every ten years. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is INCORRECT?",
        "correct_answer": "All states now limit the terms of their legislators.",
        "distractor1": "The Nebraska legislature only has one house.",
        "distractor2": "Although it is the second largest state, the Texas legislature is only scheduled to meet every other year.",
        "distractor3": "Most state legislatures have become much more professionalized over the past thirty years.",
        "distractor4": "Many state legislators are part-timers who have other careers. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Since 1975, women have",
        "correct_answer": "had numerous successes in running for governor.",
        "distractor1": "had limited success in running for governor.",
        "distractor2": "been less successful than African Americans in running for governor.",
        "distractor3": "had little interest in running for governor.",
        "distractor4": "been less successful than Hispanic Americans in running for governor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The states most likely to send women to the United States Senate are those which",
        "correct_answer": "have had high rates of women in the state legislature.",
        "distractor1": "have elected women as governors.",
        "distractor2": "have had a strong tradition of women's involvement in school politics.",
        "distractor3": "have been in the Midwest.",
        "distractor4": "have a high proportion of women in the workforce. "
    },
    {
        "question": "About how many gubernatorial vetoes are overridden by state legislatures?",
        "correct_answer": "10 percent",
        "distractor1": "20 percent",
        "distractor2": "30 percent",
        "distractor3": "15 percent",
        "distractor4": "40 percent "
    },
    {
        "question": "One power most governors have, but that the president does not, is the",
        "correct_answer": "line-item veto.",
        "distractor1": "ability to initiate legislation.",
        "distractor2": "responsibility for preparing the budget.",
        "distractor3": "symbolic head of state.",
        "distractor4": "executive clemency. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT serve to limit the power of a governor?",
        "correct_answer": "the line-item veto",
        "distractor1": "civil service employment policies in many states",
        "distractor2": "other elected executive branch officials, such as the attorney general",
        "distractor3": "state constitutional separation of powers",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following powers is NOT given to most state governors?",
        "correct_answer": "holding sole authority in the state's executive branch",
        "distractor1": "line-item veto",
        "distractor2": "overseeing the preparation of the state budget",
        "distractor3": "calling the legislature into special session",
        "distractor4": "informal ceremonial authority similar to the president being   Head of State   "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fact that most states have a number of elected state executives in addition to the governor",
        "correct_answer": "reduces the authority of the governor.",
        "distractor1": "gives the governor greater authority.",
        "distractor2": "reduces the authority of the legislature.",
        "distractor3": "reduces the democratic accountability of the executive branch of state government.",
        "distractor4": "has no effect on the authority of the governor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A governor's control over policy administration is somewhat diminished because",
        "correct_answer": "a large number of other executive branch officials are also elected in most states.",
        "distractor1": "new state constitutions tend to limit the powers of the governor.",
        "distractor2": "of the weakness of state political party structures.",
        "distractor3": "state legislatures have taken over many traditional executive duties.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The governor and lieutenant governor are elected in separate elections and can be of differentparties",
        "correct_answer": "in about half the states.",
        "distractor1": "in all fifty states.",
        "distractor2": "in none of the states.",
        "distractor3": "in eight states.",
        "distractor4": "in about one-third of the states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The lieutenant governor",
        "correct_answer": "does not exist in seven states.",
        "distractor1": "is appointed by the governor in 43 states.",
        "distractor2": "runs separately from the governor in seven states.",
        "distractor3": "runs with the governor as a team in 42 states.",
        "distractor4": "runs with the governor as a team in eight states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most lieutenant governors",
        "correct_answer": "have few formal duties.",
        "distractor1": "have substantial authority in the budgetary process.",
        "distractor2": "are not in line for succession to the governor.",
        "distractor3": "preside over the state house chamber.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about executive offices other than the governor is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Re-organization of state executive branches has resulted in cost-savings and efficiency.",
        "distractor1": "In some states, it is possible for the two top executives to be members of different political parties.",
        "distractor2": "Most lieutenant governors have few formal duties.",
        "distractor3": "Eight states don ยนt have a lieutenant governor.",
        "distractor4": "One governor was afraid to leave his state because of the lieutenant governor. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most modern state legislators are",
        "correct_answer": "very effective and professional.",
        "distractor1": "inexperienced.",
        "distractor2": "corrupt.",
        "distractor3": "paid on a part-time basis.",
        "distractor4": "millionaires. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Except for Nebraska, each state has a",
        "correct_answer": "bicameral legislature.",
        "distractor1": "governor and lieutenant governor.",
        "distractor2": "unicameral legislature.",
        "distractor3": "supreme court.",
        "distractor4": "plural executive. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A bicameral legislature is one that",
        "correct_answer": "has two houses.",
        "distractor1": "meets every two years.",
        "distractor2": "holds two sessions a year.",
        "distractor3": "has only one house.",
        "distractor4": "is evenly divided between Democrats and Republicans by law. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most states provide for legislative sessions every",
        "correct_answer": "year.",
        "distractor1": "two years.",
        "distractor2": "three years.",
        "distractor3": "four years.",
        "distractor4": "week except holidays. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the states, making laws is the legal function of",
        "correct_answer": "state legislatures.",
        "distractor1": "governors.",
        "distractor2": "state courts.",
        "distractor3": "state agencies.",
        "distractor4": "direct democracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most state legislators",
        "correct_answer": "have professional jobs.",
        "distractor1": "mirror the characteristics of their constituents.",
        "distractor2": "are women.",
        "distractor3": "lack a college education.",
        "distractor4": "are from rural areas. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Reforms of state legislatures oriented toward enhancing their   legislative professionalism  include all of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "lengthening legislative sessions.",
        "distractor1": "increasing the number of legislative committees.",
        "distractor2": "increasing the salary of state legislators.",
        "distractor3": "increasing the staff available to state legislators.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "A recent policy change in some states that actually   deprofessionalizes   legislature is",
        "correct_answer": "term limits.",
        "distractor1": "sunset legislation.",
        "distractor2": "line-item veto.",
        "distractor3": "Dillon's rule.",
        "distractor4": "Missouri Plan. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The judicial system in most states is set up",
        "correct_answer": "as a hierarchical system under state control, similar in its organization to the federal court system.",
        "distractor1": "as the lowest level of the federal court system, with the states having little say over structure or operations.",
        "distractor2": "in a haphazard fashion, with trial courts and appellate courts differing county by county, municipality by municipality.",
        "distractor3": "without an appellate level; any appeals of state trial court decisions go directly to the United States Supreme Court.",
        "distractor4": "as a merit system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared to the federal district courts, state courts, on average, hear ________ trials andappeals.",
        "correct_answer": "far more",
        "distractor1": "far fewer",
        "distractor2": "somewhat fewer",
        "distractor3": "somewhat more",
        "distractor4": "about the same number of "
    },
    {
        "question": "The judicial branch in most states operates on a ________ system.",
        "correct_answer": "three-tier",
        "distractor1": "single-level",
        "distractor2": "two-tier",
        "distractor3": "four-tier",
        "distractor4": "circular "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the state judicial system, it is at the ________ level that the facts are considered before asingle judge and a jury.",
        "correct_answer": "trial court",
        "distractor1": "federal district court",
        "distractor2": "appellate court",
        "distractor3": "court of last resort",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "All states have a ________, usually called the supreme court, that is the final appellate level ina state.",
        "correct_answer": "court of last resort",
        "distractor1": "trial court",
        "distractor2": "intermediate court of appeals",
        "distractor3": "judicial review",
        "distractor4": "criminal court "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the state court of last resort is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "State courts of last resort only hear criminal cases.",
        "distractor1": "State courts of last resort are the final appellate level in a state.",
        "distractor2": "State courts of last resort are headed by a chief justice.",
        "distractor3": "State courts of last resort may practice judicial review.",
        "distractor4": "They have recently exhibited a new wave of liberal activism. "
    },
    {
        "question": "State courts of appeals",
        "correct_answer": "decide cases using a panel of three or more judges.",
        "distractor1": "are organized on a local basis.",
        "distractor2": "hear only the facts of a case.",
        "distractor3": "have seen their case load decrease in recent years.",
        "distractor4": "use juries in 42 states. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The ________ is a system of appointing judges based on merit, with the governor given a list ofqualified persons from the state bar or a committee of jurists and other officials from whom tomake a selection, and the appointment subject to the state's voters deciding on retaining thejudge.",
        "correct_answer": "Merit Plan",
        "distractor1": "judicial review",
        "distractor2": "judicial restraint",
        "distractor3": "sunset law",
        "distractor4": "Missouri Plan "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most state judges",
        "correct_answer": "are elected by the voters.",
        "distractor1": "are appointed by the governor.",
        "distractor2": "serve for life.",
        "distractor3": "are not reelected.",
        "distractor4": "are appointed by the legislature. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The form of direct democracy that allows the public to directly adopt a policy without anyinvolvement of the state legislature is",
        "correct_answer": "initiative.",
        "distractor1": "recall.",
        "distractor2": "referendum.",
        "distractor3": "direct primary.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "The initiative is undemocratic to the extent that it",
        "correct_answer": "is often the tool of wealthy groups and individuals.",
        "distractor1": "puts power in the hands of citizens.",
        "distractor2": "contains ambiguous language.",
        "distractor3": "may be used to restrict tax increases.",
        "distractor4": "contains specific language. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Issues dealing with ________ are often proposed by referenda.",
        "correct_answer": "school bonds",
        "distractor1": "corrupt public officials",
        "distractor2": "special district creation",
        "distractor3": "racial equality",
        "distractor4": "the tax system "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under state constitutions, local governments are considered ________ the state government.",
        "correct_answer": "subdivisions of",
        "distractor1": "coequal with",
        "distractor2": "superior to",
        "distractor3": "totally separate from",
        "distractor4": "interchangeable with "
    },
    {
        "question": "County government usually consists of an elected county ________ that makes policy and acollection of   row officers   who run county services.",
        "correct_answer": "commission",
        "distractor1": "congress",
        "distractor2": "board of education",
        "distractor3": "directorate",
        "distractor4": "mayor "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the   row officers   who usually run county services?",
        "correct_answer": "commissioner",
        "distractor1": "sheriff",
        "distractor2": "clerk",
        "distractor3": "assessor",
        "distractor4": "prosecutor "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ governments are found in only twenty states, with those in New England having themost power.",
        "correct_answer": "Township",
        "distractor1": "Municipal",
        "distractor2": "County",
        "distractor3": "Special district",
        "distractor4": "Borough "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following do rural residents rely on most for services?",
        "correct_answer": "county governments",
        "distractor1": "state governments",
        "distractor2": "the Farm Bureau",
        "distractor3": "special districts",
        "distractor4": "agricultural cooperatives "
    },
    {
        "question": "The administrative arm of state government in local areas is",
        "correct_answer": "county governments.",
        "distractor1": "special districts.",
        "distractor2": "municipalities.",
        "distractor3": "districts and wards.",
        "distractor4": "the state legislator. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about townships is FALSE?",
        "correct_answer": "Almost every state has township governments.",
        "distractor1": "Most township governments have limited powers.",
        "distractor2": "In New England, townships function much like city governments.",
        "distractor3": "Most townships lack power to pass local ordinances.",
        "distractor4": "They are extensions of state and county government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ government normally provides police and fire protection, street maintenance, solidwaste collection, water and sewage works, and similar services.",
        "correct_answer": "Municipal",
        "distractor1": "National",
        "distractor2": "State",
        "distractor3": "School district",
        "distractor4": "County "
    },
    {
        "question": "The level of government that typically provides most of the police and fire protection is",
        "correct_answer": "municipalities.",
        "distractor1": "state government.",
        "distractor2": "counties.",
        "distractor3": "special districts.",
        "distractor4": "township. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Originally, most local communities in the United States operated under a",
        "correct_answer": "town meeting system.",
        "distractor1": "mayor-council government.",
        "distractor2": "council-manager government.",
        "distractor3": "commission government.",
        "distractor4": "mayor-only system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of municipal government is not in common use today?",
        "correct_answer": "town meeting government",
        "distractor1": "mayor-council government",
        "distractor2": "council-manager government",
        "distractor3": "commission government",
        "distractor4": "weak-mayor government "
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the ________ system of municipal government, the city government bureaucracy isdirected by an appointed administrator.",
        "correct_answer": "council-manager",
        "distractor1": "mayor-council with a strong mayor",
        "distractor2": "mayor-council with a weak mayor",
        "distractor3": "commission",
        "distractor4": "command "
    },
    {
        "question": "In the ________ government, used in only a few cities, voters elect a panel of officials whoserve both as legislators and as executives of a functional area of city government, such aspublic safety.",
        "correct_answer": "commissioner",
        "distractor1": "strong mayor, mayor-council",
        "distractor2": "weak mayor, mayor-council",
        "distractor3": "council-manager",
        "distractor4": "mayor-manager "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most city council members and mayors are",
        "correct_answer": "elected on non-partisan ballots.",
        "distractor1": "appointed by the governor.",
        "distractor2": "appointed by city managers.",
        "distractor3": "elected on partisan ballots.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "At-large elections for the city council were begun",
        "correct_answer": "to reform municipal government and reduce the power of political machine bosses.",
        "distractor1": "to give more power to old-time political machine bosses.",
        "distractor2": "as a way to increase minority group representation on city councils.",
        "distractor3": "to simplify the printing of election ballots throughout the city.",
        "distractor4": "to consolidate elections into one election to cut election costs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most mayor-council cities",
        "correct_answer": "follow the weak mayor form.",
        "distractor1": "follow the strong mayor form.",
        "distractor2": "have a city manager to carry out policy.",
        "distractor3": "have over 500,000 residents.",
        "distractor4": "use the commission system. "
    },
    {
        "question": "In a council-manager form of government, the implementation and administration of policy isplaced in the hands of",
        "correct_answer": "a city manager.",
        "distractor1": "the city council itself.",
        "distractor2": "a mayor.",
        "distractor3": "a county manager.",
        "distractor4": "the chief administrative officer. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of city government that combines legislative and executive function in the same bodyis the",
        "correct_answer": "commission government.",
        "distractor1": "mayor-council government.",
        "distractor2": "council-manager government.",
        "distractor3": "district-ward government.",
        "distractor4": "consolidated municipality. "
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of municipal government used least in the United States is the",
        "correct_answer": "commission government.",
        "distractor1": "mayor-council government with weak mayor.",
        "distractor2": "mayor-council government with strong mayor.",
        "distractor3": "council-manager government.",
        "distractor4": "mayor-manager-government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A majority of cities elect council members",
        "correct_answer": "at large.",
        "distractor1": "in partisan elections.",
        "distractor2": "according to districts or wards.",
        "distractor3": "on the basis of proportional representation.",
        "distractor4": "by multiple-member districts. "
    },
    {
        "question": "A consequence of at-large city council elections is that",
        "correct_answer": "minority group members have had difficulty gaining election to city council.",
        "distractor1": "they tend to create public policies that benefit individual neighborhoods.",
        "distractor2": "elections have become much less competitive.",
        "distractor3": "they have given greater power to city bosses.",
        "distractor4": "all of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most school systems are run",
        "correct_answer": "as independent local governments.",
        "distractor1": "by city government.",
        "distractor2": "by the state governments.",
        "distractor3": "by the national government.",
        "distractor4": "by county government. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does state government generally NOT do in regard to public educationin the 1990s?",
        "correct_answer": "build and operate the schools",
        "distractor1": "mandate certain programs",
        "distractor2": "provide a certain amount of state funding",
        "distractor3": "adopt general standards for educational policy and school buildings",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Independent school districts are responsible for each of the following EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "adopting general standards for education policy and school buildings.",
        "distractor1": "electing a board of education.",
        "distractor2": "picking administrators and teachers.",
        "distractor3": "adopting and funding an education budget.",
        "distractor4": "designing and running education programs. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Local revenue sources for schools are heavily dependent upon the ________ tax.",
        "correct_answer": "local property",
        "distractor1": "federal income",
        "distractor2": "state income",
        "distractor3": "state and/or local sales",
        "distractor4": "lottery revenue "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the most widely expressed criticism of paying for public schoolsprimarily through the local property taxes?",
        "correct_answer": "It means that wealthier school districts can provide more educational money than poorer districts.",
        "distractor1": "It makes local control over schools more difficult.",
        "distractor2": "The elderly and those without children are forced to pay for public education.",
        "distractor3": "Property values rise and fall so much that local school boards have no idea how much money they will have to spend.",
        "distractor4": "Higher property taxes discourage local development. "
    },
    {
        "question": "________ represent the fastest growing form of subnational government during the pastdecade.",
        "correct_answer": "Special districts",
        "distractor1": "Municipal governments",
        "distractor2": "County governments",
        "distractor3": "School districts",
        "distractor4": "State governments "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is normally classified as a special district?",
        "correct_answer": "park",
        "distractor1": "county",
        "distractor2": "municipal",
        "distractor3": "township",
        "distractor4": "city borough "
    },
    {
        "question": "The fastest growing form of local government in the United States is",
        "correct_answer": "special district.",
        "distractor1": "county.",
        "distractor2": "municipality.",
        "distractor3": "school districts.",
        "distractor4": "townships. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of governments are the most numerous in the United States?",
        "correct_answer": "special districts",
        "distractor1": "counties",
        "distractor2": "municipalities",
        "distractor3": "townships",
        "distractor4": "school districts "
    },
    {
        "question": "Local revenue sources for schools are disproportionally based upon the",
        "correct_answer": "property tax.",
        "distractor1": "income tax.",
        "distractor2": "sales tax.",
        "distractor3": "state lotteries.",
        "distractor4": "local business tax. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Special districts in the United States are characterized by their",
        "correct_answer": "organizational diversity.",
        "distractor1": "uniformity.",
        "distractor2": "scarcity.",
        "distractor3": "partisanship.",
        "distractor4": "inflexibility. "
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are limits on local government EXCEPT",
        "correct_answer": "high levels of citizen involvement.",
        "distractor1": "fragmentation of local government power.",
        "distractor2": "constitutional limitations.",
        "distractor3": "competition with other local governments.",
        "distractor4": "none of the above "
    },
    {
        "question": "Particularly in rural areas, ________ government is the administrative arm of most stategovernments, keeping records of births, deaths, and marriages, conducting a system of justiceand law enforcement, maintaining roads and bridges, and providing other services.",
        "correct_answer": "county",
        "distractor1": "regional",
        "distractor2": "municipal",
        "distractor3": "township",
        "distractor4": "commission "
    },
    {
        "question": "Councils of Governments have been formed to",
        "correct_answer": "improve cooperation between local governments.",
        "distractor1": "reform state and local campaign practices.",
        "distractor2": "improve the public image of local governments.",
        "distractor3": "lobby state legislatures on behalf of localities.",
        "distractor4": "streamline local government bureaucracy. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not a source of state revenue?",
        "correct_answer": "property taxes",
        "distractor1": "the federal government",
        "distractor2": "state insurance programs",
        "distractor3": "charges for services",
        "distractor4": "fuel taxes "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following program areas would tend to receive the smallest percentage of statemoney in most states?",
        "correct_answer": "natural resources",
        "distractor1": "education",
        "distractor2": "prisons",
        "distractor3": "transportation",
        "distractor4": "health care "
    },
    {
        "question": "States receive the largest portion of revenue from",
        "correct_answer": "taxes.",
        "distractor1": "lotteries.",
        "distractor2": "federal government.",
        "distractor3": "user fees.",
        "distractor4": "business property taxes. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Most local government moneys are allocated to",
        "correct_answer": "education.",
        "distractor1": "social services.",
        "distractor2": "public safety.",
        "distractor3": "transportation.",
        "distractor4": "local government administrative expenses. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the largest sources of local government revenues?",
        "correct_answer": "lotteries",
        "distractor1": "property tax and other taxes",
        "distractor2": "charges on users of services",
        "distractor3": "intergovernmental funds",
        "distractor4": "income tax "
    }
]